<!DOCTYPE metadata SYSTEM "http://fgdc.gov/metadata/fgdc-std-001-1998.dtd">
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>U.S. Geological Survey</origin>
        <pubdate>200201</pubdate>
        <title>Butterflies, New York State, 2002</title>
        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Reston, Virginia</pubplace>
          <publish>U.S. Geological Survey</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <onlink>https://cugir.library.cornell.edu/catalog/cugir-007323</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>This Butterfly Occurrence Database portrays the occurrence of butterflies in counties in New York State. Butterfly occurrence data are cumulative, so positive occurrence data do not necessarily imply current residence of the species. Most records are from the last 30 to 40 years, with a few records that date from as early as the late 1800's.</abstract>
      <purpose>These data are intended for use in publications at a scale of 1:2,000,000 or smaller. Due to the small scale, the primary use is for regional and national data display and analysis, rather than specific local data analysis. No responsibility is assumed by the U.S. Geological Survey in the use of these data.</purpose>
      <supplinf>This data set must be used together with the dBASE IV file bflyspt.dbf. Bflyspt.dbf describes the butterfly species to which this occurrence data applies. To create maps that are similar to the maps in the National Atlas &lt;http://nationalatlas.gov/natlas/natlasstart.asp&gt;, butflyt.dbf can be joined to the 2000 county boundaries available from the National Atlas download page, &lt;http://nationalatlas.gov/atlasftp.html&gt;.</supplinf>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <sngdate>
          <caldate>2002</caldate>
        </sngdate>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>publication date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Irregular</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
          <bounding>
            <westbc>-79.763235</westbc>
            <eastbc>-71.869987</eastbc>
            <northbc>45.006139</northbc>
            <southbc>40.506003</southbc>
          </bounding>
        </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>LCSH</themekt>
        <themekey>butterflies</themekey>
        <themekey>lepidoptera</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
        <themekey>biota</themekey>
        <themekey>environment</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
              <themekt>CUGIR Category</themekt>
              <themekey>biology</themekey>
<themekey>environment</themekey>
            </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>LCSH</placekt>
        <placekey>New York (State)</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>None. Acknowledgment of the National Atlas of the United States of America and (or) the U.S. Geological Survey would be appreciated in products derived from these data.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Terry Shaffer</cntper>
          <cntorg>U.S. Geological Survey, Biological Resources Division, Northern Prairie Wildlife Research Center</cntorg>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>
          <address>8711 37th Street Southeast</address>
          <city>Jamestown</city>
          <state>ND</state>
          <postal>58401</postal>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>701-253-5522</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>terry_shaffer@usgs.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <browse>
              <browsen>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/73/23/preview.png</browsen>
              <browsed>preview of the dataset</browsed>
              <browset>PNG</browset>
            </browse>
    <datacred>The following people and organizations contributed to the original data set compiled by the Northern Prairie Wildlife Research Center (NPWRC). Contributors are listed by project. Butterflies of the Eastern United States (Opler): Museum collections surveyed by the compiler were the National Museum of Natural History (Washington, DC); Frost Museum, Pennsylvania State University; and the E. O. Essig Museum, University of California at Berkeley. Other State institutional collections were surveyed by contributors. The contributors should receive most of the credit for the many days afield and the many hours spent compiling records. The names of the many collectors or naturalists who provided data to State compilers or for recently published State treatments are not all included, but their contributions were crucial of course. Dr. John M. Burns (USNM), Dr. K.C. Kim (Frost Museum), and Dr. J.A. Powell (Essig Museum) kindly allowed the NPWRC compiler to examine collections under their care. The U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service provided logistic support. All work by the compiler was carried out during non-duty hours. In New York, many thanks to J. Ingraham and L.L. Pechumen. Additional persons who provided county records are listed in the acknowledgments section of the Peterson Field Guide to Butterflies of Eastern North America (Opler and Malikul, 1992). Museum collections examined for Western records include the American Museum of Natural History, New York, New York</datacred>
    <native>dBASE IV</native>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>All records in the original files were checked by a qualified lepidopterist before inclusion. Both compilation and checking were performed manually and there is a possibility that some errors may remain.</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <logic>Not applicable</logic>
    <complete>This data file includes information for all counties in the United States where population information is available. A species is reported as present in a county if there is a specimen in an institutional or private collection, or a reliable literature record such as a citation in an original description, a monograph, or a State compilation. Records may represent either resident or stray status. Lack of data for a county indicates that no records exist, rather than that no species are present. This data is cumulative, so a positive record does not necessarily imply current residence of the species.</complete>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>U.S. Geological Survey, Biological Resources Division</origin>
            <pubdate>1995</pubdate>
            <title>Text file of butterfly occurrence information</title>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Jamestown, ND</pubplace>
              <publish>U.S. Geological Survey, Northern Prairie Wildlife Research Center</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>electronic mail system</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>1995</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>Bflytab</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Spatial and attribute information</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>U.S. Geological Survey, Biological Resources Division</origin>
            <pubdate>1995</pubdate>
            <title>Text file of butterfly common names and species</title>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Jamestown, ND</pubplace>
              <publish>U.S. Geological Survey, Northern Prairie Wildlife Research Center</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>electronic mail system</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>Unknown</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>bflyspec</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Attribute information</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>U.S. Geological Survey</origin>
            <pubdate>199809</pubdate>
            <title>Butterfly Occurrence Database</title>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Reston, Virginia</pubplace>
              <publish>U.S. Geological Survey</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>online</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>1995</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date of source material</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>ATLAS-BUTFLY</srccitea>
        <srccontr>attribute information</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>The original occurrence file (Bflytab) was compiled by the Biological Resources Division from multiple sources, including U.S. museums, State University collections, reliable literature publications, scientific literature, private collections, and information provided by State and regional coordinators. Most records are specimen based, although some sightings of easily identified species were accepted. Primary references include: Opler, Paul A. 1995. Lepidoptera of North America: 2. Distribution of the butterflies (Papilionoidea and Hesperioides) of the eastern United States. Contributions of the C.P. Gillette Museum of Insect Biodiversity. Colorado State University, Fort Collins, Colorado Pavulaan, Harry and Paul A. Opler. 1995. Atlas of eastern butterflies. Unpublished information. Stanford, Ray E. and Paul A. Opler. 1993. Atlas of western USA butterflies, including adjacent parts of Canada and Mexico. Published by authors. Denver, Colorado. Further information on sources and procedures can be found on the Northern Prairie Wildlife Research Center web page on butterflies at: &lt;http://www.npwrc.usgs.gov/resource/distr/lepid/bflyusa/bflyusa.htm&gt; The Species listing (bflyspec) was compiled by the Biological Resources Division. All naming is based on the most recent North American Butterfly Association standards and some changes introduced in Layberry et al, 1998, Butterflies of Canada, University of Toronto Press. The two source files were received as ASCII delimited text files. These files were read into WordPerfect and edited to delete extra characters, and to add column headings. The resulting files were loaded into ArcView as text, then saved as .dbf files. Bflytab was edited in ArcView to convert the FIPS codes from integer to character, and to add leading zeros to those FIPS codes that were only 4 digits. Both files were then saved in ArcView as .dbf files. In the online, interactive National Atlas of the United States, the occurrence file is joined to the 2000 county boundaries for display purposes, and the occurrence file and the species listing are linked via a Structured Query Language statement in Microsoft Access.</procdesc>
        <srcused>Bflytab</srcused>
        <srcused>Bflyspec</srcused>
        <procdate>1998</procdate>
        <srcprod>ATLAS-BUTFLY</srcprod>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>In ATLAS-BUTFLY, FIPS code 12025 (Dade County) was changed to FIPS code 12086 (Miami-Dade County). In addition, 50 records were deleted that contained invalid county FIPS codes.</procdesc>
        <srcused>ATLAS-BUTFLY</srcused>
        <procdate>20020104</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>In order to geoprocess spatial files for New York State from the National Atlas Data for distribution in CUGIR, the nationwide data files were added to a map document in ArcInfo 8.2. Using the geoprocessing wizard's clip function, the spatial files were clipped to the detailed New York polygon.</procdesc>
        <procdate>200212</procdate>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
        <direct>Vector</direct>
        <ptvctinf>
          <sdtsterm>
            <sdtstype>G-polygon</sdtstype>
            <ptvctcnt>62</ptvctcnt>
          </sdtsterm>
        </ptvctinf>
      </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <geograph>
        <latres>0.000278</latres>
        <longres>0.000278</longres>
        <geogunit>Decimal degrees</geogunit>
      </geograph>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>GRS1980</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257222</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>Butterfly occurrences; described by butflyt.dbf</enttypl>
        <enttypd>Whether a butterfly has been reported in a given county; listed as a table of butterfly distribution</enttypd>
        <enttypds>U.S. Geological Survey</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Fips</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The State and county FIPS code for the area to which the occurrence data applies.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>U.S. Geological Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <codesetd>
            <codesetn>Counties and Equivalent Entities of the United States, Its Possessions, and Associated Areas, FIPS 6-4, 1990.</codesetn>
            <codesets>U.S. Department of Commerce, National Institute of Standards and Technology</codesets>
          </codesetd>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Specie#</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The Species number where # is a number from 1 to 789. The species numbers represent butterfly species, which are identified by Species name, Family, Subfamily, and Common name in bflyspt.dbf. The species number in butflyt.dbf corresponds to the number listed under Column in the bflyspt.dbf file. For example, the Specie3 field contains occurrence data for Achalarus casica (Common name: Desert Cloudywing) butterflies.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>U.S. Geological Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>0</edomv>
            <edomvd>The butterfly species defined for the field has not been reported in the county. Counties are identified in the "Fips" column.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>U.S. Geological Survey</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>1</edomv>
            <edomvd>The butterfly species defined for the field has been reported in the county. Counties are identified in the "Fips" column.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>U.S. Geological Survey</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>2</edomv>
            <edomvd>The butterfly species defined for the field has been reported in the county, but the report has not been confirmed. Counties are identified in the "Fips" column.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>U.S. Geological Survey</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
        <distrib>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>Albert R. Mann Library</cntorg>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
              <address>Cornell University</address>
              <city>Ithaca</city>
              <state>New York</state>
              <postal>14853</postal>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>607-255-5406</cntvoice>
            <cntemail>mann-ref@cornell.edu</cntemail>
          </cntinfo>
        </distrib>
        <distliab>Cornell University provides these geographic data "as is". Cornell
          University makes no guarantee or warranty concerning the accuracy of
          information contained in the geographic data. Cornell University further
          makes no warranty either expressed or implied, regarding the condition of
          the product or its fitness for any particular purpose. The burden for
          determining fitness for use lies entirely with the user. Although these
          files have been processed successfully on computers at Cornell University,
          no warranty is made by Cornell University regarding the use of these data
          on any other system, nor does the fact of distribution constitute or imply
          any such warranty.</distliab>
        <stdorder>
        <digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>Shapefile</formname>
              <formcont>zipped shapefile</formcont>
              <filedec>zip</filedec>
              <transize>0.11</transize>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/73/23/cugir-007323.zip</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>metadata</formname>
              <formcont>FGDC XML metadata</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/73/23/fgdc.xml</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>HTML metadata</formname>
              <formcont>FGDC HTML metadata</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/73/23/fgdc.html</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
                <digtinfo>
                  <formname>KML</formname>
                  <formcont>generated KML, via WFS</formcont>
                </digtinfo>
                <digtopt>
                  <onlinopt>
                    <computer>
                      <networka>
                        <networkr>https://cugir.library.cornell.edu/geoserver/cugir/wfs?version=1.0.0&amp;request=GetFeature&amp;typeName=cugir007323&amp;outputFormat=application%2Fvnd.google-earth.kml%2Bxml</networkr>
                      </networka>
                    </computer>
                  </onlinopt>
                </digtopt>
              </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>GeoJSON</formname>
              <formcont>generated GeoJSON, via WFS</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir.library.cornell.edu/geoserver/cugir/wfs?version=1.0.0&amp;request=GetFeature&amp;typeName=cugir007323&amp;outputFormat=application%2Fjson</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>OGC:WMS</formname>
              <formcont>WMS, from GeoServer</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir.library.cornell.edu/geoserver/cugir/wms?version=1.1.0&amp;request=GetMap&amp;layers=cugir007323&amp;bbox=-80.00003244,40.37099892,-71.63318955999999,45.14114308&amp;width=256&amp;height=145&amp;srs=EPSG:4326&amp;format=image/png</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><fees>None</fees></stdorder>
      </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
      <metd>20190524</metd>
      <metc>
        <cntinfo>
          <cntorgp>
            <cntorg>Albert R. Mann Library</cntorg>
          </cntorgp>
          <cntaddr>
            <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
            <address>Albert R. Mann Library</address>
            <city>Ithaca</city>
            <state>New York</state>
            <postal>14853</postal>
            <country>USA</country>
          </cntaddr>
          <cntvoice>607-255-5406</cntvoice>
          <cntemail>mann-ref@cornell.edu</cntemail>
        </cntinfo>
      </metc>
      <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
      <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
      <mettc>local time</mettc>
    </metainfo>
</metadata>
