<!DOCTYPE metadata SYSTEM "http://fgdc.gov/metadata/fgdc-std-001-1998.dtd">
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>U.S. Geological Survey</origin>
        <pubdate>200101</pubdate>
        <title>Major Surface Water Sampling Sites (NAWQA), New York State, 1991 and 1994</title>
        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
        <onlink>https://cugir.library.cornell.edu/catalog/cugir-007319</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>This data set shows the 1991 and 1994 National Water-Quality Assessment (NAWQA)
        study units' major surface-water sampling sites. These sites are in NAWQA's fixed network
        and (or) in a bed sediment and tissue network.</abstract>
      <purpose>This data set was created to display NAWQA's major surface-water sampling sites
        identified as part of a fixed network and (or) a bed sediment and tissue network. The points
        were generated from the latitude and longitude coordinates in the U.S. Geological Survey's
        National Water Information System (NWIS) for the selected stations.</purpose>
      <supplinf>The National Water-Quality Assessment Program is designed to describe the status and
        trends in the quality of the Nation's ground- and surface- water resources and to provide a
        sound understanding of the natural and human factors that affect the quality of these
        resources (Leahy and others, 1990). The building blocks of the national assessment are
        investigations in major hydrologic systems of the Nation, referred to as "Study Units". The
        study units are divided into three groups. Each group of study units is intensively studied
        on a rotational schedule of three-year periods. The first group began in fiscal year 1991
        (FY 1991 ran from October 1990-September 1991), the second in fiscal year 1994 and the third
        in fiscal year 1997. This data set includes major surface- water sampling sites from the
        first two groups of study units. Sampling sites within the NAWQA program are grouped into
        "networks". A surface-water sampling network is characterized by the type of sampling
        activity, such as what constituents are sampled and (or) the sampling frequency. This data
        set includes sites in a fixed network and (or) bed sediment and tissue network. A NAWQA
        fixed site is a site on a stream, at which streamflow is measured and samples are collected
        for temperature, salinity, suspended sediment, major ions, nutrients, and organic carbon, to
        assess the broad-scale spatial and temporal character and transport of inorganic
        constituents of stream water in relation to hydrologic conditions and environmental settings
        (Gilliom and others, 1995). Samples are collected regularly at fixed sites for at least two
        years. All fixed sites are considered "basic fixed sites" but some are referred to as
        "intensive fixed sites" if the sampling frequency increased during selected seasonal periods
        and if pesticide samples were collected regularly for 1 year (Gilliom and others, 1995). A
        NAWQA bed sediment and tissue site is a site where bed sediment and (or) tissue samples are
        collected and analyzed for trace elements and hydrophobic organic contaminants in streambed
        sediment and in the tissue of aquatic organisms. Bed sediment and (or) tissue samples are
        typically collected once at a site, however some sites are resampled. Some of these sites
        are within NAWQA's major bed sediment and tissue networks, while some are not. The two major
        bed sediment and tissue networks are the Occurrence survey and the Spatial Distribution
        survey. The Occurrence survey focuses on what hydrophobic contaminants are present, while
        the Spatial Distribution survey focuses on these contaminants through broader areal
        sampling. Though these surveys constitute separate bed sediment and tissue networks, no
        differentiation is made in this data set. However, a bed sediment and tissue site in either
        the Occurrence survey or the Spatial Distribution survey is differentiated from remaining
        bed sediment and tissue sites that are not part of these surveys. These remaining sites are
        either part of another bed sediment and (or) tissue network, or part of a synoptic network
        at which bed sediment and (or) tissue samples were collected. A synoptic network consists of
        a single or multiple sites sampled to investigate specific conditions during selected
        seasonal or hydrologic periods. In this data set, synoptic sites at which bed sediment and
        (or) tissue samples are collected are considered to belong to a bed sediment and tissue
        network. The major surface-water sampling sites in the 1997 NAWQA study unit starts will be
        added to this data set in the near future. The NAWQA home page is at
        &lt;http://water.usgs.gov/nawqa/nawqa_home.html&gt;. A map showing the extent of all NAWQA
        study units, with links to individual study unit information, is available at
        &lt;http://water.usgs.gov/nawqa/nawqamap.html&gt;. For additional information about the
        NAWQA program please see: Gilliom, R.J., Alley, W.M., and Gurtz, M.E., 1995, Design of the
        National Water-Quality Assessment Program: Occurrence and Distribution of Water-Quality
        Conditions, U.S. Geological Survey Circular 1112. U.S. Geological Survey, Sacramento,
        California. Accessible online at: &lt;http://water.usgs.gov/pubs/circ1112/&gt;. Leahy, P.P.,
        Rosenshein, J.S., and Knopman, D.S., 1990, Implementation plan for the National
        Water-Quality Assessment Program: U.S. Geological Survey Open-File Report 90-174. U.S.
        Geological Survey, Reston, Virginia, 10 p. Leahy, P.P. and Thompson, T.H., 1994, National
        Water-Quality Assessment Program: U.S. Geological Survey Open-File Report 94-70, 4 p.,
        Accessible online at &lt;http://water.usgs.gov/nawqa/NAWQA.OFR94-70.html&gt;. Any use of
        trade, product, or firm names is for descriptive purposes only and does not imply
        endorsement by the U.S. Government.</supplinf>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <mdattim>
          <sngdate>
            <caldate>1991</caldate>
          </sngdate>
          <sngdate>
            <caldate>1994</caldate>
          </sngdate>
        </mdattim>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Ground condition</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>As needed</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
          <bounding>
            <westbc>-78.935036</westbc>
            <eastbc>-73.337334</eastbc>
            <northbc>43.892006</northbc>
            <southbc>40.936489</southbc>
          </bounding>
        </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>none</themekt>
        <themekey>Sampling sites</themekey>
        <themekey>Surface water</themekey>
        <themekey>Water quality</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>LCSH</themekt>
        <themekey>Hydrography</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
        <themekey>environment</themekey>
        <themekey>inlandWaters</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
              <themekt>CUGIR Category</themekt>
              <themekey>environment</themekey>
<themekey>inland waters</themekey>
            </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>LCSH</placekt>
        <placekey>New York (State)</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>None. Acknowledgment of the National Atlas of the United States of America and (or)
      the U.S. Geological Survey would be appreciated in products derived from these
      data.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>U.S. Geological Survey, NAWQA National Synthesis GIS</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing address</addrtype>
          <address>CSUS 6000 J Street</address>
          <city>Sacramento</city>
          <state>CA</state>
          <postal>95819</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>916-278-3092</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>916-278-3071</cntfax>
        <cntemail>gs-w_nawqa_nsgis@usgs.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <browse>
              <browsen>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/73/19/preview.png</browsen>
              <browsed>preview of the dataset</browsed>
              <browset>PNG</browset>
            </browse>
    <datacred>Thanks to Curtis Price for generating the NAWQA surface-water (and ground- water)
      sampling sites coverage from which this data set was extracted, the NAWQA Study Units for
      making a national NAWQA data set possible, and Jon Scott and many others on the NAWQA Data
      Synthesis team for their efforts in aggregating the data.</datacred>
    <native>Windows_NT, 4.0, Intel Arc/INFO version 8.0.2</native>
    <crossref>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Hitt, K.J.</origin>
        <origin>Nakagaki, N.</origin>
        <pubdate>19990701</pubdate>
        <title>National Water-Quality Assessment (NAWQA) Study-Unit Investigations in the
          Conterminous United States</title>
        <geoform>Map</geoform>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Reston, VA</pubplace>
          <publish>U.S. Geological Survey</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <onlink>http://water.usgs.gov/lookup/getspatial?nawqa</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </crossref>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>Sites identified as part of the fixed network were checked with existing
        record-keeping of fixed stations by the NAWQA National Synthesis team. Sites identified as
        part of the bed sediment and tissue network were verified as having bed sediment and (or)
        tissue data. Other stations were added to the data that were not part of NAWQA's bed
        sediment and tissue networks but where bed sediment and (or) tissue samples had been
        collected. Additional attribute values were checked by NWIS software on entry.</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <logic>No checks for logical consistency were performed on this data set.</logic>
    <complete>This data set shows selected NAWQA study unit surface-water sampling sites in the
      lower 48 States. The study units are those which became active in either 1991 or 1994. Site
      selection was based on whether the site was grouped within a fixed network and (or) a bed
      sediment and tissue network. NAWQA surface-water sampling sites grouped in other networks are
      not included in this data set.</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>The sampling sites were plotted with their respective drainage basin boundaries as
          provided by the NAWQA Study Units, and were verified to be within the appropriate drainage
          basins.</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Curtis Price</origin>
            <pubdate>20000731</pubdate>
            <title>Locations of USGS NAWQA Sampling Sites</title>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>online</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>200005</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>Date of last NAWQA data aggregation</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>nawqapt</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Spatial and attribute information.</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Hitt, K.J.</origin>
            <origin>Nakagaki, N.</origin>
            <pubdate>19990701</pubdate>
            <title>National Water-Quality Assessment (NAWQA) Study-Unit Investigations in the
              Conterminous United States</title>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Reston, VA</pubplace>
              <publish>U.S. Geological Survey</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <onlink>http://water.usgs.gov/lookup/getspatial?nawqa</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>online</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>19990701</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>Publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>nawqasu1</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Attribute information.</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Lanfear, K.J.</origin>
            <pubdate>19940816</pubdate>
            <title>Counties and county equivalents in the conterminous United States</title>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Reston, VA</pubplace>
              <publish>U.S. Geological Survey</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <onlink>http://water.usgs.gov/lookup/getspatial?county2m</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>online</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>19940816</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>Publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>counties</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Attribute information.</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>The NAWQA sites spatial data set (nawqapt) was generated from multiple files from
          NAWQA's national aggregated database. ARCPLOT was used to select the subset of sites in
          nawqapt that were part of the fixed network, the Occurrence survey and Spatial
          Distribution survey bed sediment and tissue networks, and other sites where bed sediment
          and (or) tissue samples were known to have been collected. These sites were added from
          nawqapt into the reselected set and the data set was saved as a new file. Fields for Study
          Unit ID (Suid), Year (Yr), and network indicators (Fix and Bst) were added and populated
          from information in nawqapt. The attribute Name was populated from additional information
          in nawqapt. Related stations were deleted from the data set. (A related station is a USGS
          station at which samples were collected, located in close proximity to a main or primary
          station. No tributaries, point sources, or any other water-quality impacting features
          exist between the primary and related stations and consequently, samples collected at both
          the primary and related stations are analyzed as if they were collected at a single
          physical location.) The data set was converted from NAD27 to NAD83.</procdesc>
        <srcused>nawqapt</srcused>
        <procdate>20000809</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>The data set was converted to Shapefile format for use in the National Atlas of
          the United States.</procdesc>
        <procdate>200008</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>The attributes Suname, State, and State_fips were added.</procdesc>
        <srcused>nawqasu1</srcused>
        <srcused>counties</srcused>
        <procdate>200012</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>In order to geoprocess spatial files for New York State from the National Atlas
          Data for distribution in CUGIR, the nationwide data files were added to a map document in
          ArcInfo 8.2. Using the geoprocessing wizard's clip function, the spatial files were
          clipped to the detailed New York polygon.</procdesc>
        <procdate>200212</procdate>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
        <direct>Vector</direct>
        <ptvctinf>
          <sdtsterm>
            <sdtstype>Point</sdtstype>
            <ptvctcnt>70</ptvctcnt>
          </sdtsterm>
        </ptvctinf>
      </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <geograph>
        <latres>0.000278</latres>
        <longres>0.000278</longres>
        <geogunit>Decimal degrees</geogunit>
      </geograph>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>GRS1980</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257222</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>Surface-water sampling sites</enttypl>
        <enttypd>The location of major surface-water sampling sites in the National Water-Quality
          Assessment (NAWQA) Program.</enttypd>
        <enttypds>U.S. Geological Survey</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Sw9194x020</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>U.S. Geological Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>1</rdommin>
            <rdommax>1044</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Staid</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The USGS National Water Information System unique station identification
          number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>U.S. Geological Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>01121000</rdommin>
            <rdommax>485634097173801</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Name</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The name of the surface-water sampling site.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>U.S. Geological Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>There is no predefined set of valid site names.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Suid</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The 4-letter abbreviation for a NAWQA study unit. A study unit is a major
          hydrologic system in which NAWQA studies are focused. Study units are geographically
          defined by a combination of ground- and surface-water features and usually encompass more
          than 10,000 square kilometers. (See Gilliom and others, 1995)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>U.S. Geological Survey,
          &lt;http://water.usgs.gov/nawqa/nawqamap.html#TABLE&gt;</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>string</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Yr</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The fiscal year in which the NAWQA study unit became active.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>U.S. Geological Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>91</edomv>
            <edomvd>The study unit became active in 1991.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>U.S. Geological Survey</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>94</edomv>
            <edomvd>The study unit became active in 1994.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>U.S. Geological Survey</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Fix</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>An indication of whether or not a surface water sample site is a fixed network
          site. A fixed network site is one where the stream flow is measured and samples are
          collected at a fixed frequency. The information from the samples includes temperature,
          salinity, suspended sediment, dissolved solids, major ions and metals, nutrients, and
          organic carbon. These characteristics are used to assess the broad- scale spatial and
          temporal character of the stream water, and to assess the transport of inorganic
          constituents by the stream water in relation to hydrologic conditions and environmental
          settings.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>U.S. Geological Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>0</edomv>
            <edomvd>Not a fixed network site.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>U.S. Geological Survey</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>1</edomv>
            <edomvd>A basic fixed site.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>U.S. Geological Survey</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>2</edomv>
            <edomvd>A basic and intensive fixed site. At these sites the sampling frequency is
              increased during selected seasonal periods and pesticide samples are collected
              regularly for 1 year.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>U.S. Geological Survey</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Bst</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>An indication of whether or not bed sediment and (or) tissue samples were collected
          at the site. Samples from these sites are analyzed for trace elements and (or) organic
          contaminants in stream bed sediment and in the tissue of aquatic organisms.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>U.S. Geological Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>0</edomv>
            <edomvd>No bed sediment or tissue sample was collected.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>U.S. Geological Survey</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>1</edomv>
            <edomvd>The site is part of the bed sediment and tissue Occurrence survey and (or)
              Spatial Distribution survey network. Bed sediment and (or) tissue samples were
              collected.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>U.S. Geological Survey</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>2</edomv>
            <edomvd>The site is not part of the bed sediment and tissue Occurrence survey and (or)
              Spatial Distribution survey network, but is part of another sampling network where bed
              sediment and (or) tissue samples were collected.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>U.S. Geological Survey</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Type</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The hydrologic setting of the sampling site.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>U.S. Geological Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>ES</edomv>
            <edomvd>An estuary.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>U.S. Geological Survey</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>LK</edomv>
            <edomvd>A lake or reservoir.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>U.S. Geological Survey</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>SP</edomv>
            <edomvd>A spring.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>U.S. Geological Survey</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>SS</edomv>
            <edomvd>A specific source, for example, a sewage treatment plant discharge
              outflow.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>U.S. Geological Survey</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>SW</edomv>
            <edomvd>A stream.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>U.S. Geological Survey</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>SWME</edomv>
            <edomvd>A meteorological source, where weather information such as precipitation amount
              or air temperature is collected.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>U.S. Geological Survey</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Londd</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The site longitude as a single value, in decimal degrees (NAD83).</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>U.S. Geological Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>-123.37039</rdommin>
            <rdommax>-71.63064</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Latdd</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The site latitude as a single value, in decimal degrees (NAD83).</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>U.S. Geological Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>25.32095</rdommin>
            <rdommax>49.03139</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
        <distrib>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>Albert R. Mann Library</cntorg>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
              <address>Cornell University</address>
              <city>Ithaca</city>
              <state>New York</state>
              <postal>14853</postal>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>607-255-5406</cntvoice>
            <cntemail>mann-ref@cornell.edu</cntemail>
          </cntinfo>
        </distrib>
        <distliab>Cornell University provides these geographic data "as is". Cornell
          University makes no guarantee or warranty concerning the accuracy of
          information contained in the geographic data. Cornell University further
          makes no warranty either expressed or implied, regarding the condition of
          the product or its fitness for any particular purpose. The burden for
          determining fitness for use lies entirely with the user. Although these
          files have been processed successfully on computers at Cornell University,
          no warranty is made by Cornell University regarding the use of these data
          on any other system, nor does the fact of distribution constitute or imply
          any such warranty.</distliab>
        <stdorder>
        <digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>Shapefile</formname>
              <formcont>zipped shapefile</formcont>
              <filedec>zip</filedec>
              <transize>0.06</transize>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/73/19/cugir-007319.zip</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>metadata</formname>
              <formcont>FGDC XML metadata</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/73/19/fgdc.xml</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>HTML metadata</formname>
              <formcont>FGDC HTML metadata</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/73/19/fgdc.html</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
                <digtinfo>
                  <formname>KML</formname>
                  <formcont>generated KML, via WFS</formcont>
                </digtinfo>
                <digtopt>
                  <onlinopt>
                    <computer>
                      <networka>
                        <networkr>https://cugir.library.cornell.edu/geoserver/cugir/wfs?version=1.0.0&amp;request=GetFeature&amp;typeName=cugir007319&amp;outputFormat=application%2Fvnd.google-earth.kml%2Bxml</networkr>
                      </networka>
                    </computer>
                  </onlinopt>
                </digtopt>
              </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>GeoJSON</formname>
              <formcont>generated GeoJSON, via WFS</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir.library.cornell.edu/geoserver/cugir/wfs?version=1.0.0&amp;request=GetFeature&amp;typeName=cugir007319&amp;outputFormat=application%2Fjson</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>OGC:WMS</formname>
              <formcont>WMS, from GeoServer</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir.library.cornell.edu/geoserver/cugir/wms?version=1.1.0&amp;request=GetMap&amp;layers=cugir007319&amp;bbox=-79.10296706,40.84782349,-73.16940294,43.98067151&amp;width=256&amp;height=135&amp;srs=EPSG:4326&amp;format=image/png</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><fees>None</fees></stdorder>
      </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
      <metd>20190524</metd>
      <metc>
        <cntinfo>
          <cntorgp>
            <cntorg>Albert R. Mann Library</cntorg>
          </cntorgp>
          <cntaddr>
            <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
            <address>Albert R. Mann Library</address>
            <city>Ithaca</city>
            <state>New York</state>
            <postal>14853</postal>
            <country>USA</country>
          </cntaddr>
          <cntvoice>607-255-5406</cntvoice>
          <cntemail>mann-ref@cornell.edu</cntemail>
        </cntinfo>
      </metc>
      <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
      <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
      <mettc>local time</mettc>
    </metainfo>
</metadata>
