<!DOCTYPE metadata SYSTEM "http://fgdc.gov/metadata/fgdc-std-001-1998.dtd">
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>New York State Adirondack Park Agency</origin>
        <pubdate>200010</pubdate>
        <title>State Forest Acquisitions, Adirondack Park, 2000</title>
        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Ray Brook, New York State</pubplace>
          <publish>Adirondack Park Agency</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <onlink>https://cugir.library.cornell.edu/catalog/cugir-007740</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>The Adirondack State Forest Acquisition Map contains the old growth timber areas of
        the Adirondack Park, New York State.</abstract>
      <purpose>The data was created for the Adirondack Park Agency (APA) as an historical reference.
        This resource may be used to determine approximate areas of old timber growth in the
        Adirondack Park.</purpose>
      <supplinf>The original data was collected by B. McMartin, who compiled a map of lands acquired
        by the State in the Adirondack Park. This information was based upon various sources,
        including a 1920 series of publications by the NYSDEC. Field checking by McMartin and others
        was also performed. The original map was a 1:250,000+ scale Great Lot map, color coded with
        five category types. Using a light table, this information was later transferred to a
        1:250,000 scale NYSDOT base map. The areas were color-coded using four categories outlined
        on the McMartin map. Digital data was developed by for the area defined by the
        Oswegatchie/Black River watershed in by State University of New York (SUNY) Plattsburgh
        under contract to the APA. Although the OB digital data created by SUNY was not incorporated
        into this coverage, the same attribute scheme was used. Please refer to McMartin, B. 1994.
        The great forest of the Adirondacks, North Country Books, Utica, NY (ISBN: 0925168297) and
        New York State Department of Environmental Conservation 1920, State of New York list of
        lands in the forest preserve. Appendix to 1919 annual report. J.B. Lyon Co., Albany, New
        York.</supplinf>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <sngdate>
          <caldate>2000</caldate>
        </sngdate>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>publication date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>none</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
          <bounding>
            <westbc>-75.302225</westbc>
            <eastbc>-73.370807</eastbc>
            <northbc>44.840283</northbc>
            <southbc>43.107888</southbc>
          </bounding>
        </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>biota</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>LCSH</themekt>
        <themekey>Forests and forestry--New York (State)--Adirondack Mountains
          Region--History.</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
        <themekey>environment</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
              <themekt>CUGIR Category</themekt>
              <themekey>biology</themekey>
<themekey>environment</themekey>
            </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>LCSH</placekt>
        <placekey>Adirondack Forest Preserve</placekey>
        <placekey>Adirondack Park</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>Data is to be used at the scale intended. Please acknowledge the Adirondack Park
      Agency as the source of the data.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Adirondack Park Agency</cntorg>
          <cntper>John W. Barge</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing Address</addrtype>
          <address>P.O. Box 99, Route 86</address>
          <city>Ray Brook</city>
          <state>New York</state>
          <postal>12977</postal>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>518-891-4050 Contact Fascimile: 518-891-3938</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>jwbarge@gw.dec.state.ny.us</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <browse>
              <browsen>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/77/40/preview.png</browsen>
              <browsed>preview of the dataset</browsed>
              <browset>PNG</browset>
            </browse>
    <native>Windows NT, ARC/INFO version 8.0, 313 KB</native>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr/>
    </attracc>
    <logic>Topologically Clean</logic>
    <complete>Topological and attribute accuracy were verified by visually comparing the data in
      checkplots to the original base map.</complete>
    <lineage>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>The NYSDOT source map has UTM crosshairs printed at 15-minute intervals. These
          markings were used to create a list of registration tic marks. The tics represented the
          corners of 15-minute quadrangle map sections. A total of seventy tic marks were included
          in the file. This file was used to register the hardcopy map.The arcs were digitized in
          Arc/Info into one coverage. The boundary of the Adirondack Park was copied into the
          coverage and arcs were digitized up to this boundary. Digitizing was performed on a
          Calcomp 9500 digitizing tablet. The map was digitized into one coverage during several
          sessions, registering the northern and southern portions of the map sheet. The RMS error
          for the sessions ranged from 0.002 to 0.004. The higher registration error for several map
          sections was due to a seam in the base map that runs east/west across the approximate
          middle of the Park. Duplicate lines, intersections and dangling nodes were edited to
          rectify topology errors. The composite coverage was then built with the POLY option. Label
          points were created with a new attribute field, "Code". Valid codes for this field
          included "B", "R", "Y", "X", and "C". An additional code, "U", was added to note polygons
          which had no color code on the original map. These areas were clearly old growth timber
          parcels, but had not been hand-colored. These were generally areas that were not internal
          polygons, i.e., they were located on the edge of other coded, old growth areas. An
          additional attribute field, "Description", was added containing the verbal description of
          the areas. A look-up table called legend.lut was created to cross-reference to the
          coverage. These values for the "Description" field were derived from the SUNY Plattsburg
          checkplot of the Oswagatchie/Black River Basin area. The list below indicates the
          description associated with each code. CODE DESCRIPTION X Virgin stands; never harvested.
          B Parcels acquired in 1871 and 1877 tax sales, or owned by the State prior to 1871. R
          Parcels acquired in 1881 and 1885 tax sales. Y Parcels acquired in 1891 or later via tax
          sale or purchase. C Uncoded on the original map. U Internal polygons not coded on the
          original map. The final data set was converted into an Arc/Info interchange filed named
          timber.e00 for easy data transfer. Quality Assurance/Quality Control was determined by a
          series of tests. Early checkplots of area boundaries were produced on velum and overlayed
          on the source map to check for omission errors. The final coverage was visually inspected
          interactively through comparison to the source material (the hardcopy map). The data set
          was thematically mapped by codes and printed at the same scale as the source material. The
          printed check plot was positioned next to the source material for cross-examination. The
          operator checked for consistency between the source material and the final coverage in
          terms of coding and position of graphic objects and attributes (fields and content).
          Objects with extreme area size (small or large) were identified in ArcView by sorting the
          attribute table by area. Small slivers and unusually large polygons were examined and
          rectified as needed. The accuracy of the type of attribute fields was verified by
          examining the Arc/Info Items listing for the coverage. Creating a summary table in ArcView
          confirmed valid attribute values. Inconsistencies (e.g., missing values) were identified
          and rectified. The coordinate system of the final data set was verified by examining the
          coverage description in Arc/Info, as well as overlaying the data over a coverage known to
          be in the desired projection. Consistency between the known coverage and the final old
          growth timber data layer was evaluated.</procdesc>
        <procdate>unknown</procdate>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
        <direct>Vector</direct>
        <ptvctinf>
          <sdtsterm>
            <sdtstype>G-polygon</sdtstype>
            <ptvctcnt>869</ptvctcnt>
          </sdtsterm>
        </ptvctinf>
      </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <gridsys>
          <gridsysn>Universal Transverse Mercator</gridsysn>
          <utm>
            <utmzone>18</utmzone>
            <transmer>
              <sfctrmer>0.999600</sfctrmer>
              <longcm>-75.000000</longcm>
              <latprjo>0.000000</latprjo>
              <feast>500000.000000</feast>
              <fnorth>0.000000</fnorth>
            </transmer>
          </utm>
        </gridsys>
        <planci>
          <plance>coordinate pair</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>0.000512</absres>
            <ordres>0.000512</ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>meters</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257222</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <distinfo>
        <distrib>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>Albert R. Mann Library</cntorg>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
              <address>Cornell University</address>
              <city>Ithaca</city>
              <state>New York</state>
              <postal>14853</postal>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>607-255-5406</cntvoice>
            <cntemail>mann-ref@cornell.edu</cntemail>
          </cntinfo>
        </distrib>
        <distliab>Cornell University provides these geographic data "as is". Cornell
          University makes no guarantee or warranty concerning the accuracy of
          information contained in the geographic data. Cornell University further
          makes no warranty either expressed or implied, regarding the condition of
          the product or its fitness for any particular purpose. The burden for
          determining fitness for use lies entirely with the user. Although these
          files have been processed successfully on computers at Cornell University,
          no warranty is made by Cornell University regarding the use of these data
          on any other system, nor does the fact of distribution constitute or imply
          any such warranty.</distliab>
        <stdorder>
        <digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>Shapefile</formname>
              <formcont>zipped shapefile</formcont>
              <filedec>zip</filedec>
              <transize>0.14</transize>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/77/40/cugir-007740.zip</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>metadata</formname>
              <formcont>FGDC XML metadata</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/77/40/fgdc.xml</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>HTML metadata</formname>
              <formcont>FGDC HTML metadata</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/77/40/fgdc.html</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
                <digtinfo>
                  <formname>KML</formname>
                  <formcont>generated KML, via WFS</formcont>
                </digtinfo>
                <digtopt>
                  <onlinopt>
                    <computer>
                      <networka>
                        <networkr>https://cugir.library.cornell.edu/geoserver/cugir/wfs?version=1.0.0&amp;request=GetFeature&amp;typeName=cugir007740&amp;outputFormat=application%2Fvnd.google-earth.kml%2Bxml</networkr>
                      </networka>
                    </computer>
                  </onlinopt>
                </digtopt>
              </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>GeoJSON</formname>
              <formcont>generated GeoJSON, via WFS</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir.library.cornell.edu/geoserver/cugir/wfs?version=1.0.0&amp;request=GetFeature&amp;typeName=cugir007740&amp;outputFormat=application%2Fjson</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>OGC:WMS</formname>
              <formcont>WMS, from GeoServer</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir.library.cornell.edu/geoserver/cugir/wms?version=1.1.0&amp;request=GetMap&amp;layers=cugir007740&amp;bbox=-75.36016754,43.05591615,-73.31286446,44.89225485&amp;width=256&amp;height=229&amp;srs=EPSG:4326&amp;format=image/png</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><fees>None</fees></stdorder>
      </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
      <metd>20190524</metd>
      <metc>
        <cntinfo>
          <cntorgp>
            <cntorg>Albert R. Mann Library</cntorg>
          </cntorgp>
          <cntaddr>
            <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
            <address>Albert R. Mann Library</address>
            <city>Ithaca</city>
            <state>New York</state>
            <postal>14853</postal>
            <country>USA</country>
          </cntaddr>
          <cntvoice>607-255-5406</cntvoice>
          <cntemail>mann-ref@cornell.edu</cntemail>
        </cntinfo>
      </metc>
      <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
      <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
      <mettc>local time</mettc>
    </metainfo>
</metadata>
