<!DOCTYPE metadata SYSTEM "http://fgdc.gov/metadata/fgdc-std-001-1998.dtd">
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>U.S. Geological Survey</origin>
        <origin>U.S. Environmental Protection Agency</origin>
        <pubdate>1990</pubdate>
        <title>1:250,000 Scale Land Use and Land Cover, New York, 1990</title>
        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Reston, VA</pubplace>
          <publish>U.S. Geological Survey</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <onlink>https://cugir.library.cornell.edu/catalog/cugir-008190</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>This is derived from land use/land cover digital data collected by USGS and coverted to ARC/INFO by the EPA. This data is useful for environmental assessment of land use patterns with respect to water quality analysis, growth management, and other types of environmental impact assessment. Use may be limited due to currency. Land use and land cover data (LU/LC) collected by USGS NMD is useful for environmental assessment of land use patterns with respect to water quality analysis, growth management, and other types of environmental impact assessment. Data are meant to be used by quadrangle, or among adjacent quadrangles where temporarily contiguous. Can be used in any geographic application where intermediate scale land use data are appropriate and the dates are representative.</abstract>
      <purpose>The purpose of the original files was to convert GIRAS data into EPA's standard GIS software. For use with other demographic and spatial data.</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <sngdate>
          <caldate>1990</caldate>
        </sngdate>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Publication Date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Unknown</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
          <bounding>
            <westbc>-80</westbc>
            <eastbc>-69.883331</eastbc>
            <northbc>45</northbc>
            <southbc>40</southbc>
          </bounding>
        </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>Land Use</themekey>
        <themekey>Land Cover</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
        <themekey>environment</themekey>
        <themekey>planningCadastre</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
              <themekt>CUGIR Category</themekt>
              <themekey>landcover</themekey>
<themekey>environment</themekey>
<themekey>property</themekey>
            </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>None</placekt>
        <placekey>New York</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>None. Acknowledgement of the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency would be appreciated.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Albert R. Mann Library</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>Cornell University</address>
          <city>Ithaca</city>
          <state>New York</state>
          <postal>14853</postal>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>607-255-5406</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>mann_ref@cornell.edu</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <browse>
              <browsen>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/81/90/preview.png</browsen>
              <browsed>preview of the dataset</browsed>
              <browset>PNG</browset>
            </browse>
    <native>Dataset processing and conversion at USGS was done using ARC/INFO version 6.</native>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>No information provided from original dataset producers.</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <logic>Polygon and chain-node topology present.</logic>
    <complete>Each quadrangle of land use data has a different representative date. Date ranges from mid 1970s to early 1980s are common. When joined together these quadrangles will not likely match along edges due to differences in interpretation and time coverage. Edges of each map file were manually digitized and may not join neighboring maps. If GIRASNEAT program has been applied (see LOG at end) then edges have been mathematically recalculated to join without overlap or gaps in coverage with adjacent maps. The GIRAS series can include several themes of spatial data. The most common, described here, is the land use and land cover data. Land use was mapped and coded using the Anderson classification system (Anderson et al., 1976) which is a hierarchical system of general (level 1) to more specific (level 2) characterization. Some agencies have taken this to a level 3 classification -- but this has not been done in the GIRAS series.</complete>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>U.S. Geological Survey</origin>
            <pubdate>1990</pubdate>
            <title>USGeoData 1:250,000 and 1:100,000 Scale Land Use and Land Cover and Associated Maps Digital Data</title>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Reston, VA</pubplace>
              <publish>U.S. Geological Survey</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <onlink>ftp://ftp.epa.gov/pub/spdata/EPAGIRAS/</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>Online</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>1977</begdate>
              <enddate>1980s</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>Publication Date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>None</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Served as basis for extraction of New York State data.</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Information concerning creation of original USGS files taken from metadata posted by EPA: "GIRAS files are received by the USGS in 9-track ASCII format, one file per quadrangle. Files are loaded onto the hard disk of the computer from tape. Data are then processed with the GIRASARC2 program written in Arc Macro Language, part of the ARC/INFO geographic information system. This program was written by the USGS Water Resources Division to process the data into a consistent ARC/INFO format with a minimum of intervention. This GIRASARC2 AML program does the following: converts the GIRAS data to ARC/INFO, reconstructs topology, creating line and polygon features, transforms the coverage into UTM and then, optionally into Albers Equal Area, using the registration points listed in the GIRAS file, notes transformation error, writing it to the bottom of the narrative file, generates a synthetic neatline based on the mathematically-determined corners of the map, loads available documentation into a series of companion documentation files with each data set, data may then be clipped against or extended to the synthetic neatline for ease in merging adjacent maps at a later date. A GIRASNEAT AML program does the following: standardize processing of coverages after use of girasarc2 AML, clips in-cover with neatline cover, dissolves polygon boundaries between polygon with the same item attribute snaps exterior arcs to the arcs of the neatline cover with a tolerance of 40 meters. Original conversion from GIRAS to ARC (see LOG for date and user ID). Data are reviewed visually by the user responsible for executing the GIRASARC2 program. The GIRASARC2 and GIRASNEAT programs were executed in Arc Macro Language to create this data set. The DOCUMENT AML (version 1.0) was used to manage the documentation and create [the original EPA] metadata file."</procdesc>
        <procdate>Unknown</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Information concerning creation of original USGS files taken from metadata posted by EPA using Kenora Quadrangle as example. Steps: 1) GIRASARC KENORA TMPCOV ; 2) BUILD TMPCOV POLY ; 3) CREATE KENLL ; 4) PROJECT COVER KENLL /EXDISK2/ED/GIRASNEW/WORK/KEN ; 5) TRANSFORM TMPCOV /EXDISK2/ED/GIRASNEW/WORK/KEN ; 6) RENAME KEN KENU ; 7) PROJECT COVER KENU KEN ; 8) BUILD KEN POLY ; 9) GIRASDOCUMENT KEN ED ; 10) GIRASARC2 KENORA KEN ALBERS -96 00 00 ED ; 11) CLIP KEN KENNL XXCOV POLY 1 ; 12) GIRASARC KENORA TMPCOV ; 13) BUILD TMPCOV POLY ; 14) CREATE KENLL ; 15) PROJECT COVER KENLL /EXDISK2/ED/GIRASNEW/WORK/KEN ; 16) TRANSFORM TMPCOV /EXDISK2/ED/GIRASNEW/WORK/KEN ; 17) RENAME KEN KENU ; 18) PROJECT COVER KENU KEN ; 19) BUILD KEN POLY ; 20) GIRASDOCUMENT KEN ED ; 21) GIRASARC2 KENORA KEN ALBERS -96 00 00 ED ; 22) CLIP KEN KENNL XXCOV POLY 1 ; 23) COPY XXCOV LKE49094 ; 24) BUILD LKE49094 LINE ; 25) ARCEDIT /EXDISK2/ED/GIRASNEW/WORK/LKE49094 ; 26) BUILD LKE49094 POLY ; 27) GIRASNEAT KEN LKE49094 KENNL # SNAP ED</procdesc>
        <procdate>19930426</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Downloaded file in Arc/Info Interchange (.e00) format. File imported into ARC/INFO, version 7.1.2. Reprojected data from Alberts Equal Area to UTM, zone 18, meters using GRS80. Exported and gzip compressed.</procdesc>
        <procdate>199905</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Reprojected from UTM/meter to Geographic/decimal degrees using GRS80 and NAD83. Then used Shapearc command to convert from Arc/Info coverage format to shapefile. Files compressed using tar and gzip.</procdesc>
        <procdate>199905</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>CUGIR staff merged 18 separate 1x2-degree quads to a single shapefile covering New York state; joined land use classification names; and recalculated area and perimeter in square meters based on EPSG:32618 (WGS 84 UTM 18N).</procdesc>
        <procdate>20170811</procdate>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
        <direct>Vector</direct>
        <ptvctinf>
          <sdtsterm>
            <sdtstype>G-polygon</sdtstype>
            <ptvctcnt>108234</ptvctcnt>
          </sdtsterm>
        </ptvctinf>
      </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <geograph>
        <latres>0.023</latres>
        <longres>0.023</longres>
        <geogunit>Decimal Degrees</geogunit>
      </geograph>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>Geodedic Reference System 80</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257222101</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>lulc250k</enttypl>
        <enttypd>Land use polygon at 1:250,000 scale</enttypd>
        <enttypds>GIRAS digital data</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>LUCODE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The salient attribute managed for this polygon data set in the polygon attribute table (PAT) is the column named LUCODE containing the Anderson level 2 classification. The first digit represents the level one value and the second digit (ones place) represents the subdivision of the level 1 or level 2 value. The Anderson land use codes are: 1 Urban or built-up land, 11 Residental, 12 Commercial and services, 13 Industrial, 14 Transportation, communication, utilities, 15 Industrial and commercial complexes, 16 Mixed urban or built-up land, 17 Other urban or built-up land, 2 Agricultural land, 21 Cropland and pasture, 22 Orchards, groves, vineyards, nurseries, and ornamental horticultural, 23 Confined feeeding operations, 24 Other agricultural land, 3 Rangeland, 31 Herbaceous rangeland, 32 Shrub and brush rangeland, 33 Mixed rangeland, 4 Forest land, 41 Deciduous forest land, 42 Evergreen forest land, 43 Mixed forest land, 5 Water, 51 Streams and canals, 52 Lakes, 53 Reservoirs, 54 Bays and estuaries, 6 Wetland, 61 Forested wetland, 62 Nonforested wetland, 7 Barren land, 71 Dry salt flats, 72 Beaches, 73 Sandy areas not beaches, 74 Bare exposed rock, 75 Strip mines, quarries, gravel pits, 76 Transitional areas, 8 Tundra, 81 Shrub and brush tundra, 82 Herbaceous tundra, 83 Bare ground, 84 Wet tundra, 85 Mixed tundra, 9 Perennial snow or ice, 91 Perennial snowfields, 92 Glaciers</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>GIRAS</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <codesetd>
            <codesetn>Anderson land use classification codes</codesetn>
            <codesets>See Anderson, Hardy, Roach and Witmer. 1976. "Land Use and Land Cover Classification System for Use with Remote Sensor Data." USGS Professional Paper 964.</codesets>
          </codesetd>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>LUTEXT</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The name/description corresponding to the LUCODE.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>GIRAS</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Text string</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>AREA</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Area of polygon in square meters</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Computed</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>positive integer</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>PERIMETER</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Perimeter of polygon in square meters</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Computed</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>positive integer</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
        <distrib>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>Albert R. Mann Library</cntorg>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
              <address>Cornell University</address>
              <city>Ithaca</city>
              <state>New York</state>
              <postal>14853</postal>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>607-255-5406</cntvoice>
            <cntemail>mann-ref@cornell.edu</cntemail>
          </cntinfo>
        </distrib>
        <distliab>Cornell University provides these geographic data "as is". Cornell
          University makes no guarantee or warranty concerning the accuracy of
          information contained in the geographic data. Cornell University further
          makes no warranty either expressed or implied, regarding the condition of
          the product or its fitness for any particular purpose. The burden for
          determining fitness for use lies entirely with the user. Although these
          files have been processed successfully on computers at Cornell University,
          no warranty is made by Cornell University regarding the use of these data
          on any other system, nor does the fact of distribution constitute or imply
          any such warranty.</distliab>
        <stdorder>
        <digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>Shapefile</formname>
              <formcont>zipped shapefile</formcont>
              <filedec>zip</filedec>
              <transize>25.96</transize>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/81/90/cugir-008190.zip</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>metadata</formname>
              <formcont>FGDC XML metadata</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/81/90/fgdc.xml</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>HTML metadata</formname>
              <formcont>FGDC HTML metadata</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/81/90/fgdc.html</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
                <digtinfo>
                  <formname>KML</formname>
                  <formcont>generated KML, via WFS</formcont>
                </digtinfo>
                <digtopt>
                  <onlinopt>
                    <computer>
                      <networka>
                        <networkr>https://cugir.library.cornell.edu/geoserver/cugir/wfs?version=1.0.0&amp;request=GetFeature&amp;typeName=cugir008190&amp;outputFormat=application%2Fvnd.google-earth.kml%2Bxml</networkr>
                      </networka>
                    </computer>
                  </onlinopt>
                </digtopt>
              </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>GeoJSON</formname>
              <formcont>generated GeoJSON, via WFS</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir.library.cornell.edu/geoserver/cugir/wfs?version=1.0.0&amp;request=GetFeature&amp;typeName=cugir008190&amp;outputFormat=application%2Fjson</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>OGC:WMS</formname>
              <formcont>WMS, from GeoServer</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir.library.cornell.edu/geoserver/cugir/wms?version=1.1.0&amp;request=GetMap&amp;layers=cugir008190&amp;bbox=-80.30350007,39.85,-69.57983093,45.15&amp;width=256&amp;height=126&amp;srs=EPSG:4326&amp;format=image/png</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><fees>None</fees></stdorder>
      </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
      <metd>20190524</metd>
      <metc>
        <cntinfo>
          <cntorgp>
            <cntorg>Albert R. Mann Library</cntorg>
          </cntorgp>
          <cntaddr>
            <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
            <address>Albert R. Mann Library</address>
            <city>Ithaca</city>
            <state>New York</state>
            <postal>14853</postal>
            <country>USA</country>
          </cntaddr>
          <cntvoice>607-255-5406</cntvoice>
          <cntemail>mann-ref@cornell.edu</cntemail>
        </cntinfo>
      </metc>
      <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
      <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
      <mettc>local time</mettc>
    </metainfo>
</metadata>
