<!DOCTYPE metadata SYSTEM "http://fgdc.gov/metadata/fgdc-std-001-1998.dtd">
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>U.S. Geological Survey</origin>
        <pubdate>unknown</pubdate>
        <title>Index of Digital Elevation Models (DEM), New York</title>
        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Reston, VA</pubplace>
          <publish>U.S. Geological Survey</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <onlink>https://cugir.library.cornell.edu/catalog/cugir-008186</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>This is an index of all the available DEM (digital elevation model) tiles within New York state.  Download links are provided for each quad.  Each DEM raster has a pixel resolution of approximately 10 meters.  Elevation values were derived from USGS contour lines mapped at a scale of 1:24,000.</abstract>
      <purpose>DEMs can be used as source data for digital orthophotos and
                as layers in geographic information systems for earth science
                analysis. DEMs can also serve as tools for volumetric analysis,
                for site location of towers, or for drainage basin delineation.
                These data are collected as part of the National Mapping
                Program.</purpose>
      <supplinf>A Digital Elevation Model (DEM) contains a series of
                elevations ordered from south to north with the order of the
                columns from west to east. The DEM is formatted as one ASCII
                header record (A-record), followed by a series of profile
                records (B-records) each of which include a short B-record
                header followed by a series of ASCII integer elevations per each
                profile. The last physical record of the DEM is an accuracy
                record (C-record). The 7.5-minute DEM (10- by 10-m data spacing,
                elevations in decimeters) is cast on the Universal Transverse
                Mercator (UTM) projection (the quads UTM zone can be found in
                the header record (Record A)) in the North American Datum of
                1927. It provides coverage in 7.5- by 7.5-minute blocks. Each
                product provides the same coverage as a standard USGS 7.5-minute
                quadrangle, but overedges are published as separate DEM files.
                Coverage is available for all quads completely contained within
                New York State, plus some additional ones falling along the
                borders and containing significant area of the State's land.

                7.5-minute DEMs have rows and columns which vary in length
                and are staggered. The UTM bounding coordinates form a
                quadrilateral (no two sides are parallel to each other), rather
                than a rectangle. The user will need to pad out the uneven rows
                and columns with blanks or flagged data values, if a rectangle
                is required for the user's application. Some software vendors
                have incorporated this function into their software for input of
                standard formatted USGS DEMs.</supplinf>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <sngdate>
          <caldate>1995</caldate>
        </sngdate>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>process date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Irregular</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
          <bounding>
            <westbc>-79.75</westbc>
            <eastbc>-71.75</eastbc>
            <northbc>45.0</northbc>
            <southbc>40.5</southbc>
          </bounding>
        </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>digital elevation model</themekey>
        <themekey>digital terrain model</themekey>
        <themekey>hypsography</themekey>
        <themekey>altitude</themekey>
        <themekey>topography</themekey>
        <themekey>index map</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
        <themekey>elevation</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
              <themekt>CUGIR Category</themekt>
              <themekey>index map</themekey>
<themekey>elevation</themekey>
            </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>None</placekt>
        <placekey>New York</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>1. The NYS DEC and the U.S. Geological Survey asks to be
            credited in derived products. 2. Secondary Distribution of the data
            is not allowed. 3. Any documentation provided is an integral part of
            the data set. Failure to use the documentation in conjunction with
            the digital data constitutes misuse of the data. 4. Although every
            effort has been made to ensure the accuracy of information, errors
            may be reflected in the data supplied. The user must be aware of
            data conditions and bear responsibility for the appropriate use of
            the information with respect to possible errors, original map scale,
            collection methodology, currency of data, and other conditions.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>New York State Department of Environmental
                        Conservation. Division of Water</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Watershed Geographic Information Technologies Support
                    Group, Chief</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>625 Broadway</address>
          <address>4th floor</address>
          <city>Albany</city>
          <state>New York</state>
          <postal>12233-3500</postal>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>518-402-8259</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>watergis@gw.dec.state.ny.us</cntemail>
        <cntinst>All questions regarding metadata and/or data should go
                    through the internal DEC contact.</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <native>24,000 scale hypsographic contour linework drawn by
            photogrametric, plane table or other methods by USGS, US Army Corp
            of Engineers, Tennessee Valley Authority or others. Linework copied
            onto stable-base mylar. Raster image of linework created by USGS,
            Reston, with Optronics drum scanner at an aperture of 20um, to give
            an equivalent resolution of 1024 DPI. Raster data converted to
            vector with line-center algorithm in LT4X v. 3.1, 11/11/93, by John
            Dabritz of Infotec Development Inc. Grid elevations calculated with
            8-profile weighted linear interpolation, with cubic smoothing of
            slope at the contour line as per algorithm in above mentioned LT4X
            v. - export in DEM format, UTM meters, - grid height and width of 10
            mt, - clipping (overedge) coordinate in UTM mt, - input coord feet
            or meters (depending on source material), output in
            meters/decimeters, - DEM grid points which are on a profile section
            longer than 80 mt are smoothed by passing the grid through a low
            pass-filter twice. The filter size (see below) is of 9 cell
            diameters (aprox 9 mt). The purpose here is to leave well-contoured
            areas untouched while smoothing areas of less than 5-2.5% slope (to
            lessen streaking in flat areas typical of multiple-profile DEM
            derivation). - cubic smoothing of elevation profile across contours
            to 35% of the distance between adjacent contours. These profiles
            have a smaller, but still discontinuous change in slope at contour
            intersection than if not rounded. - 9 cell diameter for smoothing
            reach, - use all 8 directions (from grid point to N, S, E, W ,NE,
            NW, SE, SW) for each cell, - no line feeds. export dem
            &lt;contour data name&gt; 2 10.00 10.00 2 1 4 80 2 0.35 9 8
            0</native>
    <crossref>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>US Geological Survey</origin>
        <pubdate>unknown</pubdate>
        <title>Digital Elevation Model (DEM)</title>
        <onlink>http://eros.usgs.gov/guides/dem.html</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </crossref>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>10 mt gridding cell spacing is the maximun that can be
                meaningfully extracted from hypsography contour lines. This
                allows very good hypsographic contour reproduction in all areas
                except very flat ones. Elevation_resolution_ is 1 decimeter (0.1
                meter). Elevation accuracy is 24,000 contour data, i.e.
                plus/minus half the contour interval.</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <logic>The fidelity of the relationships encoded in the data structure
            of the DEM are automatically verified using a USGS software program
            upon completion of the data production cycle. The test verifies full
            compliance to the DEM specification.</logic>
    <complete>DEM visually inspected using Delta3D version 2.0, 1995 by John
            Dabritz and S. Phan of Infotec Development Inc. Checked for
            completness and drainage characteristics matching the USGS
            Hydrography Digital Line Graphs published at the same time as the
            model. Further validation for logical consistency performed previous
            to submission for archiving.</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>The horizontal accuracy of the DEM is expressed as an
                    estimated root mean square error (RMSE). The estimate of the
                    RMSE is based upon horizontal accuracy tests of the DEM
                    source materials with equal to or less than intended
                    horizontal RMSE error of the DEM. The testing of horizontal
                    accuracy of the source materials is accomplished by
                    comparing the planimetric (X and Y) coordinates of
                    well-defined ground points with the coordinates of the same
                    points as determined from a source of higher accuracy.</horizpar>
        <qhorizpa>
          <horizpav>3 meters (estimated)</horizpav>
          <horizpae>Digital elevation models meet horizontal National
                        Map Accuracy Standards (NMAS) accuracy
                    requirements.</horizpae>
        </qhorizpa>
      </horizpa>
      <vertacc>
        <vertaccr>A vertical RMSE of one-half of the contour interval of
                    the source map is the maximum permitted. Systematic errors
                    may not exceed the contour interval of the source graphic.
                    Level 2 DEMs have been processed or smoothed for consistency
                    and edited to remove identifiable systematic errors.</vertaccr>
        <qvertpa>
          <vertaccv>6 to 8 meters</vertaccv>
          <vertacce>DEMs meet vertical National Map Accuracy Standards
                        (NMAS) accuracy requirements. Vertical Positional
                        Accuracy Vaue varies with each quad.</vertacce>
        </qvertpa>
      </vertacc>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>U.S. Geological Survey</origin>
            <pubdate>Unknown</pubdate>
            <pubtime>Unknown</pubtime>
            <title>Albany</title>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>EROS Data Center, SD</pubplace>
              <publish>U.S. Geological Survey</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>mylar separate from original color separation plate</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>unknown</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>CONTOUR1</srccitea>
        <srccontr>elevation values for interpolation</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>U.S. Geological Survey or National Geodetic
                            Survey (NGS) (ed.)</origin>
            <pubdate>Unknown</pubdate>
            <pubtime>Unknown</pubtime>
            <title>project control</title>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>EROS Data Center, SD</pubplace>
              <publish>U.S. Geological Survey</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>field notes</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>unknown</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>CONTROL1</srccitea>
        <srccontr>ground control points</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>U.S. Geological Survey (ed.)</origin>
            <pubdate>Unknown</pubdate>
            <pubtime>Unknown</pubtime>
            <title>photo ID number</title>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>EROS Data Center, SD</pubplace>
              <publish>U.S. Geological Survey</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>transparency</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>unknown</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>PHOTO1</srccitea>
        <srccontr>elevation values from photogrametry</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>The process can be seen as divided into several tasks,
                    each with associated sub-processes. A. Original Data Source
                    Preparation: 1. The United States Geological Service (USGS)
                    office of Map Production (Mid Continent Mapping Center,
                    Rolla, MO) selects the most recent original printing plates
                    (1:24,000 or 1:25,000 scale) for each published quadrangle
                    map. These plates are archived under controlled
                    environmental conditions and are produced from the original
                    map scripting materials onto dimensionally stable material
                    (Mylar). A copy of the separate is made by contact methods
                    onto photosensitive, opaque, dimensionally stable material.
                    The separate plate copy is shipped to the USGS Mapping
                    Applications Center (Reston, VA). 2. The MAC scans the
                    separate plate with an Ektaprint (a.k.a. Optronics) drum
                    scanner with an aperture of 24um (corresponding to a linear
                    resolution of approx 1030 DPI) into a run-length encoded
                    (RLE) formatted raster file. Contours lines have typically a
                    thickness of 25 to 30 pixels. The file, typically between 10
                    and 20 Mb, would be checked for completeness and distortion.
                    If satisfactory MAC forwards both the raster file, the plate
                    separate and the corresponding published quadrangle to the
                    digitization workshop at the New York State Department of
                    Environmental Conservation Water GIS unit in Albany, NY. B.
                    Raster file batch processing 1. The raster file was loaded
                    into Line Tracer for X Windows (LT4X, Infotec Inc.,
                    Portland, Oregon) version 3.1. With it is georegistered and
                    trimmed of any excess margin. 2. The file is put through an
                    automated raster-to-vector batch process in which a vector
                    following the center of the raster line is created, with a
                    minimum vertex separation of 25 pixels. Once the vector has
                    been calculated and the topology of the resultant data
                    established, the resolution of the original raster was
                    reduced to 500 DPI, to allow faster processing in the
                    succeeding steps. C. Vector Contour Edit, Edge Matching and
                    Labeling. 1. The vectorized contours are edited carefully to
                    correct any line breaks, vector webbing (due to pen
                    thickness or lack of resolution of the original's drafting
                    process), labels and special line symbols (depressions, road
                    fills, etc). 2. The contours are labeled with their
                    corresponding elevations, as tagged in the original
                    material. 3. The eight adjoining maps' vector contours are
                    brought in and checked against those of the map being
                    edited. Vectors of matching labels are snapped together if
                    the gap is less than 3 line-thicknesses. Otherwise they are
                    tagged as "disagreement in the original" (see DLG standards
                    for hypsography layer). For each border only one of the maps
                    is edited. 4. An independent quality control check of
                    contour edits and labeling is carried out. 5. The Digital
                    Elevation Model is interpolated in a batch process (see
                    "Native Dataset Environment" above). D. DEM Edit and Quality
                    Control 1. The resultant DEM is loaded in Delta3D (Infotec
                    Inc., Portland, OR) v. 2.1, together with the corresponding
                    hydrography vectors. The DEM is checked for the presence of
                    irregular patterns, in which case it is returned to the
                    previous process; water body height (e.g. in large lakes) is
                    set for all grid cells within the water body; and drainage
                    along vector streams is enforced by lowering cells higher
                    than the upstream one along the stream. Water retention
                    areas (wetlands, marshes...) are not modified except for
                    stream entrance and exit. - Edge matching with the adjoining
                    eight DEMs. 2. From thirty to thirty-five height reference
                    markers are collected from the corresponding cultural
                    separate for the quadrangle. These are compared to heights
                    as read from the DEM and an statistical RMS is calculated,
                    this is recorded in the DEM's C record. 3. The quadrangle
                    record A is filled and checked for consistency. 4. A final
                    DEM-formatted elevation dataset for the quadrangle is
                    recorded. E. Final Quality Control and Databasing 1. The DEM
                    file is shipped to USGS's Rocky Mountain Mapping Center
                    (Boulder, CO). There it undergoes a separate quality control
                    process which essentially mimics D. 2. The corresponding
                    quality control flags are established. The DEM is
                    sub-sampled to 30 mt grid spacing and the resultant file is
                    forwarded to USGS's EROS Data Center, were it is catalogued
                    into the National Elevation database. The 10 mt grid spacing
                    file is returned to NYS DEC, from where it is forwarded to
                    Cornell University's Mann Library.</procdesc>
        <procdate>Unknown</procdate>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Vector</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>G-polygon</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>961</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <gridsys>
          <gridsysn>Universal Transverse Mercator</gridsysn>
          <utm>
            <utmzone>17 or 18 or 19</utmzone>
            <transmer>
              <sfctrmer>.9996</sfctrmer>
              <longcm>+075.000000</longcm>
              <latprjo>+00.000000</latprjo>
              <feast>0</feast>
              <fnorth>0</fnorth>
            </transmer>
          </utm>
        </gridsys>
        <planci>
          <plance>row and column</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>10</absres>
            <ordres>10</ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>Meters</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1927</horizdn>
        <ellips>Clarke 1866</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378206.4</semiaxis>
        <denflat>294.9787</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
    <vertdef>
      <altsys>
        <altdatum>National Geodetic Vertical Datum of 1929</altdatum>
        <altres>1</altres>
        <altunits>decimeters</altunits>
        <altenc>Explicit elevation coordinate included with horizontal
                    coordinates</altenc>
      </altsys>
    </vertdef>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <overview>
      <eaover>The digital elevation model is composed of an elevation
                value linked to a grid cell location representing a gridded form
                of a topographic map hypsography overlay. Each grid cell entity
                contains an 8-character value between -32,767.0 and 32,768.0.</eaover>
      <eadetcit>U.S. department of the Interior, U.S. Geological Survey,
                1992, Standards for digital elevation models: Reston, VA, a
                hypertext version of the Digital Elevation Model (DEM) is
                available at: http://eros.usgs.gov/guides/dem.html (see Cross
                Reference)</eadetcit>
    </overview>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
        <distrib>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>Albert R. Mann Library</cntorg>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
              <address>Cornell University</address>
              <city>Ithaca</city>
              <state>New York</state>
              <postal>14853</postal>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>607-255-5406</cntvoice>
            <cntemail>mann-ref@cornell.edu</cntemail>
          </cntinfo>
        </distrib>
        <distliab>Cornell University provides these geographic data "as is". Cornell
          University makes no guarantee or warranty concerning the accuracy of
          information contained in the geographic data. Cornell University further
          makes no warranty either expressed or implied, regarding the condition of
          the product or its fitness for any particular purpose. The burden for
          determining fitness for use lies entirely with the user. Although these
          files have been processed successfully on computers at Cornell University,
          no warranty is made by Cornell University regarding the use of these data
          on any other system, nor does the fact of distribution constitute or imply
          any such warranty.</distliab>
        <stdorder>
        <digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>GeoJSON</formname>
              <formcont>OpenIndexMaps</formcont>
              <transize>0.08</transize>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/81/86/cugir-008186-index.geojson</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>metadata</formname>
              <formcont>FGDC XML metadata</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/81/86/fgdc.xml</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>HTML metadata</formname>
              <formcont>FGDC HTML metadata</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/81/86/fgdc.html</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><fees>None</fees></stdorder>
      </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
      <metd>20190524</metd>
      <metc>
        <cntinfo>
          <cntorgp>
            <cntorg>Albert R. Mann Library</cntorg>
          </cntorgp>
          <cntaddr>
            <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
            <address>Albert R. Mann Library</address>
            <city>Ithaca</city>
            <state>New York</state>
            <postal>14853</postal>
            <country>USA</country>
          </cntaddr>
          <cntvoice>607-255-5406</cntvoice>
          <cntemail>mann-ref@cornell.edu</cntemail>
        </cntinfo>
      </metc>
      <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
      <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
      <mettc>local time</mettc>
    </metainfo>
</metadata>
