<!DOCTYPE metadata SYSTEM "http://fgdc.gov/metadata/fgdc-std-001-1998.dtd">
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Tompkins County ITS GIS Division</origin>
        <origin>Tompkins County Assessment Department</origin>
        <pubdate>20060701</pubdate>
        <title>Tax Parcels, Tompkins County NY, 2006</title>
        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
        <onlink>https://cugir.library.cornell.edu/catalog/cugir-007899</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>The active tax parcel boundaries for all of Tompkins County for
        the current tax year. The boundaries represent the parcel boundaries
        shown on the final paper maps for the current tax year.</abstract>
      <purpose>The parcel boundaries represent legal descriptions of property
        ownership, as recorded in various public documents in the Tompkins
        County Clerk's Office. This is the database of property ownership and
        information in Tompkins County, as mandated by New York State. This
        database can be related to the New York State Office of Real Property
        Services (RPS) database extract using either the SWISPRINTK field or the
        PARCELKEY field.</purpose>
      <supplinf>Properties that are tracked by an account number (utilities,
        railroads, etc.) may be shown as several separate tax parcel boundaries,
        with different tax map print keys, even though they are tracked in the
        RPS database under the same account number and treated as one single
        parcel. The parcel region will show these account-number properties as
        one tax parcel boundary. As of 2006, the tax parcel boundaries have not
        been edge-matched by municipality, except for Villages within their
        respective Town. This data set is derived from the tax parcel region for
        all tax parcel data sets in Tompkins County and is currently maintained
        in separate geodatabase feature classes by municipality.</supplinf>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <sngdate>
          <caldate>20060701</caldate>
        </sngdate>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>publication date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Continually, with new versions published annually, each July
      1</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
          <bounding>
            <westbc>-76.696211</westbc>
            <eastbc>-76.237347</eastbc>
            <northbc>42.627348</northbc>
            <southbc>42.262716</southbc>
          </bounding>
        </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>property</themekey>
        <themekey>ownership</themekey>
        <themekey>land record</themekey>
        <themekey>parcel</themekey>
        <themekey>tax</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
        <themekey>boundaries</themekey>
        <themekey>planningCadastre</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>LCSH</themekt>
        <themekey>Real property</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
              <themekt>CUGIR Category</themekt>
              <themekey>boundaries</themekey>
<themekey>property</themekey>
            </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>None</placekt>
        <placekey>Tompkins County, New York</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>The following statement must be included with any products that
      use or are derived from this data set: Data contained in this product was
      originally produced by the Tompkins County ITS GIS Division and the
      Tompkins County Assessment Department and may not be reproduced or
      redistributed without the express written consent of the originators. The
      originators do not warrant the accuracy or completeness of the information
      portrayed by the data. The data contained herein is for visualization
      purposes only and cannot be used for conveyance. Property boundaries are
      based on legal documents, aerial photos, software interpolation, and
      registration to the 1991 Tompkins County Digital Planimetric Files and,
      therefore, may differ from legal property descriptions. For complete legal
      descriptions and conveyance, please refer to the appropriate deeds,
      surveys, and other legal documents.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Cattyann Campbell</cntper>
          <cntorg>Tompkins County ITS GIS Division</cntorg>
        </cntperp>
        <cntpos>GIS Project Leader</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>
          <address>128 East Buffalo Street</address>
          <city>Ithaca</city>
          <state>New York</state>
          <postal>14850</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>(607) 274-5418</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>(607) 274-5420</cntfax>
        <cntemail>gis@tompkins-co.org</cntemail>
        <hours>M-F 8:30 a.m. to 4:30 p.m.</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <browse>
              <browsen>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/78/99/preview.png</browsen>
              <browsed>preview of the dataset</browsed>
              <browset>PNG</browset>
            </browse>
    <datacred>Tompkins County ITS GIS Division and Tompkins County Assessment
      Department</datacred>
    <crossref>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Tompkins County Assessment Department</origin>
        <pubdate>20060701</pubdate>
        <title>Standard GIS Extract of Tax Parcel Data for Tompkins County, 2006</title>
        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
        <othercit>Tompkins County ITS GIS Division is responsible for creating
          the extract and converting it to a format that is compatible with the
          County's GIS.</othercit>
      </citeinfo>
    </crossref>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>See Entity and Attribute Information</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <logic>The taxparcel region from each municipality's tax map data set is
      appended into one County-wide data set. This data set's topology is
      created real-time using ArcGIS map and geodatabase topology rules, then
      converted to an ArcView shapefile. All error checking is done in the
      source data sets.</logic>
    <complete>Complete parcels for the entire County.</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>Varies, depending on source of parcel boundary (survey, deed,
          aerial photo, raw conversion from paper maps). The accuracy of the
          data set is limited to the accuracy of the 1991 Tompkins County
          Planimetric Base Map series.</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
      <vertacc>
        <vertaccr>The accuracy of the data set is limited to the accuracy of the
          1991 Tompkins County Planimetric Base Map series.</vertaccr>
      </vertacc>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Tax parcel boundaries were initially maintained manually on
          mylar originals, using erasable ink. In 1991, a series of planimetric
          base data sets were produced from aerial photography, and are now
          referred to as the 1991 Tompkins County Digital Planimetric Base Map.
          The tax parcel mylar maps were digitized using MapGrafix and
          referenced to the 1991 Tompkins County Digital Planimetric Base Map.
          In 1997, the MapGrafix data sets for the City of Ithaca and the Towns
          of Caroline and Danby were approved by the New York State Office of
          Real Property Services (NYS ORPS). In 1998, the Map Grafix data sets
          were converted to Arc/Info for the City of Ithaca, Towns of Caroline,
          Danby, Dryden, and Ithaca, and the Villages of Cayuga Heights, Dryden,
          and Freeville. In 1999, the Towns of Enfield, Groton, Lansing,
          Newfield, and Ulysses, and the Villages of Groton, Lansing, and
          Trumansburg were converted to Arc/Info. Beginning with the 1999 tax
          year, all tax parcel boundaries were maintained in Arc/Info, all tax
          maps are printed using ArcView, and all tax maps are archived
          digitally using Adobe Acrobat, as well as the traditional paper
          archival. During the transition period from paper to digital maps,
          parcel boundaries were approximated, except for those boundaries that
          have been input using paper surveys and legal descriptions. The tax
          parcel data sets consisted of three groups of layers: boundary layers,
          text layers, and region layers. The boundary layers consisted of those
          Arc/Info feature classes upon which the region layers are created.
          Boundary layers include the nodes, arcs, and polygons. Parcel
          boundaries are changed by first modifying the arc and node layers, and
          updating the arc attributes. Next, the polygons were re-created and
          their attributes were updated. The text layers were then updated to
          reflect the boundary changes. Finally, the regions were created from
          the polygons using polygon attributes and the Arc/Info REGIONDISSOLVE
          command. The text layers are Arc/Info annotation layers and include
          acreage, block, dimension, non-roll section 1 (exempt/utility/state
          lands), lot, Military Tract/Watkins and Flint Purchase, municipality,
          place, road name, special district, tax map, tic mark, and water text,
          as it appears on the printed tax parcel maps. The region layers
          include deed book/page, municipal, parcel, printkey, and tax map
          regions. The printkey regions from each of the municipal data sets for
          the current tax year are then combined into a county-wide data set,
          which is then converted to an ArcView shapefile. Regions for special
          districts were derived from polygon attributes in the same manner as
          the other regions, for each municipality, then combined into a
          County-wide special districts data set. Regions for public lands were
          similarly combined and converted into a County-wide public lands data
          set. In 2004, the original Arc/Info coverages described above were
          migrated to the ESRI ArcInfo Desktop geodatabase format. Parcel
          boundaries are changed based on deed and survey information and are
          modified in the software using Map topology and several geodatabase
          topology rules to ensure spatial data integrity. All regions,
          annotations, centroids and polygons listed above were successfully
          migrated by municipality and are maintained in the ESRI personal
          geodatabase format. Beginning with the 2004 tax year, all tax parcel
          boundaries are maintained in ArcInfo Desktop, all tax maps are printed
          via a special script which outputs the tax maps to Adobe Acrobat (PDF)
          format. All tax maps are archived digitally using Adobe Acrobat, as
          well as the traditional paper archival. 2006 tax maps in the Adobe PDF
          format can be obtained digitally online at:
          &lt;http://www.co.tompkins.ny.us/gis/maps/tax.html&gt;. </procdesc>
        <procdate>2006</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Tompkins County ITS GIS Division</cntper>
              <cntorg>Cattyann Campbell</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>GIS Project Leader</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>128 East Buffalo Street</address>
              <city>Ithaca</city>
              <state>New York</state>
              <postal>14820</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>(607) 274-5418</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>(607) 274-5420</cntfax>
            <cntemail>gis@tompkins-co.org</cntemail>
            <hours>M-F 8:30 a.m. to 4:30 p.m.</hours>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
        <direct>Vector</direct>
        <ptvctinf>
          <sdtsterm>
            <sdtstype>G-polygon</sdtstype>
            <ptvctcnt>34414</ptvctcnt>
          </sdtsterm>
        </ptvctinf>
      </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <gridsys>
          <gridsysn>State Plane Coordinate System 1983</gridsysn>
          <spcs>
            <spcszone>3102</spcszone>
            <transmer>
              <sfctrmer>0.999938</sfctrmer>
              <longcm>-76.583333</longcm>
              <latprjo>40.000000</latprjo>
              <feast>820208.333333</feast>
              <fnorth>0.000000</fnorth>
            </transmer>
          </spcs>
        </gridsys>
        <planci>
          <plance>coordinate pair</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>0.000256</absres>
            <ordres>0.000256</ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>survey feet</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257222</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>tcparcels2006</enttypl>
        <enttypd>Tompkins County Tax parcels 2006</enttypd>
        <enttypds>Tompkins County ITS GIS Division</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>AREA</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Area, in square U.S. survey feet</attrdef>
        <attrdefs/>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>0</rdommin>
            <rdommax>Unbounded</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>PERIMETER</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The sum of the lengths of the sides of the parcel polygon, in
          U.S. survey feet</attrdef>
        <attrdefs/>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>0</rdommin>
            <rdommax>Unbounded</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>PARCELKEY</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Real Property Services (RPS) Database parcel key
          (Swis-Section-Block-Lot or SSBL). This field is updated yearly based
          on the GIS extract of the final-roll RPS database.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Tompkins County ITS GIS Division</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>string</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SWISPRINTK</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Concatenation of SWIS code, "-", and the PRINTKEY field, for
          those polygons without an account number (i.e., a blank "ACCT_NUM"),
          or a concatenation of SWIS code, "-", and the "ACCT_NUM" field, for
          those polygons with an account number. This field is easily
          reproducible within the Real Property Services database extract, and
          is used as the primary join (key) field to the RPS extract from the
          parcel data sets.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Tompkins County ITS GIS Division</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>string</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SWIS</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>State SWIS code for the municipality in which the property is
          located.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Tompkins County ITS GIS Division</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>500200</edomv>
            <edomvd>Town of Caroline</edomvd>
            <edomvds>New York State Office of Real Property Services</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>502200</edomv>
            <edomvd>Town of Danby</edomvd>
            <edomvds>New York State Office of Real Property Services</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>502401</edomv>
            <edomvd>Village of Dryden</edomvd>
            <edomvds>New York State Office of Real Property Services</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>502403</edomv>
            <edomvd>Village of Freeville</edomvd>
            <edomvds>New York State Office of Real Property Services</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>502489</edomv>
            <edomvd>Town of Dryden</edomvd>
            <edomvds>New York State Office of Real Property Services</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>502600</edomv>
            <edomvd>Town of Enfield</edomvd>
            <edomvds>New York State Office of Real Property Services</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>502801</edomv>
            <edomvd>Village of Groton</edomvd>
            <edomvds>New York State Office of Real Property Services</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>502889</edomv>
            <edomvd>Town of Groton</edomvd>
            <edomvds>New York State Office of Real Property Services</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>503001</edomv>
            <edomvd>Village of Cayuga Heights</edomvd>
            <edomvds>New York State Office of Real Property Services</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>503089</edomv>
            <edomvd>Town of Ithaca</edomvd>
            <edomvds>New York State Office of Real Property Services</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>503201</edomv>
            <edomvd>Village of Lansing</edomvd>
            <edomvds>New York State Office of Real Property Services</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>503289</edomv>
            <edomvd>Town of Lansing</edomvd>
            <edomvds>New York State Office of Real Property Services</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>503400</edomv>
            <edomvd>Town of Newfield</edomvd>
            <edomvds>New York State Office of Real Property Services</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>503601</edomv>
            <edomvd>Village of Trumansburg</edomvd>
            <edomvds>New York State Office of Real Property Services</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>503689</edomv>
            <edomvd>Town of Ulysses</edomvd>
            <edomvds>New York State Office of Real Property Services</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>500700</edomv>
            <edomvd>City of Ithaca</edomvd>
            <edomvds>New York State Office of Real Property Services</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>PRINTKEY</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Real Property Services database print key (Section-Block-Lot or
          S-B-L).</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Tompkins County ITS GIS Division</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>string</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>ACCT_NUM</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Real Property Services (RPS) database account number, which is
          used to uniquely identify railroad, state-owned, and utility
          properties.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Tompkins County ITS GIS Division</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>string</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>ACCT_NUM2</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Old RPS database account number, which is used to uniquely
          identify railroad, state-owned, and utility properties. These numbers
          are from the GIS database from previous years. The format has changed
          for this year and is reflected in the "ACCT_NUM" field.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Tompkins County ITS GIS Division</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>string</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>CALCACRES</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Calculated Acreage (AREA / 43560)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Tompkins County ITS GIS Division</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>0</rdommin>
            <rdommax>Unbounded</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>RPSACRES</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Real Property Services (RPS) acreage, extracted from the RPS
          database. This acreage will reflect the total acreage of the parcel,
          which is not necessarily the same acreage value as the polygon.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Tompkins County ITS GIS Division</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>0</rdommin>
            <rdommax>Unbounded</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
        <distrib>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>Albert R. Mann Library</cntorg>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
              <address>Cornell University</address>
              <city>Ithaca</city>
              <state>New York</state>
              <postal>14853</postal>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>607-255-5406</cntvoice>
            <cntemail>mann-ref@cornell.edu</cntemail>
          </cntinfo>
        </distrib>
        <distliab>Cornell University provides these geographic data "as is". Cornell
          University makes no guarantee or warranty concerning the accuracy of
          information contained in the geographic data. Cornell University further
          makes no warranty either expressed or implied, regarding the condition of
          the product or its fitness for any particular purpose. The burden for
          determining fitness for use lies entirely with the user. Although these
          files have been processed successfully on computers at Cornell University,
          no warranty is made by Cornell University regarding the use of these data
          on any other system, nor does the fact of distribution constitute or imply
          any such warranty.</distliab>
        <stdorder>
        <digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>Shapefile</formname>
              <formcont>zipped shapefile</formcont>
              <filedec>zip</filedec>
              <transize>5.90</transize>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/78/99/cugir-007899.zip</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>metadata</formname>
              <formcont>FGDC XML metadata</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/78/99/fgdc.xml</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>HTML metadata</formname>
              <formcont>FGDC HTML metadata</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/78/99/fgdc.html</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
                <digtinfo>
                  <formname>KML</formname>
                  <formcont>generated KML, via WFS</formcont>
                </digtinfo>
                <digtopt>
                  <onlinopt>
                    <computer>
                      <networka>
                        <networkr>https://cugir.library.cornell.edu/geoserver/cugir/wfs?version=1.0.0&amp;request=GetFeature&amp;typeName=cugir007899&amp;outputFormat=application%2Fvnd.google-earth.kml%2Bxml</networkr>
                      </networka>
                    </computer>
                  </onlinopt>
                </digtopt>
              </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>GeoJSON</formname>
              <formcont>generated GeoJSON, via WFS</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir.library.cornell.edu/geoserver/cugir/wfs?version=1.0.0&amp;request=GetFeature&amp;typeName=cugir007899&amp;outputFormat=application%2Fjson</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>OGC:WMS</formname>
              <formcont>WMS, from GeoServer</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir.library.cornell.edu/geoserver/cugir/wms?version=1.1.0&amp;request=GetMap&amp;layers=cugir007899&amp;bbox=-76.70997692,42.25177704,-76.22358108,42.638286959999995&amp;width=256&amp;height=203&amp;srs=EPSG:4326&amp;format=image/png</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><fees>None</fees></stdorder>
      </distinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Tompkins County ITS GIS Division</cntorg>
          <cntper>Cattyann Campbell</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>GIS Project Leader</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
          <address>128 East Buffalo Street</address>
          <city>Ithaca</city>
          <state>New York</state>
          <postal>14850</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>(607) 274-5418</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>(607) 274-5420</cntfax>
        <cntemail>gis@tompkins-co.org</cntemail>
        <hours>M-F 8:30 a.m. to 4:30 p.m.</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>The tax parcel data set and any products derived from it
      represents a compilation of graphical and textual information from deeds
      and surveys, hand-drawn mylar maps, a digital planimetric base map,
      various paper and digital aerial photographs, and digital conversion of
      hand-drawn mylar maps. Errors and omissions can occur from each of these
      sources, as each source represents a large number of records and
      originators of information. As a practical matter, Tompkins County does
      not warrant the accuracy or completeness of the information portrayed. The
      end user of the data sets and products derived from them agrees to accept
      the data "as is", with the full knowledge that errors and omissions may
      exist. The end user further agrees to hold harmless Tompkins County for
      any liability or damages that may result from an improper or inappropriate
      use of the data.</distliab>
    <stdorder>
      <nondig>Paper maps, either color or black and white</nondig>
      <fees>For printed maps Half-size (11"x17") color maps are $2.00 each.
        Half-size black and white maps are $1.50 each. Full-size (24"x36") color
        and black and white maps are $12.00 each on coated paper. Fees for
        special-request media or non-standard print sizes will vary.</fees>
      <ordering>Submit a written request to the Tompkins County GIS Department
        at gis@tompkins-co.org or visit our office at 128 E. Buffalo St. to
        obtain map in person. </ordering>
      <turnarnd>Existing Half-size maps: 1-2 days. Existing Full-size maps: 1-2
        days. Custom maps may take up to 5-10 days. Digital maps 5-10
      days.</turnarnd>
    </stdorder>
    <stdorder>
      <digform>
        <digtinfo>
          <formname>ArcInfo Shapefile</formname>
        </digtinfo>
        <digtopt>
          <offoptn>
            <offmedia>Zip disk, CD-ROM, floppy disk, etc.</offmedia>
            <recfmt>varies</recfmt>
          </offoptn>
        </digtopt>
      </digform>
      <fees>The cost of reproduction for a standard data set, which varies
        depending on the type of media requested (zip disk, CD-ROM, floppy
        diskette, etc.). A standard data set is an ESRI shapefile, ArcGIS
        feature class, ArcView shapefile, dBASE III database, or Microsoft
        Access database. Official tax maps are available in Adobe Acrobat
        format, organized by municipality. Custom data sets or file types will
        incur additional labor costs</fees>
      <ordering>Submit a written request to the Tompkins County ITS GIS
        Division.</ordering>
      <turnarnd>Three to four days.</turnarnd>
    </stdorder>
    <availabl>
      <timeinfo>
        <sngdate>
          <caldate>20060731</caldate>
        </sngdate>
      </timeinfo>
    </availabl>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
      <metd>20190524</metd>
      <metc>
        <cntinfo>
          <cntorgp>
            <cntorg>Albert R. Mann Library</cntorg>
          </cntorgp>
          <cntaddr>
            <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
            <address>Albert R. Mann Library</address>
            <city>Ithaca</city>
            <state>New York</state>
            <postal>14853</postal>
            <country>USA</country>
          </cntaddr>
          <cntvoice>607-255-5406</cntvoice>
          <cntemail>mann-ref@cornell.edu</cntemail>
        </cntinfo>
      </metc>
      <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
      <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
      <mettc>local time</mettc>
    </metainfo>
</metadata>
