<!DOCTYPE metadata SYSTEM "http://fgdc.gov/metadata/fgdc-std-001-1998.dtd">
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>James A. Miller (comp.)</origin>
        <pubdate>19980701</pubdate>
        <title>Principal Aquifers, New York State, 1998</title>
        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Madison, Wisconsin, USA</pubplace>
          <publish>U.S. Geological Survey</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <onlink>https://cugir.library.cornell.edu/catalog/cugir-007317</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>This data set contains the shallowest principal aquifers of New York State,
        portrayed as lines. The data set was developed as part of the effort to produce the maps
        published at 1:2,500,000 in the printed series "Ground Water Atlas of the United States".
        The published maps contain base and cultural features not included in these data. This data
        set was previously called Principal Aquifers of the 48 Contiguous United States.</abstract>
      <purpose>These data are intended for use in publications, at a scale of 1:2,500,000 or
        smaller. Due to the small scale, the primary intended use is for regional and national data
        display and analysis, rather than specific local data analysis.</purpose>
      <supplinf>The Ground Water Atlas of the United States (GWA) chapters include additional
        information that may be relevant to the use of this data set, such as maps of alluvial and
        glacial aquifers that overlie the aquifers in this data set, as well as other information
        described below. The areal extent of the aquifers, as shown in this data set, represents the
        area in which a named aquifer is the shallowest of the principal aquifers. These aquifer
        areas are not necessarily the only areas in which ground water can be withdrawn, for two
        reasons: 1) The aquifers shown may have a larger areal extent than is represented here. The
        boundaries in this data set generally represent an interpretation of the surface location
        (outcrop), or near-surface location (shallow subcrop) of the uppermost principal aquifer for
        the area. An aquifer may extend beyond the area shown, but be overlain by one or more other
        aquifers, and (or) low-permeability material. 2) There may be areas of water-bearing
        surficial material not shown in this data set. Major alluvial aquifers that occur along main
        watercourses are not shown. Significant unconsolidated sand and gravel aquifers, that are
        not indicated in this data set but are important sources of water, may occur locally in
        glaciated regions. The user of this data set is advised that to get complete information
        regarding areas that serve as sources of water, more information about surficial aquifers
        needs to be obtained, particularly in glaciated areas. This data set was constructed by
        combining data created for or from the regional GWA chapters. Minor aquifers that are
        important local sources of water were mapped in some regions, so the regional maps in the
        GWA may show more detail than this data set. The juxtaposition of regionally mapped aquifers
        has led to some instances where an aquifer outcrop or shallow subcrop is bounded by a State
        line. This is a result of the regional mapping and national categorization methods used and
        is not meant to imply a hydrogeologic change coincident with a State boundary. The aquifer
        outcrop and shallow subcrop boundaries represent broad, regional categories and should not
        be interpreted as site-specific. Comments regarding the names of aquifers or the
        hydrogeologic interpretation of the aquifers can be directed to the U.S. Geological Survey,
        Water Resources Division, Office of Ground Water, Roy Sonenshein, sunshine@usgs.gov, (305)
        717-5824. This data set was used as part of the effort to publish a 1:5,000,000- scale
        'Principal Aquifers' map in the National Atlas of the United States of America series of
        printed maps. The printed map can be considered a representation of this data set with the
        exceptions of: the smaller scale, slight differences in the coastline due to generalization,
        base and cultural information, and delineation of the glacial-deposit area. These data were
        developed in conjunction with the publication of the GWA. For documentation purposes, areas
        are referred to by their corresponding GWA chapter letter, or by State. This list shows the
        relationship between State names and GWA chapters: HA 730-L Segment 11-Delaware, Maryland,
        New Jersey, North Carolina, Pennsylvania, Virginia, West Virginia HA 730-M Segment
        12-Connecticut, Maine, Massachusetts, New Hampshire, New York, Rhode Island, Vermont Refer
        to &lt;http://capp.water.usgs.gov/gwa/gwa.html&gt; for a graphic depiction of the GWA
        chapter regions, as well as more information about the GWA. Although these spatial data can
        stand alone, it may be helpful to refer to the printed GWA chapters when using the data.
        There are three subject areas in which there are significant differences between this data
        set and the printed chapters: category changes, which are described below; coastline
        location, and the representation of aquifers in Western Montana, both of which are discussed
        in the Process Description under Lineage. Category Changes Because the GWA regional chapters
        were written by different authors, there were areas of different interpretations and
        category delineations, aquifer names, etc., that became apparent when combining the regions.
        In most cases, the name and delineation of the aquifer is identical between this data set
        and the GWA printed maps, but there are several areas of differences. In some cases, a
        single aquifer from a GWA chapter is represented among multiple aquifers in this data set.
        The following listings show the differences between aquifer names in the GWA chapters and
        the aq_name and aq_code used in this data set. See the Entity and Attribute Information
        section for definitions of the data attributes. GWA chapter HA 730-G Name from fig 3, page 3
        aq_code-aq_name -- Sand and gravel aquifer 201-Coastal lowlands aquifer system Piedmont and
        Blue Ridge 999-Not a principal aquifer aquifers Appalachian Plateaus 310-Pennsylvanian
        aquifers aquifers Confining unit 999-Not a principal aquifer PIEDMONT AND BLUE RIDGE
        AQUIFERS Aquifers in early Mesozoic 308-Early Mesozoic basin basins aquifers Carbonate-rock
        aquifers 417-Piedmont and Blue Ridge carbonate-rock aquifers Crystalline-rock aquifers
        999-Not a principal aquifer Valley and Ridge 505-Valley and Ridge carbonate-rock aquifers
        carbonate-rock aquifers 416-New York and New England carbonate-rock aquifers APPALACHIAN
        PLATEAUS Permian and Pennsylvanian 310-Pennsylvanian aquifers aquifers GWA chapter HA 730-M
        Name from fig 10, page M5 aq_code-aq_name -- CARBONATE-ROCK AQUIFERS New York and New
        England 416-New York and New England carbonate-rock aquifers Valley and Ridge 416-New York
        and New England carbonate-rock aquifers SANDSTONE AQUIFERS Mesozoic sandstone and 308-Early
        Mesozoic basin basalt of the Newark aquifers Supergroup Lower Paleozoic 309-New York
        sandstone aquifers CRYSTALLINE-ROCK AQUIFERS Adirondack 999-Not a principal aquifer New
        England 999-Not a principal aquifer Related Spatial and Tabular Data Sets A data set showing
        the extent of glacial deposits is included in the online, interactive National Atlas of the
        United States, but is not available to download. This data set shows the southern limit of
        glaciation in the United States; areas north of the limit line may contain significant sand
        and gravel glacial deposits that are important sources of water for local areas. The final
        data are being served to the public in the following formats: Arc/INFO Export, or ArcView
        Shapefile. Other Online Sources of Information About Aquifers include Aquifer Basics
        &lt;https://water.usgs.gov/ogw/aquiferbasics/index.html&gt; provides information about the
        various aquifer types; The USGS Office of Ground Water provides information about the
        ground-water resources of the Nation and ground-water activities of the USGS
        &lt;http://water.usgs.gov/ogw/&gt;; The Ground Water Atlas of the United States
        &lt;http://capp.water.usgs.gov/gwa/index.html&gt;describes the location, the extent, and the
        geologic and hydrologic characteristics of the important aquifers of the Nation.</supplinf>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <sngdate>
          <caldate>19980701</caldate>
        </sngdate>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Publication date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>As needed</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
          <bounding>
            <westbc>-79.763235</westbc>
            <eastbc>-71.870162</eastbc>
            <northbc>45.006138</northbc>
            <southbc>40.506003</southbc>
          </bounding>
        </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>Aquifer</themekey>
        <themekey>Groundwater</themekey>
        <themekey>Hydrogeology</themekey>
        <themekey>Geohydrology</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
        <themekey>environment</themekey>
        <themekey>inlandWaters</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
              <themekt>CUGIR Category</themekt>
              <themekey>environment</themekey>
<themekey>inland waters</themekey>
            </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>LCSH</placekt>
        <placekey>New York (State)</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>None. Acknowledgment of the Ground Water Atlas of the United States and (or) the
      National Atlas of the United States of America would be appreciated in products derived from
      these data.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>U.S. Geological Survey</cntorg>
          <cntper>Chief, Cartographic and Publications Program, Water Resources Division</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>505 Science Drive</address>
          <city>Madison</city>
          <state>WI</state>
          <postal>53711-1061</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>608-238-9333</cntvoice>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <browse>
              <browsen>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/73/17/preview.png</browsen>
              <browsed>preview of the dataset</browsed>
              <browset>PNG</browset>
            </browse>
    <datacred>This data set was created and modified over a period of at least five years by several
      staff members of the U.S. Geological Survey Water Resources Division Cartographic and
      Publications Program in Madison, Wisconsin. Completion of this data set and associated
      metadata was funded, in part, under a cooperative joint funding agreement between the U.S.
      Geological Survey and the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency.</datacred>
    <native>Data General UNIX, Arc/INFO Version 7.04 coverage; and ESRI Shapefile format</native>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <logic>Lines. Each line is closed and has one label point.</logic>
    <complete>This data set includes aquifer information for New York State</complete>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Trapp, H., Jr. (comp.)</origin>
            <origin>Horn, M.A. (comp.)</origin>
            <pubdate>1997</pubdate>
            <title>Ground Water Atlas of the United States-Segment 11: Delaware, Maryland, New
              Jersey, North Carolina, Pennsylvania, Virginia, West Virginia</title>
            <edition>1.0</edition>
            <geoform>Map</geoform>
            <serinfo>
              <sername>Hydrologic Investigations Atlas</sername>
              <issue>HA 730-L</issue>
            </serinfo>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Reston, VA</pubplace>
              <publish>U.S. Geological Survey</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>2500000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>Stable-base material</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>1997</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>Publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>GWA HA 730-L</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Aquifer data for Delaware, Maryland, New Jersey, North Carolina, Pennsylvania,
          Virginia, and West Virginia</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Olcott, P.G. (comp.)</origin>
            <pubdate>1995</pubdate>
            <title>Ground Water Atlas of the United States-Segment 12: Connecticut, Maine,
              Massachusetts, New Hampshire, New York, Rhode Island, Vermont</title>
            <edition>1.0</edition>
            <geoform>Map</geoform>
            <serinfo>
              <sername>Hydrologic Investigations Atlas</sername>
              <issue>HA 730-M</issue>
            </serinfo>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Reston,VA</pubplace>
              <publish>U.S. Geological Survey</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>2500000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>Stable-base material</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>1995</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>Publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>GWA HA 730-M</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Aquifer data for Connecticut, Maine, Massachusetts, New Hampshire, New York, Rhode
          Island, and Vermont</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>United States Geological Survey</origin>
            <pubdate>1998</pubdate>
            <title>State Boundaries</title>
            <geoform>Map</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Reston,VA</pubplace>
              <publish>U.S. Geological Survey</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <onlink>http://nationalatlas.gov/atlasftp.html</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>2000000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>Online</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>1997</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>Publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>DLG State boundaries</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Coastline and international boundary</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>U.S. Geological Survey, Water Resources Division</origin>
            <pubdate>Unpublished material</pubdate>
            <title>National aquifers file</title>
            <geoform>Map</geoform>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>2500000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>Internal file</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>1990</begdate>
              <enddate>1993</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>Publication or compilation date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>National aquifers file</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Preliminary aquifer map of the 48 conterminous States.</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Aquifer outcrop line work for each GWA chapter was compiled on mylar at a scale of
          1:2,000,000, and reduced to 1:2,500,000 for further production work. For chapters HA
          730-G, -H, and -J, the outcrop lines were scribed at a line width of 0.006 inch. Film
          positives made from the scribed materials were scanned on a drum scanner, vectorized, and
          converted to Arc/INFO coverages. For chapters HA 730-B, -C, -D, -E, -F, -I, -K, -L, and
          -M, the aquifer compilation was either hand digitized, and (or) scanned on a drum scanner,
          vectorized and converted to Arc/INFO coverages. The data were then checked, cleaned up,
          and attribute creation was done. Individual chapter coverages were appended into one
          continuous coverage. Arcedit was used for edgematching and to remove duplicate
          labels.</procdesc>
        <srcused>HA 730-L</srcused>
        <srcused>HA 730-M</srcused>
        <procdate>1993</procdate>
        <srcprod>National aquifers file</srcprod>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Plots of the national aquifers file were made at 1:2,500,000, covering the areas
          of the regional GWA chapters. Each plot was compared to the printed GWA chapter aquifer
          maps. Where applicable (chapters HA 730-B, -C, -D, -E, -F, -I, -K, - L, and -M), an Adobe
          Illustrator file of the coverage data was compared on-screen with the Illustrator file
          used to print the published map. Discrepancies between the coverage file and print file
          were noted, and the coverage updated to match the published map. Where a line appeared to
          shift noticeably (approximately 1/8 inch at a scale of 1:2,500,000) across the boundary of
          two adjacent GWA chapter regions, the line was adjusted for a smoother appearance. The
          adjustments may have been made on one or both sides of the region boundary, depending on a
          cartographic assessment of the instance. Coastline Location The 1:2,500,000 principal
          aquifer maps in the Ground Water Atlas publications used a coastline and international
          boundary, derived either from the map separates from the National Atlas of the United
          States of America (published 1970), or from the Digital Line Graph (DLG) data created from
          the 1970 National Atlas. GWA chapters HA 730-G, -J, and -H used coastline and boundary
          filmwork photo-mechanically reduced from the 1:2,000,000 National Atlas map separates. The
          remaining chapters used coastline and boundary data from the DLG's. A revision of the DLG
          data took place in 1997, after the creation of the chapter aquifer map data. After the
          edgematching, a decision was made to replace the coast and international boundary of this
          national-level aquifer data with one derived from a newer version of 1997 DLG data. State
          boundary data from the U.S. Geological Survey National Mapping Division was used to
          provide the coastline and two aquifer boundaries that coincide with State lines. A
          publicly available version of this data and its metadata (Map Layer Theme States) can be
          found at http://nationalatlas.gov/atlasftp.html. The existing outline (coastline and
          international boundary line) was removed, the new outline added to the coverage, and the
          remaining aquifer contact lines snapped to the new outline. The coverage was re- cleaned,
          data categories checked onscreen and with plots, and corrected. Line and labeling
          corrections, such as undershoots, overshoots, and improper labels were corrected in
          Arcedit. There are some slight locational differences between this data set and the
          printed GWA chapters. For example, there are several small differences in the number of
          small islands in coastal areas and the categorization of these small islands was assigned
          to either the nearby principal aquifer category or as Not a principal aquifer, depending
          on the location and categorization of similar small islands in the printed GWA chapters.
          There are other differences in the categorization of some land/shoreline-related features.
          For example, an area symbolized as a bay in a GWA chapter may be land in this data
          set.</procdesc>
        <procdate>unknown</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>In order to geoprocess spatial files for New York State from the National Atlas
          Data for distribution in CUGIR, the nationwide data files were added to a map document in
          ArcInfo 8.2. Using the geoprocessing wizard's clip function, the spatial files were
          clipped to the detailed New York line.</procdesc>
        <procdate>200212</procdate>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
        <direct>Vector</direct>
        <ptvctinf>
          <sdtsterm>
            <sdtstype>G-polygon</sdtstype>
            <ptvctcnt>90</ptvctcnt>
          </sdtsterm>
        </ptvctinf>
      </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <geograph>
        <latres>0.000278</latres>
        <longres>0.000278</longres>
        <geogunit>Decimal degrees</geogunit>
      </geograph>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>GRS1980</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.0</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257222</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>Aquifer</enttypl>
        <enttypd>A formation, group of formations, or part of a formation that contains sufficient
          saturated permeable material to yield significant quantities of water to wells and
          springs.</enttypd>
        <enttypds>U.S. Geological Survey</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Area</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The size of the shape in coverage units (degrees)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>U.S. Geological Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>0.00000</rdommin>
            <rdommax>56.31950</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Perimeter</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The perimeter of the shape in coverage units (degrees)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>U.S. Geological Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>0.01024</rdommin>
            <rdommax>606.75187</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Aquifrp025</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>U.S. Geological Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>2</rdommin>
            <rdommax>4277</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Rock_name</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The name of the permeable geologic material that composes the aquifer.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>U.S. Geological Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>unconsolidated sand and gravel aquifers</edomv>
            <edomvd>Formations composed of loose sand and gravel.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>U.S. Geological Survey</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>semiconsolidated sand aquifers</edomv>
            <edomvd>Formations composed of partially solidified sand.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>U.S. Geological Survey</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>sandstone aquifers</edomv>
            <edomvd>Formations composed of sandstone.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>U.S. Geological Survey</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Carbonate-rock aquifers</edomv>
            <edomvd>Formations composed of limestone and (or) dolomite.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>U.S. Geological Survey</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Sandstone and carbonate-rock aquifers</edomv>
            <edomvd>Formations composed of sandstone, limestone, and (or) dolomite.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>U.S. Geological Survey</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Basalt and other volcanic-rock aquifers</edomv>
            <edomvd>Formations composed of volcanic rocks.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>U.S. Geological Survey</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>(blank field)</edomv>
            <edomvd>Not a principal aquifer. Rocks that are generally poorly permeable but locally
              may contain productive aquifers.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>U.S. Geological Survey</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Rock_type</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The code number relating to the rock_name.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>U.S. Geological Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>0</edomv>
            <edomvd>Null value, assigned to null line.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>U.S. Geological Survey</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>100</edomv>
            <edomvd>Number for unconsolidated sand and gravel aquifers.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>U.S. Geological Survey</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>200</edomv>
            <edomvd>Number for semiconsolidated sand aquifers.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>U.S. Geological Survey</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>300</edomv>
            <edomvd>Number for sandstone aquifers.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>U.S. Geological Survey</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>400</edomv>
            <edomvd>Number for carbonate-rock aquifers.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>U.S. Geological Survey</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>500</edomv>
            <edomvd>Number for sandstone and carbonate-rock aquifers.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>U.S. Geological Survey</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>600</edomv>
            <edomvd>Number for basalt and other volcanic-rock aquifers.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>U.S. Geological Survey</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>999</edomv>
            <edomvd>Number for areas that are not a principal aquifer.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>U.S. Geological Survey</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Aq_name</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The aquifer unit name.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>U.S. Geological Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>There is no predefined set of official aquifer names.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Aq_code</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The code number relating to the aquifer unit name. There should be a direct
          correlation between the values of the rock_type and rock_name attributes, and between the
          aq_name and aq_code attributes.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>U.S. Geological Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>0</rdommin>
            <rdommax>999</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
        <distrib>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>Albert R. Mann Library</cntorg>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
              <address>Cornell University</address>
              <city>Ithaca</city>
              <state>New York</state>
              <postal>14853</postal>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>607-255-5406</cntvoice>
            <cntemail>mann-ref@cornell.edu</cntemail>
          </cntinfo>
        </distrib>
        <distliab>Cornell University provides these geographic data "as is". Cornell
          University makes no guarantee or warranty concerning the accuracy of
          information contained in the geographic data. Cornell University further
          makes no warranty either expressed or implied, regarding the condition of
          the product or its fitness for any particular purpose. The burden for
          determining fitness for use lies entirely with the user. Although these
          files have been processed successfully on computers at Cornell University,
          no warranty is made by Cornell University regarding the use of these data
          on any other system, nor does the fact of distribution constitute or imply
          any such warranty.</distliab>
        <stdorder>
        <digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>Shapefile</formname>
              <formcont>zipped shapefile</formcont>
              <filedec>zip</filedec>
              <transize>0.20</transize>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/73/17/cugir-007317.zip</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>metadata</formname>
              <formcont>FGDC XML metadata</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/73/17/fgdc.xml</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>HTML metadata</formname>
              <formcont>FGDC HTML metadata</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/73/17/fgdc.html</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
                <digtinfo>
                  <formname>KML</formname>
                  <formcont>generated KML, via WFS</formcont>
                </digtinfo>
                <digtopt>
                  <onlinopt>
                    <computer>
                      <networka>
                        <networkr>https://cugir.library.cornell.edu/geoserver/cugir/wfs?version=1.0.0&amp;request=GetFeature&amp;typeName=cugir007317&amp;outputFormat=application%2Fvnd.google-earth.kml%2Bxml</networkr>
                      </networka>
                    </computer>
                  </onlinopt>
                </digtopt>
              </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>GeoJSON</formname>
              <formcont>generated GeoJSON, via WFS</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir.library.cornell.edu/geoserver/cugir/wfs?version=1.0.0&amp;request=GetFeature&amp;typeName=cugir007317&amp;outputFormat=application%2Fjson</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>OGC:WMS</formname>
              <formcont>WMS, from GeoServer</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir.library.cornell.edu/geoserver/cugir/wms?version=1.1.0&amp;request=GetMap&amp;layers=cugir007317&amp;bbox=-80.00002719,40.37099895,-71.63336980999999,45.14114205&amp;width=256&amp;height=145&amp;srs=EPSG:4326&amp;format=image/png</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><fees>None</fees></stdorder>
      </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
      <metd>20190524</metd>
      <metc>
        <cntinfo>
          <cntorgp>
            <cntorg>Albert R. Mann Library</cntorg>
          </cntorgp>
          <cntaddr>
            <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
            <address>Albert R. Mann Library</address>
            <city>Ithaca</city>
            <state>New York</state>
            <postal>14853</postal>
            <country>USA</country>
          </cntaddr>
          <cntvoice>607-255-5406</cntvoice>
          <cntemail>mann-ref@cornell.edu</cntemail>
        </cntinfo>
      </metc>
      <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
      <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
      <mettc>local time</mettc>
    </metainfo>
</metadata>
