<!DOCTYPE metadata SYSTEM "http://fgdc.gov/metadata/fgdc-std-001-1998.dtd">
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Mann Library, Cornell University</origin>
        <pubdate>20171205</pubdate>
        <title>Index of USGS Topographic Maps, New York State, 2000</title>
        <geoform>raster digital data</geoform>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Ithaca, New York</pubplace>
          <publish>Mann Library, Cornell University</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <onlink>https://cugir.library.cornell.edu/catalog/cugir-009001</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>This is an index of county-based mosaics of USGS topographic maps.
        Map images were derived from scans of USGS 7.5 minute quadrangle maps
        (Digital Raster Graphics) circa 2000, from which the map collar
        information was removed. Images are GeoTIFF files in NAD83, UTM zone 18.</abstract>
      <purpose>A DRG is useful as a source or background layer in a GIS, as a
        means to perform quality assurance on other digital products, and as a
        source for the collection and revision of DLG data.</purpose>
      <supplinf>1. Checking a sample of the DRGs produced by the U.S.G.S.
        indicated that the images were mis-registered by as much as 5 pixels
        (about 12 meters). Although the images were re-registered in an effort
        to reduce this error, perfect registration was not always possible. We
        found that some of the original images were scanned with distortion that
        could not be removed in the re-registration process. Thus, an unknown
        proportion of the images have errors which, when combined with any
        errors in the original maps, may exceed the limits of the National Map
        Accuracy Standards adhered to by the original maps. If a scanned image
        is to be used where accuracy at the 1:24,000 scale is needed, its
        registration accuracy should be verified. 2. The maps upon which the
        images are based used either metric contours in meters or English
        contours in feet. There is no easy way to determine which units are used
        for a particular image because the map collar information is not
        present. Users need to be aware of the need to use care in determining
        elevation units from these images. 3. For more background on Digital
        Raster Graphics, refer to the USGS.</supplinf>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>1942</begdate>
          <enddate>2000</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Ground Condition</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Irregular</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
          <bounding>
            <westbc>-79.762152</westbc>
            <eastbc>-71.856214</eastbc>
            <northbc>45.01585</northbc>
            <southbc>40.496103</southbc>
          </bounding>
        </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>Digital Raster Graphic</themekey>
        <themekey>basemaps</themekey>
        <themekey>topographic maps</themekey>
        <themekey>topo maps</themekey>
        <themekey>index map</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
        <themekey>imageryBaseMapsEarthCover</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
              <themekt>CUGIR Category</themekt>
              <themekey>basemaps</themekey>
<themekey>index map</themekey>
            </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>None</placekt>
        <placekey>New York State</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>Acknowledgement of the USGS would be appreciated in products
      derived from these data.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>New York State Department of Environmental Conservation</cntorg>
          <cntper>Katherine Barnes</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical</addrtype>
          <address>625 Broadway</address>
          <city>Albany</city>
          <state>NY</state>
          <postal>12233-4754</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>518-402-8940</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>kfbarnes@gw.dec.state.ny.us</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <logic>Not Applicable</logic>
    <complete>The DRG is a faithfully reproduced digital images of the original
      source map. Some differences may be detected between the source graphic
      used and the DRG due to the RGB values assigned that particular color. The
      intent is to recreate those colors as near as possible. Data completeness
      for DRG files reflect content of the source graphic. Features may have
      been eliminated or generalized on the source graphic due to scale and
      legibility constraints. For information on collection and inclusion
      criteria, see U.S. Geological Survey, 1994, 24,000-Scale Digital Line
      Graphs and Natioal Mapping Program Technical Instructions and U.S.
      Geological Survey, 1994, Standards National Mapping Program Technical
      Instructions.</complete>
    <lineage>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>The 7.5 minute image files were copied from the distribution
          CDs to a disk drive. Images were selected for registration quality
          checking using a stratified random sampling scheme in which two
          non-adjacent maps were selected from each 1 degree block that was
          entirely within New York and one map was selected from each block that
          was partially within New York. This approximately 3% sample was
          evaluated by checking the neatline corners of the scanned map against
          a vector coverage of the quadrangle boundaries. Only three of the 47
          sampled maps had neatline corners within one pixel of the vector
          boundaries. The remainder were mis-registered by between one and five
          pixels, equivalent to between 2.4 and 12 meters, in one or both
          directions. We decided, therefore, to re-register the images.
          Information on the evaluation process can be found in the report
          Evaluating DRG Image Registration Accuracy. Our ultimate goal was a
          set of images in UTM zone 18 in NAD83. A set of tests demonstrated
          negligible differences between the computationally time consuming
          process of projecting the images and projecting the coordinates of the
          upper left "placement" point in the ESRI world file. Theoretical
          considerations indicate little difference between projecting the image
          and using the ArcInfo GRIDWARP command to re-register the images
          because the NADCON grid spacing is 15 minutes. We decided to use
          GRIDWARP to perform datum conversion and re-registration at the same
          time. GRIDWARP was set up by creating links from the four corners of
          the image's map neatlines to a vector coverage of quadrangle
          boundaries. The vector coverage was derived from a coverage that had
          been generated in geodetic coordinates and projected to UTM Zone 18 in
          NAD27. For DRG re-registration this coverage was projected to NAD83
          and the proper UTM zone for the quadrangle. Each image was converted
          to a grid, subjected to a first order (linear) GRIDWARP, and converted
          back to an image. The registration quality at the four corners was
          checked by a different person. The registration process was repeated
          if necessary until a good match was obtained between the raster and
          vector quadrangle corners. Eight quadrangles (o41076h5, o44074b8,
          o40073h2, k44073c7, k44073c5, o42073d7, k42073e3, o42073h7, o42079a1,
          and o42079a2) could not be successfully registered. Additional links
          were added for these files and they were registered with a second
          order GRIDWARP. Map collars were clipped from the images by extracting
          the zone and bounding geodetic coordinates for each quadrangle from
          the .fgd files that accompanied the images. This information was used
          to create a coverage that was projected from NAD27 to NAD83 in the
          proper UTM zone and used to clip a grid made from the image. The grids
          were then merged. Merging was automated for up to 48 images at a time.
          These grids were further merged. Grids with all quadrangles in UTM
          zones 17 and 19 were created and projected to zone 18. We attempted to
          create a single grid for the entire state but were unable to do so
          because the result would have exceeded the 2.1 GB size limit for a
          single grid. We therefore somewhat haphazardly merged the grids into
          larger grids. We then divided the state into six longitudinal zones.
          An outline coverage for each zone was created. All sides of these
          grids were oriented along the coordinate axes so that no areas of
          NODATA would be created when they were used to clip grids. Each
          outline coverage was then used to clip each of the larger merged
          grids. Finally, these clipped component grids were merged to grids
          that exactly filled a longitudinal zone. We created a coverage of
          polygons that were to be used to define the final image tiles. These
          polygons were squares of 5000 m oriented along the coordinate grid.
          The tiles were designed to coincide with the blocks used by the New
          York State Breeding Bird Atlas. The minimum X coordinate of the
          Breeding Bird Atlas coverage was projected to NAD83. This value was
          decreased by 20,000 and used as the starting coordinate in an ArcInfo
          GENERATE with FISHNET to produce square polygons 5000 m on a side.
          This coverage was then clipped by a polygon created by buffering a New
          York State outline coverage by 24,200 m. Labels were copied from the
          Breeding Bird Atlas coverage. Additional labels were added to the
          polygons that did not occur in the Breeding Bird Atlas coverage. These
          polygons were given a unique value for BLOCK, the item in the Breeding
          Bird Atlas coverage that identified each 5000 m square. The 5000 m
          square polygons were used to clip 5000 m square tiles from the
          longitudinal zone grids. Each 5000 m square polygon was extracted into
          a separate coverage. The minimum and maximum coordinates of this new
          coverage were determined. The maximum coordinates were incremented by
          2.5, the approximate size of pixel, to deal with improper rounding in
          the ArcInfo GRIDCLIP command. These coordinates were then used as
          arguments to the Grid GRIDCLIP command with the BOX option to clip a
          5000 m square tile out the longitudinal zone grid. This grid was then
          converted to an image with IMAGEGRID. Image file names were obtained
          by preceding the BLOCK item from the coverage PAT with "o" and
          converting the letter in BLOCK from upper case to lower case. An image
          catalog was created to manage the images. The AML FILELIST function
          was used to create a file that listed all the images. The name of this
          file was used as the argument in the ADDIMAGE command in order to
          populate the image catalog.</procdesc>
        <procdate>19991231</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
          CUGIR staff merged the 5000m tiles statewide, then clipped by each county bounding box.
        </procdesc>
        <procdate>2012</procdate>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Vector</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>G-polygon</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>62</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <gridsys>
          <gridsysn>Universal Transverse Mercator</gridsysn>
          <utm>
            <utmzone>18</utmzone>
            <transmer>
              <sfctrmer>.9996</sfctrmer>
              <longcm>-075.000000</longcm>
              <latprjo>+00.000000</latprjo>
              <feast>500000</feast>
              <fnorth>0</fnorth>
            </transmer>
          </utm>
        </gridsys>
        <planci>
          <plance>row and column</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>2.5</absres>
            <ordres>2.5</ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>Meters</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257222101</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <distinfo>
        <distrib>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>Albert R. Mann Library</cntorg>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
              <address>Cornell University</address>
              <city>Ithaca</city>
              <state>New York</state>
              <postal>14853</postal>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>607-255-5406</cntvoice>
            <cntemail>mann-ref@cornell.edu</cntemail>
          </cntinfo>
        </distrib>
        <distliab>Cornell University provides these geographic data "as is". Cornell
          University makes no guarantee or warranty concerning the accuracy of
          information contained in the geographic data. Cornell University further
          makes no warranty either expressed or implied, regarding the condition of
          the product or its fitness for any particular purpose. The burden for
          determining fitness for use lies entirely with the user. Although these
          files have been processed successfully on computers at Cornell University,
          no warranty is made by Cornell University regarding the use of these data
          on any other system, nor does the fact of distribution constitute or imply
          any such warranty.</distliab>
        <stdorder>
        <digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>GeoJSON</formname>
              <formcont>OpenIndexMaps</formcont>
              <transize>0.18</transize>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/90/01/cugir-009001-index.geojson</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>metadata</formname>
              <formcont>FGDC XML metadata</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/90/01/fgdc.xml</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>HTML metadata</formname>
              <formcont>FGDC HTML metadata</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/90/01/fgdc.html</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><fees>None</fees></stdorder>
      </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
      <metd>20190524</metd>
      <metc>
        <cntinfo>
          <cntorgp>
            <cntorg>Albert R. Mann Library</cntorg>
          </cntorgp>
          <cntaddr>
            <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
            <address>Albert R. Mann Library</address>
            <city>Ithaca</city>
            <state>New York</state>
            <postal>14853</postal>
            <country>USA</country>
          </cntaddr>
          <cntvoice>607-255-5406</cntvoice>
          <cntemail>mann-ref@cornell.edu</cntemail>
        </cntinfo>
      </metc>
      <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
      <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
      <mettc>local time</mettc>
    </metainfo>
</metadata>
