<!DOCTYPE metadata SYSTEM "http://fgdc.gov/metadata/fgdc-std-001-1998.dtd">
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>
U.S. Department of Agriculture,
Natural Resources Conservation Service
</origin>
        <pubdate>20131215</pubdate>
        <title>SSURGO soils, Wayne County NY</title>
        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
        <serinfo>
          <sername>Soil Survey Geographic (SSURGO) database</sername>
          <issue>Wayne County NY</issue>
        </serinfo>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Fort Worth, Texas</pubplace>
          <publish>
U.S. Department of Agriculture,
Natural Resources Conservation Service
</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <onlink>https://cugir.library.cornell.edu/catalog/cugir-007923</onlink>
        <onlink>https://websoilsurvey-dev.dev.sc.egov.usda.gov/</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>
This data set is a digital soil survey and generally is the most
detailed level of soil geographic data developed by the National
Cooperative Soil Survey. The information was prepared by digitizing
maps, by compiling information onto a planimetric correct base
and digitizing, or by revising digitized maps using remotely
sensed and other information.

This data set consists of georeferenced digital map data and
computerized attribute data. The map data are in a soil survey area
extent format and include a detailed, field verified inventory
of soils and miscellaneous areas that normally occur in a repeatable
pattern on the landscape and that can be cartographically shown at
the scale mapped. A special soil features layer (point and line
features) is optional. This layer displays the location of features
too small to delineate at the mapping scale, but they are large
enough and contrasting enough to significantly influence use and
management. The soil map units are linked to attributes in the
National Soil Information System relational database, which gives
the proportionate extent of the component soils and their properties.
</abstract>
      <purpose>
SSURGO depicts information about the kinds and distribution of
soils on the landscape. The soil map and data used in the SSURGO
product were prepared by soil scientists as part of the National
Cooperative Soil Survey.
</purpose>
      <supplinf>
Digital versions of hydrography, cultural features, and other
associated layers that are not part of the SSURGO data set may be
available from the primary organization listed in the Point of
Contact.
</supplinf>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>20070808</begdate>
          <enddate>20131215</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>publication date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>As needed</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
          <bounding>
            <westbc>-77.376094</westbc>
            <eastbc>-76.702315</eastbc>
            <northbc>43.343891</northbc>
            <southbc>43.01246</southbc>
          </bounding>
        </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>soil survey</themekey>
        <themekey>soils</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
              <themekt>CUGIR Category</themekt>
              <themekey>geology</themekey>
            </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>USGS Geographic Names Information System (GNIS)</placekt>
        <placekey>Wayne County</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>
The U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources Conservation
Service, should be acknowledged as the data source in products
derived from these data.

This data set is not designed for use as a primary regulatory tool
in permitting or citing decisions, but may be used as a reference
source. This is public information and may be interpreted by
organizations, agencies, units of government, or others based on
needs; however, they are responsible for the appropriate
application. Federal, State, or local regulatory bodies are not to
reassign to the Natural Resources Conservation Service any
authority for the decisions that they make. The Natural Resources
Conservation Service will not perform any evaluations of these maps
for purposes related solely to State or local regulatory programs.

Photographic or digital enlargement of these maps to scales greater
than at which they were originally mapped can cause misinterpretation
of the data. If enlarged, maps do not show the small areas of
contrasting soils that could have been shown at a larger scale. The
depicted soil boundaries, interpretations, and analysis derived from
them do not eliminate the need for onsite sampling, testing, and
detailed study of specific sites for intensive uses. Thus, these data
and their interpretations are intended for planning purposes only.
Digital data files are periodically updated. Files are dated, and
users are responsible for obtaining the latest version of the data.
</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources Conservation Service</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>State Soil Scientist</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>
          <address>USDA Natural Resources Conservation Service</address>
          <address>441 South Salina Street</address>
          <address>Fifth Floor Suite 354</address>
          <city>Syracuse</city>
          <state>NY</state>
          <postal>13202</postal>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>315-477-6526</cntvoice>
        <cnttdd>800-877-8339</cnttdd>
        <cntfax>855-477-8518</cntfax>
        <cntemail>stephen.page@ny.usda.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <browse>
              <browsen>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/79/23/preview.png</browsen>
              <browsed>preview of the dataset</browsed>
              <browset>PNG</browset>
            </browse>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>
The attribute accuracy is tested by manual
comparison of the source with hard copy plots and/or symbolized
display of the map data on an interactive computer graphic system.
Selected attributes that cannot be visually verified on plots or
on screen are interactively queried and verified on screen. In
addition, the attributes are tested against a master set of valid
attributes. All attribute data conform to the attribute codes in
the signed classification and correlation document and amendment(s).
</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <logic>
Certain node/geometry and topology GT- polygon/chain relationships
are collected or generated to satisfy topological requirements
(the GT-polygon corresponds to the soil delineation). Some of these
requirements include: chains must begin and end at nodes, chains
must connect to each other at nodes, chains do not extend through
nodes, left and right GT-polygons are defined for each chain
element and are consistent throughout, and the chains representing
the limits of the file are free of gaps. The tests of logical
consistency are performed using vendor software. All internal
polygons are tested for closure with vendor software and are checked
on hard copy plots. All data are checked for common soil lines (i.e.,
adjacent polygons with the same label). Edge locations generally do
not deviate from centerline to centerline by more than 0.01 inch.

The Soil Survey of (NY117)  Wayne County, New York is edge matched to
all of the adjacent SSURGO certified soil surveys:
NY011  Cayuga County, New York
NY055  Monroe County, New York
NY069  Ontario County, New York
NY099  Seneca County, New York

Most feature edges (polygon and line segments) match adjacent ones
in the edge matched survey areas, however, feature labels don't match the
adjacent feature labels in edge matched surveys.

Descriptive attributes (tabular information about the polygons and
line segments) were developed specifically for each survey area.
Although most don't match exactly, the descriptive attributes of
most polygon and line segments in this survey are nearly the same
as adjacent ones in edge matched soil surveys.

The soil survey area boundaries match.
</logic>
    <complete>
A map unit is a collection of areas defined and named in terms of
their soil components or miscellaneous areas or both. Each map
unit differs in some respect from all others in a survey area and
each map unit has a symbol that uniquely identifies the map unit
on a soil map. Each individual area, point, or line so identified
on the map is a delineation.

Soil Scientists identify small areas of soils or miscellaneous areas
that have properties and behavior significantly different than the
named soils in the surrounding map unit. These minor components
may be indicated as special features. If they have a minimal effect
on use and management, or could not be precisely located, they may
not be indicated on the map.

A map unit has specified kinds of soils or miscellaneous areas
(map unit components), each with a designated range in
proportionate extent. Map units include one or more kinds of soil
or miscellaneous area. Miscellaneous areas are areas that have little
or no recognizable soil.

Specific National Cooperative Soil Survey standards and procedures
were used in the classification of soils, design and name of map
units, and location of special soil features. These standards are
outlined in Agricultural Handbook 18, Soil Survey Manual, 1993,
USDA, NRCS; Agricultural Handbook 436, Soil Taxonomy, 1995,
USDA, NRCS; and all Amendments; Keys to Soil Taxonomy,
(current issue) USDA, NRCS; National Soil Survey
Handbook, title 430-VI,(current issue) USDA, NRCS.

The actual composition and interpretive purity of the map unit
delineations were based on data collected by scientists during
the course of preparing the soil maps. Adherence to National
Cooperative Soil Survey standards and procedures is based on
peer review, quality control, and quality assurance. Quality
control is outlined in the memorandum of understanding for the
soil survey area and in documents that reside with the Natural
Resources Conservation Service state soil scientist. Four kinds
of map units are used in soil surveys: consociations, complexes,
associations, and undifferentiated groups.

Consociations - Consociations are named for the dominant soil.
In a consociation, delineated areas use a single name from the
dominant component in the map unit. Dissimilar components are
minor in extent. The soil component in a consociation may be
identified at any taxonomic level. Soil series is the lowest
taxonomic level. A consociation that is named as a miscellaneous
area is dominantly that kind of area and minor components do not
significantly affect the use of the map unit. The total amount of
dissimilar inclusions of other components in a map unit generally
does not exceed about 15 percent if limiting and 25 percent if
nonlimiting. A single component of a dissimilar limiting inclusion
generally does not exceed 10 percent if very contrasting.

Complexes and associations - Complexes and associations consist
of two or more  dissimilar components that occur in a regularly
repeating pattern. The total amount of other dissimilar components
is minor extent. The following arbitrary rule determines whether
complex or association is used in the name. The major components
of an association can be separated at the scale of mapping. In
either case, because the major components are sufficiently different
in morphology or behavior, the map unit cannot be called a
consociation. In each delineation of a complex or an association,
each major component is normally present though their proportions
may vary appreciably from one delineation to another. The total
amount of inclusions in a map unit that are dissimilar to any of
the major components does not exceed 15 percent if limiting and
25 percent if nonlimiting. A single kind of dissimilar limiting
inclusion usually does not exceed 10 percent.

Undifferentiated groups - Undifferentiated groups consist of two
or more components that are not consistently associated
geographically and, therefore, do not always occur together in
the same map delineation. These components are included in the
same named map unit because their use and management are the same
or very similar for common uses. Generally they are grouped together
because some common feature, such as steepness, stoniness, or
flooding, determines their use and management. If two or more
additional map units would serve no useful purpose, they may be
included in the same unit. Each delineation has at least one of the
major components, and some may have all of them. The same principles
regarding the proportion of minor components that apply to
consociations also apply to undifferentiated groups. The same
principles regarding proportion of inclusion apply to
undifferentiated groups as to consociations.

Minimum documentation consists of three complete soil profile
descriptions that are collected for each soil added to the legend,
one additional per 3,000 acres mapped; three 10 observation
transects for each map unit, one additional 10 point transect per
3,000 acres.

A defined standard or level of confidence in the interpretive
purity of the map unit delineations is attained by adjusting the
kind and intensity of field investigations. Field investigations
and data collection are carried out in sufficient detail to name
map units and to identify accurately and consistently areas of
about 3 acres.
</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>
The accuracy of these digital data is based upon their
compilation to base maps that meet National Map
Accuracy Standards at a scale of 1 inch equals 1,000
feet. The difference in positional accuracy between the
soil boundaries and special soil features locations in the
field and their digitized map locations is unknown. The
locational accuracy of soil delineations on the ground varies
with the transition between map units.

For example, on long gently sloping landscapes the transition
occurs gradually over many feet. Where landscapes change
abruptly from steep to level, the transition will be very
narrow. Soil delineation boundaries and special soil features
generally were digitized within 0.01 inch of their locations on
the digitizing source. The digital map elements are edge matched
between data sets. The data along each quadrangle edge are
matched against the data for the adjacent quadrangle. Edge
locations generally do not deviate from centerline to centerline
by more than 0.01 inch.
</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>U.S Department of Agriculture, Soil Conservation Service</origin>
            <pubdate>1978</pubdate>
            <title>Soil Survey of Wayne County, New York</title>
            <geoform>atlas</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Washington, D.C.</pubplace>
              <publish>U.S. Government Printing Office</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>15840</srcscale>
        <typesrc>paper</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>1972</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>final correlation date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>SCS1</srccitea>
        <srccontr>soil attributes and special feature locations</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>
U.S. Department of Agriculture,
Natural Resources Conservation Service
</origin>
            <pubdate>unpublished material</pubdate>
            <title>publication annotation overlays</title>
            <geoform>map</geoform>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>15840</srcscale>
        <typesrc>film</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>1972</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>final correlation date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>NRCS1</srccitea>
        <srccontr>
final publication negatives used to develop film
positives
</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>
U.S. Department of Agriculture,
Natural Resources Conservation Service
</origin>
            <pubdate>unpublished material</pubdate>
            <title>ratio film positives of publication annotated overlays</title>
            <geoform>remote sensing image</geoform>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>12000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>film</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>1972</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>final correlation date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>NRCS2</srccitea>
        <srccontr>
source material for special soil features, soil
polygons, and soil attributes
</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>
U.S. Department of Agriculture,
Natural Resources Conservation Service
</origin>
            <pubdate>2005</pubdate>
            <title>multiple 3.75 minute orthophotographic quadrangles</title>
            <geoform>remote sensing image</geoform>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>12000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>stable-base material</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>1994</begdate>
              <enddate>1996</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>date aerial photography was flown</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>NRCS3</srccitea>
        <srccontr>
base material for compilation and a reference for
compilation of cultural features
</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>
U.S. Department of Agriculture,
Natural Resources Conservation Service
</origin>
            <pubdate>2007</pubdate>
            <title>Digital Raster Graphic County Mosaic of Wayne County, New York</title>
            <geoform>map</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Fort Worth, Texas</pubplace>
              <publish>
U.S. Department of Agriculture,
Natural Resources Conservation Service,
National Cartography and Geospatial Center
</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>24000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>online</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>1949</begdate>
              <enddate>1978</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>source material publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>NRCS4</srccitea>
        <srccontr>source for county boundaries</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>
U.S. Department of Agriculture,
Natural Resources Conservation Service
</origin>
            <pubdate>unpublished material</pubdate>
            <title>annotated soil delineation overlays</title>
            <geoform>map</geoform>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>12000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>stable-base material</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>1994</begdate>
              <enddate>1996</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>date aerial photography was flown</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>NRCS5</srccitea>
        <srccontr>scanning and digitizing source</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>U.S. Department of Agriculture</origin>
            <pubdate>2007</pubdate>
            <title>
National Soil Information System (NASIS) database for Wayne
County, New York
</title>
            <geoform>tabular digital data</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Fort Collins, Colorado</pubplace>
              <publish>
U.S. Department of Agriculture,
Natural Resources Conservation Service,
Information Technology Center
</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>online</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>2007</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>export certification date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>NRCS6</srccitea>
        <srccontr>tabular data linked to spatial data</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>
U.S. Department of Agriculture,
Natural Resources Conservation Service
</origin>
            <pubdate>2007</pubdate>
            <title>National Soil Information System (NASIS) data base</title>
            <geoform>tabular digital data</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Fort Collins, Colorado</pubplace>
              <publish>
U.S. Department of Agriculture,
Natural Resources Conservation Service
</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>database</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>2007</begdate>
              <enddate>2007</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>NASIS</srccitea>
        <srccontr>attribute (tabular) information</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural
Resources Conservation Service
</origin>
            <pubdate>2007</pubdate>
            <title>
Soil Survey Geographic (SSURGO) database for Wayne
County, New York
</title>
            <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Fort Worth, Texas</pubplace>
              <publish>
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural
Resources Conservation Service, National Cartography
and Geospatial Center
</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>online</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>2007</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>NRCS7</srccitea>
        <srccontr>re-archiving source</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>U.S Department of Agriculture, Farm Service Agency</origin>
            <pubdate>2008</pubdate>
            <title>NAIP imagery for Wayne County, New York</title>
            <geoform>remote sensing image</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Salt Lake City, Utah</pubplace>
              <publish>U.S. Department of Agriculture, Farm Service Agency APFO</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>online</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>2008</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>date aerial photography was flown</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>FSA1</srccitea>
        <srccontr>editing selected water and soil polygon boundaries to current imagery</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>
U.S. Department of Agriculture,
Natural Resources Conservation Service
</origin>
            <pubdate>unpublished material</pubdate>
            <title>ARCGIS geodatabase for Wayne County, New York</title>
            <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>12000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>CD-ROM</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>2009</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>date of soil survey update</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>NRCS8</srccitea>
        <srccontr>source for digital revision</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>
U.S. Department of Agriculture,
Natural Resources Conservation Service
</origin>
            <pubdate>2005-2007</pubdate>
            <title>
Soil Survey Geographic (SSURGO) databases
for adjacent surveys
</title>
            <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Fort Collins, Colorado</pubplace>
              <publish>
U.S. Department of Agriculture,
Natural Resources Conservation Service,
Information Technology Center
</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>
These SSURGO certified soil surveys are adjacent to
the Soil Survey of (NY117) Wayne County, New York:
NY011  Cayuga County, New York
NY055  Monroe County, New York
NY069  Ontario County, New York
NY099  Seneca County, New York
</othercit>
            <onlink>&lt;http://soildatamart.nrcs.usda.gov/&gt;</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>12000, 24000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>online</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>2005</begdate>
              <enddate>2007</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>dates of publication</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>NRCS9</srccitea>
        <srccontr>used to check joins to the adjacent soil surveys</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>
U.S. Department of Agriculture,
Natural Resources Conservation Service
</origin>
            <pubdate>20100218</pubdate>
            <title>
Soil Survey Geographic (SSURGO) database
for Wayne County, New York
</title>
            <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Fort Worth, Texas</pubplace>
              <publish>
U.S. Department of Agriculture,
Natural Resources Conservation Service
</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>online</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>20100218</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>NRCS10</srccitea>
        <srccontr>
certified SSURGO product used as source
for digital revision
</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>
U.S. Department of Agriculture,
Natural Resources Conservation Service
</origin>
            <pubdate>unpublished material</pubdate>
            <title>
ARCGIS geodatabase for the Soil Survey of
Wayne County, New York
</title>
            <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>12000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>geographic database</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>2012</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>date of digitizing completion</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>NRCS11</srccitea>
        <srccontr>source for digital review</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources
Conservation Service
</origin>
            <pubdate>unpublished material</pubdate>
            <title>region 12 soils geodatabase</title>
            <geoform>file geodatabase</geoform>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>vector digital data</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>2006</begdate>
              <enddate>2012</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>SSURGO publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>NRCS12</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Source of digital revision</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
Wayne County had a soil survey published in 1978, at 1:15840 scale.
An evaluation was made of the soil survey in 2001. It was determined
that the soil map unit delineations and map unit components
were accurate.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>SCS1</srcused>
        <procdate>2001</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
Ratio film positives, at 1:12000 scale, were made
from the publication annotation overlays.  Soil map unit delineations,
soil symbols and special soil features were manually compiled from the
ratio film positives to stable-base material registered to 3.75 minute
orthophotographic quadrangles.  Errors from the published soil survey
were corrected and map unit boundaries were refined, as needed, to the
orthophotographic quadrangles.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NRCS1, NRCS2, NRCS3, NRCS5</srcused>
        <procdate>2006</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The National Soil Information System data base was
developed by Natural Resources Conservation Service soil scientists
according to national standards.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>SCS1, NRCS6</srcused>
        <procdate>2007</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The compiled soil and feature overlays were mailed
to the Wisconsin Digitizing Unit in Madison, Wisconsin.  The 3.75 minute
soil map unit delineation and label overlays were raster scanned at the
Wisconsin Digitizing Unit at 250 dpi on a Graphtec scanner in tiff
uncompressed format.  Four control points used, corresponded to the four
corners on the 3.75 minute quadrangles were, used for registration
during data collection.  The tiff files were imported into ArcGIS 9.1
ArcMap.  The tiff files were georeferenced in ArcMap.  Using the raster
cleanup tools, the tiff files were cleaned, edge-matched and vectorized
to a polygon feature class.  A survey area boundary was added to the
soil feature class  Using the label overlay tiff files as a back drop,
the soil polygons were attributed and a point feature class
was digitized and labeled.  Using topology rules, errors were
identified and corrected.  The data were then exported to polygon
and point coverages using ArcCatalog.  Next, the data were then
projected to Geographic coordinates in decimal degrees and run through
the 20040524 ReCert AMLs provided by NCGC and uploaded to the Soil Data
Warehouse for archival and distribution.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NRCS5</srcused>
        <procdate>2007</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist or
delegate, upon completion of data quality verification, determined
that the tabular data should be released for official use. A
selected set of map units and components in the soil survey legend was
copied to a staging database, and rating values for selected
interpretations were generated. The list of selected interpretations is
stored in the database table named sainterp.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NASIS</srcused>
        <procdate>20070808</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist or
delegate verified that the labels on the digitized soil map units
link to map units in the tabular database, and certified the joined
data sets for release to the Soil Data Warehouse. A system assigned
version number and date stamp were added and the data were copied to
the data warehouse. The tabular data for the map units and components
were extracted from the data warehouse and reformatted into the soil
data delivery data model, then stored in the Soil Data Mart. The spatial
data were copied to the Soil Data Mart without change.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NASIS</srcused>
        <procdate>20070808</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The soils staff in New York downloaded the SSURGO data for Wayne County
from the Soil Data Warehouse (SDW).  Water polygons and adjacent soil
polygons in the existing SSURGO spatial data were reviewed against the
1978 hardcopy soil survey atlas sheets and the 2008 NAIP imagery.
The digital mapping was revised where water polygons were determined
to be ponded soil, so that the spatial data corresponds more closely
with the original hard copy atlas sheets. Some edits to other polygons
were made based on the imagery and atlas sheets.  The revised
geodatabase was sent to the Michigan Digitizing Unit (MIDU) in
East Lansing, Michigan for review and certification.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>SCS1, FSA1, NRCS7, NRCS8</srcused>
        <procdate>2009</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The MIDU staff checked the spatial data with the ARCGIS Version 9.2
software.  The boundaries of this soil survey were adjusted to match
the adjacent soil surveys.  To remove excess vertices, the soil
boundaries were generalized at a 0.5 meter tolerance.  After the soil
survey was edited, the area, line and point feature classes were
converted to ARC/INFO coverages and exported as e00 files.
The digital maps of the mapping units and the special soil features
were imported into the ARC/INFO Version 7.2.1 software for review and
certification. The MIDU staff checked the data with a set of ARC Macro
Language (AML) programs developed by the NCGC.  The seamless coverages
were checked using the January 2006 SSURGO Evaluation AML programs.
Upon successful completion of the SSURGO Evaluation, the county
coverages, feature file and the metadata were electronically
transferred to the NRCS Staging Server to be joined with
the tabular data.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NRCS8, NRCS9</srcused>
        <procdate>20100216</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist or
delegate, upon completion of data quality verification, determined
that the tabular data should be released for official use. A
selected set of map units and components in the soil survey legend was
copied to a staging database, and rating values for selected
interpretations were generated. The list of selected interpretations is
stored in the database table named sainterp.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NASIS</srcused>
        <procdate>20100204</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
Soil scientists reviewed and edited data for hydric rating and hydric
criteria. Interpretations for storm water management were added to the set
of interpretations. The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil
Scientist or delegate verified that the labels on the digitized soil map
units link to map units in the tabular database, and certified the joined
data sets for release to the Soil Data Warehouse. A system assigned version
number and date stamp were added and the data were copied to the data
warehouse. The tabular data for the map units and components were extracted
from the data warehouse and reformatted into the soil data delivery data
model, then stored in the Soil Data Mart. The spatial data were copied to
the Soil Data Mart without change.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NASIS</srcused>
        <procdate>20100218</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist or
delegate, upon completion of data quality verification, determined
that the tabular data should be released for official use. A
selected set of map units and components in the soil survey legend was
copied to a staging database, and rating values for selected
interpretations were generated. The list of selected interpretations is
stored in the database table named sainterp.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NASIS</srcused>
        <procdate>20110308</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
Updated tabular data so that Massena soil map units contain both
poorly drained and somewhat poorly drained major components.
The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist or delegate
verified that the labels on the digitized soil map units link to map units
in the tabular database, and certified the joined data sets for release to
the Soil Data Warehouse. A system assigned version number and date stamp
were added and the data were copied to the data warehouse. The tabular data
for the map units and components were extracted from the data warehouse and
reformatted into the soil data delivery data model, then stored in the Soil
Data Mart. The spatial data were copied to the Soil Data Mart without change.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NASIS</srcused>
        <procdate>20110308</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist or
delegate, upon completion of data quality verification, determined
that the tabular data should be released for official use. A
selected set of map units and components in the soil survey legend was
copied to a staging database, and rating values for selected
interpretations were generated. The list of selected interpretations is
stored in the database table named sainterp.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NASIS</srcused>
        <procdate>20111208</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
Hydric ratings for minor soil components were included in the data set.
Hydrologic Soil Group data was updated to current criteria.
The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist or delegate
verified that the labels on the digitized soil map units link to map units
in the tabular database, and certified the joined data sets for release to
the Soil Data Warehouse. A system assigned version number and date stamp
were added and the data were copied to the data warehouse. The tabular data
for the map units and components were extracted from the data warehouse and
reformatted into the soil data delivery data model, then stored in the Soil
Data Mart. The spatial data were copied to the Soil Data Mart without change.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NASIS</srcused>
        <procdate>20111208</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The staff at the Major Land Resource Area (MLRA) Soil Survey Office in
Belmont, New York downloaded the Soil SURvey GeOgraphic (SSURGO)
dataset for Wayne County, New York from the Soil Data Mart (SDM).
Mapping along the join with Ontario County, New York has been adjusted
according to field work conducted by the NRCS soil scientists.  After
the edits were completed, the geodatabase for the soil survey was
forwarded to the certification team at the Michigan Digitizing Unit
(MIDU) in East Lansing, Michigan.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NRCS10, NRCS11</srcused>
        <procdate>2012</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The MIDU staff checked the spatial data with the ARCGIS Version 10.0
software.  The boundaries of this soil survey were adjusted to match
the adjacent soil surveys.  To remove excess vertices, the soil
boundaries were generalized at a 0.5 meter tolerance.  After the soil
survey was edited, the area, line and point feature classes were
converted to ARC/INFO coverages.  The digital maps of the mapping units
and the special soil features were imported into the ARC/INFO
Version 10.0 software for review and certification.  The MIDU staff
checked the data with a set of ARC Macro Language (AML) programs
developed by the USDA-NRCS National Cartographic and Geospatial Center
(NCGC). The seamless coverages were checked using the July 2009 SSURGO
Evaluation AML programs. The labels in the spatial data match the
symbols in the soils tables archived at the Soil Data Warehouse (SDW).
Upon successful completion of the SSURGO Evaluation, the area, line and
point coverages, the feature file and the metadata were electronically
transferred to the NRCS Staging Server to be joined with the tabular data.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NRCS11, NASIS</srcused>
        <procdate>2012</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist or
delegate verified that the labels on the digitized soil map units
link to map units in the tabular database, and certified the joined
data sets for release to the Soil Data Warehouse. A system assigned
version number and date stamp were added and the data were copied to
the data warehouse. The tabular data for the map units and components
were extracted from the data warehouse and reformatted into the soil
data delivery data model, then stored in the Soil Data Mart. The spatial
data were copied to the Soil Data Mart without change.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NASIS</srcused>
        <procdate>20120925</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The spatial data for Wayne County, New York soil survey area was
downloaded from the Soil Data Mart on October 15, 2012.  The individual
shapefiles were appended into a geodatabase for region 12.  The data were
processed in ARCGIS 10.1 using a topology object with a 0.1 meter cluster
tolerance for the purpose of eliminating gaps and overlaps within the
region 12 soils geodatabase.  Individual soil survey area data were
exported as shapefiles from the regional geodatabase.  A datum
transformation from NAD83 to WGS84 using the NAD_1983_To_WGS_1984_1 datum
transformation method was applied to the data.  The data were checked with
the SSURGO Evaluation scripts provided by U.S. Department of Agriculture,
Natural Resources Conservation Service. The shapefiles were then uploaded
to the soil data warehouse for archival and distribution.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NRCS12</srcused>
        <procdate>2013</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist or
delegate, upon completion of data quality verification, determined
that the tabular data should be released for official use. A
selected set of map units and components in the soil survey legend was
copied to a staging database, and rating values for selected
interpretations were generated. The list of selected interpretations is
stored in the database table named sainterp.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NASIS</srcused>
        <procdate>20131124</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist or
delegate verified that the labels on the digitized soil map units
link to map units in the tabular database, and certified the joined
data sets for release to the Soil Data Warehouse. A system assigned
version number and date stamp were added and the data were copied to
the data warehouse. The tabular data for the map units and components
were extracted from the data warehouse and reformatted into the soil
data delivery data model, then stored in the Soil Data Mart. The spatial
data were copied to the Soil Data Mart without change.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NASIS</srcused>
        <procdate>20131124</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist or
delegate, upon completion of data quality verification, determined
that the tabular data should be released for official use. A
selected set of map units and components in the soil survey legend was
copied to a staging database, and rating values for selected
interpretations were generated. The list of selected interpretations is
stored in the database table named sainterp.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NASIS</srcused>
        <procdate>20140917</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Soil interpretation factors K, T, WEG, WEI, concrete corrosion potential, and steel corrosion potential were calculated based on national standard parameters.
The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist or
delegate verified that the labels on the digitized soil map units
link to map units in the tabular database, and certified the joined
data sets for release to the Soil Data Warehouse. A system assigned
version number and date stamp were added and the data were copied to
the data warehouse. The tabular data for the map units and components
were extracted from the data warehouse and reformatted into the soil
data delivery data model, then stored in the Soil Data Mart. The spatial
data were copied to the Soil Data Mart without change.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NASIS</srcused>
        <procdate>20140917</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist or
delegate, upon completion of data quality verification, determined
that the tabular data should be released for official use. A
selected set of map units and components in the soil survey legend was
copied to a staging database, and rating values for selected
interpretations were generated. The list of selected interpretations is
stored in the database table named sainterp.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NASIS</srcused>
        <procdate>20150925</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist or
delegate verified that the labels on the digitized soil map units
link to map units in the tabular database, and certified the joined
data sets for release to the Soil Data Warehouse. A system assigned
version number and date stamp were added and the data were copied to
the data warehouse. The tabular data for the map units and components
were extracted from the data warehouse and reformatted into the soil
data delivery data model, then stored in the Soil Data Mart. The spatial
data were copied to the Soil Data Mart without change.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NASIS</srcused>
        <procdate>20150925</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist or
delegate, upon completion of data quality verification, determined
that the tabular data should be released for official use. A
selected set of map units and components in the soil survey legend was
copied to a staging database, and rating values for selected
interpretations were generated. The list of selected interpretations is
stored in the database table named sainterp.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NASIS</srcused>
        <procdate>20160924</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist or
delegate verified that the labels on the digitized soil map units
link to map units in the tabular database, and certified the joined
data sets for release to the Soil Data Warehouse. A system assigned
version number and date stamp were added and the data were copied to
the data warehouse. The tabular data for the map units and components
were extracted from the data warehouse and reformatted into the soil
data delivery data model, then stored in the Soil Data Mart. The spatial
data were copied to the Soil Data Mart without change.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NASIS</srcused>
        <procdate>20160924</procdate>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
        <direct>Vector</direct>
        <ptvctinf>
          <sdtsterm>
            <sdtstype>G-polygon</sdtstype>
            <ptvctcnt>33244</ptvctcnt>
          </sdtsterm>
        </ptvctinf>
      </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <geograph>
        <latres>0.000001</latres>
        <longres>0.0000001</longres>
        <geogunit>decimal degrees</geogunit>
      </geograph>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>World Geodetic System 1984</horizdn>
        <ellips>World Geodetic System 1984</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.00000</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257222</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>Special Soil Features</enttypl>
        <enttypd>
Special Soil Features represent soil, miscellaneous area, or landform
features that are too small to be digitized as soil delineations
(area features).
</enttypd>
        <enttypds>
Agricultural Handbook 18,
Soil Survey Manual, 1993, USDA, SCS.
</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Special Soil Features Codes</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>
Special Soil Features labels represent specific Special Soil
Features. These features are identified with a descriptive
label. The label is assigned to the point or line assigned
to represent the feature on maps.
</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>
Agricultural Handbook 18, Soil Survey Manual, 1993, USDA, SCS;
National Soil Survey Handbook, Title 430-VI, part 647
(current issue), USDA, NRCS.
</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <codesetd>
            <codesetn>
Classification and Correlation of
the Soils of Wayne County, New York
</codesetn>
            <codesets>
U.S. Department of Agriculture,
Natural Resources Conservation Service
</codesets>
          </codesetd>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
    <overview>
      <eaover>
Map Unit Delineations are closed polygons that may be dominated
by a single soil or miscellaneous area component plus allowable
similar or dissimilar soils, or they can be geographic mixtures
of groups of soils or soils and miscellaneous areas.

The map unit symbol uniquely identifies each closed map unit
delineation. Each symbol corresponds to a map unit name. The
map unit key is used to link to information in the National
Soil Information System tables.

Map Unit Delineations are described by the National Soil
Information System database. This attribute database gives the
proportionate extent of the component soils and the properties for
each soil. The database contains both estimated and measured data
on the physical and chemical soil properties and soil
interpretations for engineering, water management, recreation,
agronomic, woodland, range, and wildlife uses of the soil.

The National Soil Information System database contains static
metadata. It documents the data structure and includes such
information as what tables, columns, indexes, and relationships
are defined as well as a variety of attributes of each of these
database objects. Attributes include table and column
descriptions and detailed domain information.

The National Soil Information System database also contains a
distribution metadata. It records the criteria used for selecting
map units and components for inclusion in the set of distributed
data.

Special features are described in the feature table.  It includes an
area symbol, feature label, feature name, and feature description for
each special and ad hoc feature in the survey area.
</eaover>
      <eadetcit>
Soil Taxonomy: A basic system of soil classification for making and
interpreting soil surveys. Agricultural Handbook 436, 1999, USDA, SCS.

Keys to Soil Taxonomy (current issue), USDA, SCS.

National Soil Survey Handbook, Title 430-VI, part 647 (current
issue), USDA, NRCS.

Agricultural Handbook 18, Soil Survey Manual, 1993, USDA, SCS.
</eadetcit>
    </overview>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
        <distrib>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>Albert R. Mann Library</cntorg>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
              <address>Cornell University</address>
              <city>Ithaca</city>
              <state>New York</state>
              <postal>14853</postal>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>607-255-5406</cntvoice>
            <cntemail>mann-ref@cornell.edu</cntemail>
          </cntinfo>
        </distrib>
        <distliab>Cornell University provides these geographic data "as is". Cornell
          University makes no guarantee or warranty concerning the accuracy of
          information contained in the geographic data. Cornell University further
          makes no warranty either expressed or implied, regarding the condition of
          the product or its fitness for any particular purpose. The burden for
          determining fitness for use lies entirely with the user. Although these
          files have been processed successfully on computers at Cornell University,
          no warranty is made by Cornell University regarding the use of these data
          on any other system, nor does the fact of distribution constitute or imply
          any such warranty.</distliab>
        <stdorder>
        <digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>Shapefile</formname>
              <formcont>zipped shapefile</formcont>
              <filedec>zip</filedec>
              <transize>42.47</transize>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/79/23/cugir-007923.zip</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>metadata</formname>
              <formcont>FGDC XML metadata</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/79/23/fgdc.xml</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>HTML metadata</formname>
              <formcont>FGDC HTML metadata</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/79/23/fgdc.html</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
                <digtinfo>
                  <formname>KML</formname>
                  <formcont>generated KML, via WFS</formcont>
                </digtinfo>
                <digtopt>
                  <onlinopt>
                    <computer>
                      <networka>
                        <networkr>https://cugir.library.cornell.edu/geoserver/cugir/wfs?version=1.0.0&amp;request=GetFeature&amp;typeName=cugir007923&amp;outputFormat=application%2Fvnd.google-earth.kml%2Bxml</networkr>
                      </networka>
                    </computer>
                  </onlinopt>
                </digtopt>
              </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>GeoJSON</formname>
              <formcont>generated GeoJSON, via WFS</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir.library.cornell.edu/geoserver/cugir/wfs?version=1.0.0&amp;request=GetFeature&amp;typeName=cugir007923&amp;outputFormat=application%2Fjson</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>OGC:WMS</formname>
              <formcont>WMS, from GeoServer</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir.library.cornell.edu/geoserver/cugir/wms?version=1.1.0&amp;request=GetMap&amp;layers=cugir007923&amp;bbox=-77.39630736999999,43.002517069999996,-76.68210163,43.35383393&amp;width=256&amp;height=125&amp;srs=EPSG:4326&amp;format=image/png</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><fees>None</fees></stdorder>
      </distinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural
Resources Conservation Service, National
Geospatial Center of Excellence
</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>501 West Felix Street, Building 23</address>
          <city>Fort Worth</city>
          <state>Texas</state>
          <postal>76115</postal>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>800 672 5559</cntvoice>
        <cnttdd>202 720 2600</cnttdd>
        <cntfax>817 509 3469</cntfax>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <resdesc>Wayne County, New York SSURGO</resdesc>
    <distliab>
Although these data have been processed successfully on a computer
system at the U.S. Department of Agriculture, no warranty expressed
or implied is made by the Agency regarding the utility of the data
on any other system, nor shall the act of distribution constitute
any such warranty. The U.S. Department of Agriculture will warrant
the delivery of this product in computer readable format, and will
offer appropriate adjustment of credit when the product is determined
unreadable by correctly adjusted computer input peripherals, or
when the physical medium is delivered in damaged condition. Request
for adjustment of credit must be made within 90 days from the date
of this shipment from the ordering site.

The U.S. Department of Agriculture, nor any of its agencies are
liable for misuse of the data, for damage, for transmission of
viruses, or for computer contamination through the distribution of
these data sets. The U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) prohibits
discrimination in all its programs and activities on the basis of race,
color, national origin, sex, religion, age, disability, political
beliefs, sexual orientation, or marital or family status. (Not all
prohibited bases apply to all programs.)
</distliab>
    <stdorder>
      <digform>
        <digtinfo>
          <formname>ESRI shapefile</formname>
          <formcont>spatial</formcont>
          <transize>50.1</transize>
        </digtinfo>
        <digtopt>
          <onlinopt>
            <computer>
              <networka>
                <networkr>URL:http://DataGateway.nrcs.usda.gov/</networkr>
              </networka>
            </computer>
            <accinstr>
Select desired survey area at above Internet
Web site. An email address is required for receipt of
instructions on retrieval via anonymous FTP. Anticipate a
delay between submission of request at Web site and receipt of
email message.
</accinstr>
          </onlinopt>
        </digtopt>
      </digform>
      <fees>
There is currently no direct charge for requesting data or for
retrieval via FTP.
</fees>
      <ordering>
Visit the above mentioned Internet Web Site, select state or
territory, then select individual soil survey area of interest.
Spatial line data and locations of special feature symbols are in
ESRI ArcGIS shapefile, format. The National Soil Information
System attribute soil data are available in variable length, pipe
delimited, ASCII file format.
</ordering>
      <turnarnd>Typically within four hours</turnarnd>
    </stdorder>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
      <metd>20190524</metd>
      <metc>
        <cntinfo>
          <cntorgp>
            <cntorg>Albert R. Mann Library</cntorg>
          </cntorgp>
          <cntaddr>
            <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
            <address>Albert R. Mann Library</address>
            <city>Ithaca</city>
            <state>New York</state>
            <postal>14853</postal>
            <country>USA</country>
          </cntaddr>
          <cntvoice>607-255-5406</cntvoice>
          <cntemail>mann-ref@cornell.edu</cntemail>
        </cntinfo>
      </metc>
      <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
      <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
      <mettc>local time</mettc>
    </metainfo>
</metadata>
