<!DOCTYPE metadata SYSTEM "http://fgdc.gov/metadata/fgdc-std-001-1998.dtd">
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Tompkins County ITS GIS Division, Tompkins County Assessment Department</origin>
        <pubdate>20020701</pubdate>
        <title>Tax Parcels, Tompkins County NY, 2002</title>
        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Tompkins County</pubplace>
          <publish>Tompkins County GIS Program</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <onlink>https://cugir.library.cornell.edu/catalog/cugir-007499</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>The active tax parcel boundaries for all of Tompkins County for a given year. The boundaries represent the one-to-one match with the parcel boundaries shown on the final paper maps for a given year.</abstract>
      <purpose>The parcel boundaries represent legal descriptions of property ownership, as recorded in various public documents in the Tompkins County Clerk's Office.</purpose>
      <supplinf>Properties that are tracked by an account number (utilities, railroads, etc.) may be shown as several separate tax parcel boundaries, with different tax map print keys, even though they are tracked in the Real Property Services (RPS) database under the same account number and treated as one single parcel. The parcel region will show these account-number properties as one tax parcel boundary, while the printkey region will show each separate tax parcel boundary that is a part of the account number. As of 2000, the tax parcel boundaries have not been edge-matched by municipality, except for Villages within their respective Town. This shapefile data set is derived from the printkey region of all tax parcel data sets in Tompkins County and is maintained as a shapefile because it can be manipulated much faster in ArcView than an Arc/Info data set. All Individual Tompkins County Tax Parcels can be found in PDF Format: &lt;http://www.tompkins-co.org/gis/maps/tax.html&gt; In addition, New York State GIS also has Tompkins County Tax Parcel Information: &lt;http://www.nysgis.state.ny.us/repository/counties/tompkins.htm&gt;</supplinf>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <sngdate>
          <caldate>2002</caldate>
        </sngdate>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>The data represents an entire tax year, which begins July 1st of the previous tax year and ends June 30th of the current tax year. (For example, taxparcels2000 would represent the 2000 tax year roll, from July 1, 1999 to June 30, 2000). The data is "published" each July 1st as a "frozen file" in conjunction with a "frozen file" for the Real Property Services (RPS) database.</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Continually</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
          <bounding>
            <westbc>-76.696211</westbc>
            <eastbc>-76.237347</eastbc>
            <northbc>42.627348</northbc>
            <southbc>42.262716</southbc>
          </bounding>
        </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>LCSH</themekt>
        <themekey>Government property</themekey>
        <themekey>Real property</themekey>
        <themekey>Land use</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>boundaries</themekey>
        <themekey>ownership</themekey>
        <themekey>land record</themekey>
        <themekey>parcel</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
        <themekey>boundaries</themekey>
        <themekey>planningCadastre</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
              <themekt>CUGIR Category</themekt>
              <themekey>boundaries</themekey>
<themekey>property</themekey>
            </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>LCSH</placekt>
        <placekey>Tompkins County (N.Y.)</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>The following statement must be included with any products that use or are derived from this data set: Data contained in this product was originally produced by the Tompkins County ITS GIS Division and the Tompkins County Assessment Department and may not be reproduced or redistributed without the express written consent of the originators. The originators do not warrant the accuracy or completeness of the information portrayed by the data. The data contained herein is for visualization purposes only and cannot be used for conveyance. Property boundaries are based on legal documents, aerial photos, software interpolation, and registration to the 1991 Tompkins County Digital Planimetric Files and, therefore, may differ from legal property descriptions. For complete legal descriptions and conveyance, please refer to the appropriate deeds, surveys, and other legal documents.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Tompkins County ITS GIS Division</cntorg>
          <cntper>Kirk Eby</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>GIS Project Leader</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>128 East Buffalo Street</address>
          <city>Ithaca</city>
          <state>New York</state>
          <postal>14850</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>(607) 274-5418</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>(607) 274-5420</cntfax>
        <cntemail>mailto:gis@tompkins-co.org</cntemail>
        <hours>M-F 8:30 a.m. to 4:30 p.m.</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <browse>
              <browsen>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/74/99/preview.png</browsen>
              <browsed>preview of the dataset</browsed>
              <browset>PNG</browset>
            </browse>
    <datacred>Tompkins County ITS GIS Division and Tompkins County Assessment Department</datacred>
    <native>Computer Path-- (Current years)/DATA/SHAPEFILES/PROPERTY/TAXPARCELS(Prior years)/DATA/SHAPEFILES/PROPERTY/(4-digit tax year)/TAXPARCELS; SOFTWARE-- Windows NT 4.0 x86, ArcView Shapefile; LAYERS-- Overlapping Polygons</native>
    <crossref>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Tompkins County Assessment Department</origin>
        <pubdate>20040600</pubdate>
        <title>Tompkins County Real Property Services (RPS) Database</title>
        <othercit>The New York State mandated database of property ownership and information in Tompkins County. This database can be related to the digital tax parcels data sets using either the SWISPRINTK field or the PARCELKEY field.</othercit>
      </citeinfo>
    </crossref>
    <crossref>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Tompkins County Assessment Department</origin>
        <pubdate>20000701</pubdate>
        <title>Standard GIS Extract of Real Property Services Data - 2000</title>
        <othercit>Tompkins County ITS GIS Division is responsible for creating the extract and converting it to a format that is compatible with the County's GIS.</othercit>
      </citeinfo>
    </crossref>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>See Entity and Attribute Information</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <logic>The Printkey region from each municipality's tax map data set is appended into one County-wide data set. This data set's topology is then created using the CLEAN command, then converted to an ArcView shapefile. All error checking is done in the source data sets.</logic>
    <complete>Complete coverage for entire County.</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>Varies, depending on source of parcel boundary (survey, deed, aerial photo, raw conversion from paper maps). The accuracy of the data set is limited to the accuracy of the 1991 Tompkins County Planimetric Base Map series.</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
      <vertacc>
        <vertaccr>The accuracy of the data set is limited to the accuracy of the 1991 Tompkins County Planimetric Base Map series.</vertaccr>
      </vertacc>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Tax parcel boundaries were initially maintained manually on mylar originals, using erasable ink. In 1991, a series of planimetric base data sets were produced from aerial photography, and are now referred to as the 1991 Tompkins County Digital Planimetric Base Map. The tax parcel mylar maps were digitized using MapGrafix and referenced to the 1991 Tompkins County Digital Planimetric Base Map. In 1997, the MapGrafix data sets for the City of Ithaca and the Towns of Caroline and Danby were approved by the New York State Office of Real Property Services (NYS ORPS). In 1998, the Map Grafix data sets were converted to Arc/Info for the City of Ithaca, Towns of Caroline, Danby, Dryden, and Ithaca, and the Villages of Cayuga Heights, Dryden, and Freeville. In 1999, the Towns of Enfield, Groton, Lansing, Newfield, and Ulysses, and the Villages of Groton, Lansing, and Trumansburg were converted to Arc/Info. Beginning with the 1999 tax year, all tax parcel boundaries are maintained in Arc/Info, all tax maps are printed using ArcView, and all tax maps are archived digitally using Adobe Acrobat, as well as the traditional paper archival. During the transition period from paper to digital maps, parcel boundaries are approximate, except for those boundaries that have been input using paper surveys and legal descriptions. The tax parcel data sets consist of three groups of layers: boundary layers, text layers, and region layers. The boundary layers consist of those Arc/Info feature classes upon which the region layers are created. Boundary layers include the nodes, arcs, and polygons. Parcel boundaries are changed by first modifying the arc and node layers, and updating the arc attributes. Next, the polygons are re-created and their attributes are updated. The text layers are then updated to reflect the boundary changes. Finally, the regions are created from the polygons using polygon attributes and the Arc/Info REGIONDISSOLVE command. The text layers are Arc/Info annotation layers and include acreage, block, dimension, non-roll section 1 (exempt/utility/state lands), lot, Military Tract/Watkins and Flint Purchase, municipality, place, road name, special district, tax map, tic mark, and water text, as it appears on the printed tax parcel maps. The region layers include deed book/page, municipal, parcel, printkey, and tax map regions. The printkey regions from each of the municipal data sets for the current tax year are then combined into a county-wide data set, which is then converted to an ArcView shapefile. Regions for special districts are derived from polygon attributes in the same manner as the other regions, for each municipality, then combined into a County-wide special districts data set. Regions for public lands are similiarly combined and converted into a County-wide public lands data set.</procdesc>
        <procdate>1998 (partial coverage), 1999 and newer</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>Tompkins County ITS GIS Division</cntorg>
              <cntper>Kirk Eby</cntper>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntpos>GIS Project Leader</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>128 East Buffalo Street</address>
              <city>Ithaca</city>
              <state>New York</state>
              <postal>14850</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>(607) 274-5418</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>(607) 274-5420</cntfax>
            <cntemail>mailto:gis@tompkins-co.org</cntemail>
            <hours>M-F 8:30 a.m. to 4:30 p.m.</hours>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
    <cloud>0</cloud>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
        <direct>Vector</direct>
        <ptvctinf>
          <sdtsterm>
            <sdtstype>G-polygon</sdtstype>
            <ptvctcnt>35648</ptvctcnt>
          </sdtsterm>
        </ptvctinf>
      </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <gridsys>
          <gridsysn>State Plane Coordinate System 1983</gridsysn>
          <spcs>
            <spcszone>3102</spcszone>
            <transmer>
              <sfctrmer>0.9999375</sfctrmer>
              <longcm>-76.5833333334</longcm>
              <latprjo>40</latprjo>
              <feast>250000</feast>
              <fnorth>0</fnorth>
            </transmer>
          </spcs>
        </gridsys>
        <planci>
          <plance>Coordinate Pair</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>1</absres>
            <ordres>1</ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>US survey feet</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378206</semiaxis>
        <denflat>294.9786982</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>TAXPARCELS</enttypl>
        <enttypd>Polygons provide the basis for all other area layers (regions), which are produced from attributes of the polygons. The polygons are the source layer for information about the accuracy of the area boundaries.</enttypd>
        <enttypds>Tompkins County ITS GIS Division, 1998</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>AREA</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Polygon Area (Internal Software Attribute, in Map Units)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Tompkins County ITS GIS Division, 1997</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Unspecified</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>PERIMETER</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Polygon Boundary Perimeter (Internal Software Attribute, in Map Units)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Tompkins County ITS GIS Division, 1997</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Unspecified</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>ParcelKey</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Real Property Services (RPS) Database parcel key (Swis-Section-Block-Lot or SSBL). This field is updated yearly based on the GIS extract of the final-roll RPS database. This field can be used to relate to the RPS database.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Tompkins County ITS GIS Division, 1997</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Unspecified</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>PrintKey</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Real Property Services database print key (Section-Block-Lot or S-B-L).</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Tompkins County ITS GIS Division, 1997</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Unspecified</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>AccountNum</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Real Property Services (RPS) Database account number, which is used to uniquely identify railroad, state-owned, and utility properties. The original values were extracted directly from the RPS database. This field is updated automatically when the region layers are created using the PARCREGS.aml Macro.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Tompkins County ITS GIS Division, 1998</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Unspecified</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Swis</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>State SWIS code for the municipality in which the parcel is located (not necessarily the same as the SWIS code in which the polygon is located - see POLYSWIS field).</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Tompkins County ITS GIS Division, 1997</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom/>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SwisPrintK</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Concatenation of SWIS code, "-", and the PRINTKEY field, for those polygons without an account number (ie, a blank ACCOUNTNUM), or a concatenation of SWIS code, "-", and the ACCOUNTNUM field, for those polygons with an account number. This field is easily reproducible within the Real Property Services database extract, and is used as the primary relate (key) field to the RPS extract from the parcel data sets. This field is used to create the Print Key region in this data set.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Tompkins County ITS GIS Division, 1997</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Unspecified</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>CalcAcres</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Calculated Acreage (AREA / 43560)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Tompkins County ITS GIS Division, 1998</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Unspecified</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>RpsAcres</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Real Property Services (RPS) acreage, extracted from the RPS database. This acreage will reflect the total acreage of the parcel, which is not necessarily the same area as the polygon.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Tompkins County ITS GIS Division, 1999</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Unspecified</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>LongDD</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Longitude (X-coordinate), in decimal degrees, of the main parcel centroid (ie, the polygon centroid coded with PRCLTEXT equal to MP or SP).</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Tompkins County ITS GIS Division, 2000</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Unspecified</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>LatDD</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Lattitude (Y-coordinate), in decimal degrees, of the main parcel centroid (ie, the polygon centroid coded with PRCLTEXT equal to MP or SP).</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Tompkins County ITS GIS Division, 2000</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Unspecified</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Inset</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Inset Location for paper map. Main map area will always be 0, with insets numbered 1 and above. For maps without an inset, the inset number will be 0. This field will be used to generate an inset region, if it deemed as necessary.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Tompkins County ITS GIS Division, 1999</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Unspecified</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
        <distrib>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>Albert R. Mann Library</cntorg>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
              <address>Cornell University</address>
              <city>Ithaca</city>
              <state>New York</state>
              <postal>14853</postal>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>607-255-5406</cntvoice>
            <cntemail>mann-ref@cornell.edu</cntemail>
          </cntinfo>
        </distrib>
        <distliab>Cornell University provides these geographic data "as is". Cornell
          University makes no guarantee or warranty concerning the accuracy of
          information contained in the geographic data. Cornell University further
          makes no warranty either expressed or implied, regarding the condition of
          the product or its fitness for any particular purpose. The burden for
          determining fitness for use lies entirely with the user. Although these
          files have been processed successfully on computers at Cornell University,
          no warranty is made by Cornell University regarding the use of these data
          on any other system, nor does the fact of distribution constitute or imply
          any such warranty.</distliab>
        <stdorder>
        <digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>Shapefile</formname>
              <formcont>zipped shapefile</formcont>
              <filedec>zip</filedec>
              <transize>5.38</transize>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/74/99/cugir-007499.zip</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>metadata</formname>
              <formcont>FGDC XML metadata</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/74/99/fgdc.xml</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>HTML metadata</formname>
              <formcont>FGDC HTML metadata</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/74/99/fgdc.html</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
                <digtinfo>
                  <formname>KML</formname>
                  <formcont>generated KML, via WFS</formcont>
                </digtinfo>
                <digtopt>
                  <onlinopt>
                    <computer>
                      <networka>
                        <networkr>https://cugir.library.cornell.edu/geoserver/cugir/wfs?version=1.0.0&amp;request=GetFeature&amp;typeName=cugir007499&amp;outputFormat=application%2Fvnd.google-earth.kml%2Bxml</networkr>
                      </networka>
                    </computer>
                  </onlinopt>
                </digtopt>
              </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>GeoJSON</formname>
              <formcont>generated GeoJSON, via WFS</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir.library.cornell.edu/geoserver/cugir/wfs?version=1.0.0&amp;request=GetFeature&amp;typeName=cugir007499&amp;outputFormat=application%2Fjson</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>OGC:WMS</formname>
              <formcont>WMS, from GeoServer</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir.library.cornell.edu/geoserver/cugir/wms?version=1.1.0&amp;request=GetMap&amp;layers=cugir007499&amp;bbox=-76.70997692,42.25177704,-76.22358108,42.638286959999995&amp;width=256&amp;height=203&amp;srs=EPSG:4326&amp;format=image/png</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><fees>None</fees></stdorder>
      </distinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Tompkins County ITS GIS Division</cntorg>
          <cntper>Greg Potter</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>GIS Manager</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>128 East Buffalo Street</address>
          <city>Ithaca</city>
          <state>New York</state>
          <postal>14850</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>(607) 274-5416</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>(607) 274-5420</cntfax>
        <cntemail>mailto:gis@tompkins-co.org</cntemail>
        <hours>M-F 8:30 a.m. to 4:30 p.m.</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>The tax parcel data set and any products derived from it represents a compilation of graphical and textual information from deeds and surveys, hand-drawn mylar maps, a digitial planimetric base map, various paper and digital aerial photographs, and digital conversion of hand-drawn mylar maps. Errors and omissions can occur from each of these sources, as each source represents a large number of records and originators of information. As a practical matter, Tompkins County does not warrant the accuracy or completeness of the information portrayed. The end user of the data sets and products derived from them agrees to accept the data "as is", with the full knowledge that errors and omissions may exist. The end user further agrees to hold harmless Tompkins County for any liability or damages that may result from an improper or inappropriate use of the data.</distliab>
    <stdorder>
      <nondig>Paper maps, either color or black and white, available on 11"x17" 28lb paper or on 24"x36" coated inkjet paper. Maps are also available on special media and at different print sizes, by request.</nondig>
      <fees>Half-size (11"x17") color maps are $2.00 each. Half-size black and white maps are $0.50 each. Full-size (24"x36") color and black and white maps are $4.00 each on coated paper. Fees for special-request media or non-standard print sizes will vary. The cost of reproduction for a standard data set, which varies depending on the type of media requested (zip disk, CD-ROM, floppy diskette, etc). A standard data set is an Arc/Info coverage, Arc/Info export (.e00) file, ArcView shapefile, Dbase III database, or Microsoft Access database. Official tax maps are available in Adobe Acrobat format, organized by municipality. Custom data sets or file types will incur additional labor costs. The standard data set is also available for free download at &lt;http://www.nysgis.state.ny.us/repository/counties/tompkins.htm&gt;</fees>
      <ordering>Submit a written request to the Tompkins County Assessment Department or Tompkins County ITS GIS Division. Specify the municipality, map number(s), media type, print size, and color or black and white.</ordering>
      <turnarnd>Half-size maps: 3-4 days. Full-size maps: 5-10 days.</turnarnd>
    </stdorder>
    <availabl>
      <timeinfo>
        <sngdate>
          <caldate>19990100</caldate>
        </sngdate>
      </timeinfo>
    </availabl>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
      <metd>20190524</metd>
      <metc>
        <cntinfo>
          <cntorgp>
            <cntorg>Albert R. Mann Library</cntorg>
          </cntorgp>
          <cntaddr>
            <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
            <address>Albert R. Mann Library</address>
            <city>Ithaca</city>
            <state>New York</state>
            <postal>14853</postal>
            <country>USA</country>
          </cntaddr>
          <cntvoice>607-255-5406</cntvoice>
          <cntemail>mann-ref@cornell.edu</cntemail>
        </cntinfo>
      </metc>
      <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
      <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
      <mettc>local time</mettc>
    </metainfo>
</metadata>
