<!DOCTYPE metadata SYSTEM "http://fgdc.gov/metadata/fgdc-std-001-1998.dtd">
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>United States Department of Agriculture (USDA), National Agricultural Statistics Service (NASS), Research and Development Division, Geospatial Information Branch, Spatial Analysis Research Section (SARS)</origin>
        <pubdate>20060101</pubdate>
        <title>Cropland Data Layer, New York State, 2002</title>
        <edition>2002 edition</edition>
        <geoform>raster digital data</geoform>
        <serinfo>
          <sername>USDA-NASS Cropland Data Layer</sername>
          <issue>New York 2002</issue>
        </serinfo>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>USDA-NASS Marketing Division, Washington, D.C.</pubplace>
          <publish>United States Department of Agriculture (USDA), National Agriculture Statistics Service (NASS)</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <othercit>Available only on DVD through the official website http://www.nass.usda.gov/research/Cropland/SARS1a.htm.</othercit>
        <onlink>https://cugir.library.cornell.edu/catalog/cugir-008027</onlink>
        <onlink>http://www.nass.usda.gov/research/Cropland/SARS1a.htm</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>
The USDA-NASS 2002 New York Cropland Data Layer (CDL) is a raster, geo-referenced, categorized land cover data layer produced using satellite imagery from the Thematic Mapper (TM) instrument on Landsat 5 and the Enhanced Thematic Mapper (ETM+) on Landsat 7. The imagery was collected between May 4, 2002 and September 12, 2002. The approximate scale is 1:100,000 with a ground resolution of 30 meters by 30 meters. The CDL emphasis is on agricultural land cover. The area of coverage is the entire State of New York.
This land cover dataset is part of a one-time series in which ten Mid-Atlantic States were categorized based on the extensive field observations collected during the 2002 annual NASS June Agricultural Survey. No farmer reported data is included or derivable from the Cropland Data Layer. The area of coverage for the 2002 Mid-Atlantic CDL includes the entire states of Connecticut, Delaware, Maryland, New Jersey, New York, North Carolina, Pennsylvania, Rhode Island, Virginia and West Virginia. The funding for this project was shared between the USDA-NASS and Towson State University.
The 2002 Mid-Atlantic CDL is currently a special one-time project. However, the possibility does exist to establish an annual cropland data layer for any state that shows significant interest and can offer an in-state cooperative agreement with another federal, state, local, or university agency or group. If interested, please contact the Section Head of the USDA-NASS Spatial Analysis Research Section at 703/877-8000.
There are several additional Mid-Western States for which Cropland Data Layers are produced on an annual basis. The website below provides information and examples of all publicly available Cropland Data Layers:  http://www.nass.usda.gov/research/Cropland/SARS1a.htm
</abstract>
      <purpose>
The purpose of the Cropland Data Layer Program is to use satellite imagery to (1) provide supplemental acreage estimates for the state's major commodities and (2) produce digital, crop specific, categorized geo-referenced output products.
These data are intended for geographic display and analysis at the state level. The cropland data layers are provided "as is". USDA-NASS does not warrant results you may obtain using the data.
</purpose>
      <supplinf>
PEDITOR is used as the NASS' main image processing software. PEDITOR has been maintained in-house and contains much of the functionality available in commercial image processing systems. However, program/process modifications are relatively easy to support in a research type environment, and the development/release cycle is faster. PEDITOR is deployed in all participating NASS State Statistical Field Offices to handle the ground truthing process and all image processing tasks, and is continuously tested with the Spatial Analysis Research Section (SARS) in Fairfax, Virginia. Currently, PEDITOR runs on most Microsoft Windows platforms.
Additional information about ArcExplorer from ESRI can be found at http://www.esri.com/arcexplorer.
Additional information about EarthSat Inc's ortho-rectified GeoCover Stock used to georegister the NASS Cropland Data Layer can be found at http://www.geocover.com/.
Towson University, Center for Geographic Information Sciences (CGIS):
http://cgis.towson.edu/
</supplinf>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>20020504</begdate>
          <enddate>20020912</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>ground condition</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
          <bounding>
            <westbc>-79.996683</westbc>
            <eastbc>-71.650117</eastbc>
            <northbc>45.022995</northbc>
            <southbc>40.404936</southbc>
          </bounding>
        </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>crop cover</themekey>
        <themekey>classification</themekey>
        <themekey>cropland</themekey>
        <themekey>agriculture</themekey>
        <themekey>land cover</themekey>
        <themekey>crop estimates</themekey>
        <themekey>crop identification</themekey>
        <themekey>Landsat</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
              <themekt>CUGIR Category</themekt>
              <themekey>landcover</themekey>
            </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>None</placekt>
        <placekey>New York</placekey>
        <placekey>Mid-Atlantic</placekey>
      </place>
      <temporal>
        <tempkt>None</tempkt>
        <tempkey>2002</tempkey>
      </temporal>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>There are NO copyright restrictions with either the NASS Cropland categorized imagery or ESRI's ArcExplorer software included on the DVD. The NASS Cropland categorized imagery is considered public domain and FREE to redistribute. However, NASS would appreciate acknowledgment or credit for the usage of our categorized imagery.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>USDA-NASS Spatial Analysis Research Section</cntorg>
          <cntper>USDA-NASS Spatial Analysis Research Section staff</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>
          <address>3251 Old Lee Highway, Rm 305</address>
          <city>Fairfax</city>
          <state>Virginia</state>
          <postal>22030-1504</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>703/877-8000</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>703/877-8044</cntfax>
        <cntemail>HQ_RD_OD@nass.usda.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <browse>
              <browsen>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/80/27/preview.png</browsen>
              <browsed>preview of the dataset</browsed>
              <browset>PNG</browset>
            </browse>
    <native>
The data layer is distributed on DVD in a GEOTIFF image file format.
The hardware requirements for processing this data set are as follows: for digitizing/ground truth editing, any of the 32 bit Microsoft OS's will work.  For computationally intensive jobs including; scene processing, clustering, classification, estimation and mosaicking a batch type system is utilized where jobs can be queued on different devices, and the minimum requirements are NT/2000/XP.
Image processing is performed by PEDITOR, where PEDITOR utilizes the Windows console along with environmental variables, and neither are available with 95/98. PEDITOR as it is now constituted, will only run under the Microsoft Windows operating systems.
A Microsoft Visual FoxPro application called the Remote Sensing Project or RSP is used to manage the ground truth collection process, and track each segment to its completion.
Commercial off the shelf software XLNT from Advanced Systems Concepts, allows for batch job processing on the NT/2000/XP operating systems.  SARS utilizes XLNT to run computationally intensive jobs that are shared across network resources to expedite processing.
</native>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>Classification accuracy is generally between 85% to 95% correct for agricultural-related land cover categories. Due to the extensiveness of the attribute accuracy  report, the accuracy metadata is published on the DVD in an html format. The DVD contains details of the Analysis District coverage, sensors used, percent correct and kappa coefficients, regression analysis by Analysis District, the sampling frame scheme, and the original cover type signatures.</attraccr>
      <qattracc>
        <attraccv>Classification accuracy is generally between 85% to 95% correct for agricultural-related land cover categories.</attraccv>
        <attracce>NASS collects the remote sensing Acreage Estimation Program's field level training data during the June Agricultural Survey. This is a national survey based on a stratified random sample of land areas selected from each state's area frame. An area frame is a land use stratification based on percent cultivation. Our enumerators are given questionnaires to ask the farmers what, where, when and how much are they planting.  Our surveys focus on cropland, but the enumerators record all land covers within the sampled area of land whether it is cropland or not. NASS uses broad land use categories to define land that is not under cultivation, including; non-agricultural, pasture/rangeland, waste, woods, and farmstead. NASS defines these non-agricultural land use types very broadly, which makes it difficult to precisely know what specific type of land use/cover actually is on the ground. For instance, there is no breakdown as to the type of woods in a given field/pasture, that's where the power of a GIS could be useful. If a external forestry GIS layer was overlaid, the land use can be accurately identified, and the specific cover type can be derived from the data layer. SARS is currently looking at creating extra categories for the enumerators to better identify non-cropland features, thereby, increasing the accuracy and improving the appearance of the classification.</attracce>
      </qattracc>
    </attracc>
    <logic>The accuracy of the land cover classifications are evaluated using the extensive training data collected in the annual NASS June Agricultural Survey (JAS).</logic>
    <complete>The area of coverage is the entire State of New York.</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>The categorized images are co-registered to EarthSat Inc's ortho-rectified GeoCover Stock Mosaic images using automated block correlation techniques.  The block correlation is run against band two of each original raw satellite image and band two of the GeoCover Stock Mosaic.  The resulting correlations are applied to each categorized image, and then added to a master image or mosaic using PEDITOR.  The EarthSat images were chosen as they provide the best available large area ortho-rectified images as a basis to register large volume Landsat images with.</horizpar>
        <qhorizpa>
          <horizpav>50 meters root mean squared error overall</horizpav>
          <horizpae>The GeoCover Stock Mosaics are within 50 meters root mean squared error overall. See EarthSat's http://www.geocover.com/ website for further details.</horizpae>
        </qhorizpa>
      </horizpa>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Landsat 5</origin>
            <pubdate>20021001</pubdate>
            <title>LANDSAT TM Path 12, Row(s) 31</title>
            <geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Sioux Falls, South Dakota, USA</pubplace>
              <publish>USGS EROS Data Center</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>
LANDSAT TM Path 12, Row(s) 31. 30 meter by 30 meter pixel resolution, EOSAT Fast Format.
Additional information about Landsat 5 and Landsat 7 satellite imagery can be obtained from the United States Geological Survey (USGS) EROS Data Center.
</othercit>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>100000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>DVD</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <mdattim>
              <sngdate>
                <caldate>20020504</caldate>
              </sngdate>
              <sngdate>
                <caldate>20020909</caldate>
              </sngdate>
            </mdattim>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccontr>Raw data used in land cover spectral signature analysis.</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Landsat 7</origin>
            <pubdate>20021001</pubdate>
            <title>LANDSAT TM Path 13, Row(s) 31 and 32</title>
            <geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Sioux Falls, South Dakota, USA</pubplace>
              <publish>USGS EROS Data Center</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>
LANDSAT TM Path 13, Row(s) 31 and 32. 30 meter by 30 meter pixel resolution, EOSAT Fast Format.
Additional information about Landsat 5 and Landsat 7 satellite imagery can be obtained from the United States Geological Survey (USGS) EROS Data Center.
</othercit>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>100000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>DVD</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <mdattim>
              <sngdate>
                <caldate>20020511</caldate>
              </sngdate>
              <sngdate>
                <caldate>20020908</caldate>
              </sngdate>
            </mdattim>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccontr>Raw data used in land cover spectral signature analysis.</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Landsat 7</origin>
            <pubdate>20021001</pubdate>
            <title>LANDSAT TM Path 14, Row(s) 29, 30 and 31</title>
            <geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Sioux Falls, South Dakota, USA</pubplace>
              <publish>USGS EROS Data Center</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>
LANDSAT TM Path 14, Row(s) 29, 30 and 31. 30 meter by 30 meter pixel resolution, EOSAT Fast Format.
Additional information about Landsat 5 and Landsat 7 satellite imagery can be obtained from the United States Geological Survey (USGS) EROS Data Center.
</othercit>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>100000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>DVD</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>20020510</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccontr>Raw data used in land cover spectral signature analysis.</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Landsat 5</origin>
            <pubdate>20021001</pubdate>
            <title>LANDSAT TM Path 14, Row(s) 29, 30 and 31</title>
            <geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Sioux Falls, South Dakota, USA</pubplace>
              <publish>USGS EROS Data Center</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>
LANDSAT TM Path 14, Row(s) 29, 30 and 31. 30 meter by 30 meter pixel resolution, EOSAT Fast Format.
Additional information about Landsat 5 and Landsat 7 satellite imagery can be obtained from the United States Geological Survey (USGS) EROS Data Center.
</othercit>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>100000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>DVD</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>20020907</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccontr>Raw data used in land cover spectral signature analysis.</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Landsat 7</origin>
            <pubdate>20021001</pubdate>
            <title>LANDSAT TM Path 14, Row(s) 32</title>
            <geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Sioux Falls, South Dakota, USA</pubplace>
              <publish>USGS EROS Data Center</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>
LANDSAT TM Path 14, Row(s) 32. 30 meter by 30 meter pixel resolution, EOSAT Fast Format.
Additional information about Landsat 5 and Landsat 7 satellite imagery can be obtained from the United States Geological Survey (USGS) EROS Data Center.
</othercit>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>100000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>DVD</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <mdattim>
              <sngdate>
                <caldate>20020814</caldate>
              </sngdate>
              <sngdate>
                <caldate>20020424</caldate>
              </sngdate>
            </mdattim>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccontr>Raw data used in land cover spectral signature analysis.</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Landsat 5</origin>
            <pubdate>20021001</pubdate>
            <title>LANDSAT TM Path 15, Row(s) 29, 30 and 31</title>
            <geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Sioux Falls, South Dakota, USA</pubplace>
              <publish>USGS EROS Data Center</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>
LANDSAT TM Path 15, Row(s) 29, 30 and 31. 30 meter by 30 meter pixel resolution, EOSAT Fast Format.
Additional information about Landsat 5 and Landsat 7 satellite imagery can be obtained from the United States Geological Survey (USGS) EROS Data Center.
</othercit>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>100000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>DVD</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>20020525</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccontr>Raw data used in land cover spectral signature analysis.</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Landsat 7</origin>
            <pubdate>20021001</pubdate>
            <title>LANDSAT TM Path 15, Row(s) 29, 30 and 31</title>
            <geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Sioux Falls, South Dakota, USA</pubplace>
              <publish>USGS EROS Data Center</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>
LANDSAT TM Path 15, Row(s) 29, 30 and 31. 30 meter by 30 meter pixel resolution, EOSAT Fast Format.
Additional information about Landsat 5 and Landsat 7 satellite imagery can be obtained from the United States Geological Survey (USGS) EROS Data Center.
</othercit>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>100000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>DVD</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>20020906</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccontr>Raw data used in land cover spectral signature analysis.</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Landsat 7</origin>
            <pubdate>20021001</pubdate>
            <title>LANDSAT TM Path 15, Row(s) 32</title>
            <geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Sioux Falls, South Dakota, USA</pubplace>
              <publish>USGS EROS Data Center</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>
LANDSAT TM Path 15, Row(s) 32. 30 meter by 30 meter pixel resolution, EOSAT Fast Format.
Additional information about Landsat 5 and Landsat 7 satellite imagery can be obtained from the United States Geological Survey (USGS) EROS Data Center.
</othercit>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>100000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>DVD</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <mdattim>
              <sngdate>
                <caldate>20020704</caldate>
              </sngdate>
              <sngdate>
                <caldate>20020906</caldate>
              </sngdate>
            </mdattim>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccontr>Raw data used in land cover spectral signature analysis.</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Landsat 5</origin>
            <pubdate>20021001</pubdate>
            <title>LANDSAT TM Path 16, Row(s) 29, 30 and 31</title>
            <geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Sioux Falls, South Dakota, USA</pubplace>
              <publish>USGS EROS Data Center</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>
LANDSAT TM Path 16, Row(s) 29, 30 and 31. 30 meter by 30 meter pixel resolution, EOSAT Fast Format.
Additional information about Landsat 5 and Landsat 7 satellite imagery can be obtained from the United States Geological Survey (USGS) EROS Data Center.
</othercit>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>100000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>DVD</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>20020804</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccontr>Raw data used in land cover spectral signature analysis.</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Landsat 5</origin>
            <pubdate>20021001</pubdate>
            <title>LANDSAT TM Path 17, Row(s) 30</title>
            <geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Sioux Falls, South Dakota, USA</pubplace>
              <publish>USGS EROS Data Center</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>
LANDSAT TM Path 17, Row(s) 30. 30 meter by 30 meter pixel resolution, EOSAT Fast Format.
Additional information about Landsat 5 and Landsat 7 satellite imagery can be obtained from the United States Geological Survey (USGS) EROS Data Center.
</othercit>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>100000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>DVD</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <mdattim>
              <sngdate>
                <caldate>20020523</caldate>
              </sngdate>
              <sngdate>
                <caldate>20020710</caldate>
              </sngdate>
            </mdattim>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccontr>Raw data used in land cover spectral signature analysis.</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Landsat 5</origin>
            <pubdate>20021001</pubdate>
            <title>LANDSAT TM Path 17, Row(s) 31</title>
            <geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Sioux Falls, South Dakota, USA</pubplace>
              <publish>USGS EROS Data Center</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>
LANDSAT TM Path 17, Row(s) 31. 30 meter by 30 meter pixel resolution, EOSAT Fast Format.
Additional information about Landsat 5 and Landsat 7 satellite imagery can be obtained from the United States Geological Survey (USGS) EROS Data Center.
</othercit>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>100000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>DVD</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <mdattim>
              <sngdate>
                <caldate>20020523</caldate>
              </sngdate>
              <sngdate>
                <caldate>20020912</caldate>
              </sngdate>
            </mdattim>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccontr>Raw data used in land cover spectral signature analysis.</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Landsat 7</origin>
            <pubdate>20021001</pubdate>
            <title>LANDSAT TM Path 18, Row(s) 31</title>
            <geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Sioux Falls, South Dakota, USA</pubplace>
              <publish>USGS EROS Data Center</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>
LANDSAT TM Path 18, Row(s) 31. 30 meter by 30 meter pixel resolution, EOSAT Fast Format.
Additional information about Landsat 5 and Landsat 7 satellite imagery can be obtained from the United States Geological Survey (USGS) EROS Data Center.
</othercit>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>100000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>DVD</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <mdattim>
              <sngdate>
                <caldate>20020522</caldate>
              </sngdate>
              <sngdate>
                <caldate>20020810</caldate>
              </sngdate>
            </mdattim>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccontr>Raw data used in land cover spectral signature analysis.</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>National Aerial Photography Program (NAPP)</origin>
            <pubdate>variable</pubdate>
            <title>NAPP aerial photographs</title>
            <geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Salt Lake City, Utah, USA</pubplace>
              <publish>Aerial Photography Field Office (AFPO)</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>Additional information about NAPP can be obtained from the following internet site: http://edc.usgs.gov/glis/hyper/guide/napp</othercit>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>8000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>paper</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>variable</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccontr>spatial and attribute information</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>USDA-NASS, Research and Development Division, Area Frame Section</origin>
            <pubdate>1995</pubdate>
            <title>Area Sampling Frame (ASF) of New York</title>
            <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Washington D.C., USA</pubplace>
              <publish>USDA-NASS</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>Additional information about the NASS Area Frame Stratification can be obtained from the following internet site: http://www.nass.usda.gov/research/stratafront2b.htm</othercit>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>100000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>online</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>1995</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccontr>spatial and attribute information</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The Cropland Data Layer (CDL) Program provides the National Agricultural Statistics Service (NASS) with internal proprietary county and state level acreage indications of major crop commodities, and secondarily provides the public with "statewide" (where available) raster, geo-referenced, categorized land cover data products after the public release of county estimates. This project builds upon the USDA's National Agricultural Statistics Service (NASS) traditional crop acreage estimation program, and integrates the enumerator collected ground survey data with satellite imagery to create an unbiased statistical estimator of crop area at the state and county level for internal use. No farmer reported data is revealed, nor can it be derived in the publicly releasable Cropland Data Layer product.
Every June thousands of farms are visited by enumerators as part of the USDA-NASS June Agricultural Survey (JAS). These farmers are asked to report the acreage, by crop, that has been planted or that they intend to plant, and the acreage they expect to harvest. Approximately 11,000 area segments are selected nationwide for the JAS. The segment size can range in size from about 1 square mile in cultivated areas to 0.1 of a square mile in urban areas, to 2-4 square miles for larger probability proportional to size (PPS) segments in rangeland areas. This division allows intensively cultivated land segments to be selected with a greater frequency than those in less intensively cultivated areas. The 150-400 square miles of ground truth collected during the JAS provides a great ground truth training set annually.
In addition to the JAS segments, the 2002 growing season had extra segments associated with the 2002 Census of Agriculture. More information on the Census of Agricultre can be found at http://www.nass.usda.gov/census/census02/volume1/us/us2appxc.pdf. The Census segments, called Agricultural Coverage Evaluation Survey (ACES) segments, were designed to increase the coverage of different land use stratum and smaller acreage crop covers.
The Area Sampling Frame (ASF) is a stratification of each state into broad land use categories according to the percentage of cropland present. The ASF is stratified using visual interpretation of satellite imagery. The sampling frames are constructed by defining blocks of land whose boundaries are physical features on the ground (roads, railroads, rivers, etc). These blocks of land cover the entire state, do not overlap, and are placed in strata based on the percent of land in the block that is cultivated. The strata allow for efficient sampling of the land, as an agriculturally intensive area will be more heavily sampled than a non ag intensive area.
The enumerators draw off field boundaries onto NAPP 1:8,000 black and white aerial photos containing the segment, according to their observations and the farmer reported information. The fields are labeled and the cover type is recorded using a grease pencil on the aerial photo. Enumerators account for every field/land use type within a segment. They assign each field a cover type based upon a fixed set of land use classes for each state. Every field within a segment must fit into one of the pre-defined classes.
The program methodology is a continuous process throughout the year.  The first step "Segment Preparation" establishes the training segments, digitizes the perimeters, and distributes software and data to the field offices, this goes from February to late May. Segment digitizing begins during the JAS and continues until all fields and all segments are completely digitized, this may run thru July or even until mid-October in some states depending on human resource availability. Segment cleanup analyzes the newly digitized segments with the new acquired imagery. Fields that are bad either by digitizing or cover type are corrected or removed from training. Scene processing fits each segment onto a scene by shifting, and cloud-influenced segments are removed. The cluster/classification process runs in concert with the scene processing steps, as segments are shifted they can be clustered. This process is iterative, and can run into December. Estimation can be performed once a scene is finished classification, and the user is satisfied with the outputs. Estimation can begin as early as late October and run into late January/February. The mosaic process runs once estimation is completed. It is also iterative and can go from late December to March. The mosaic for a particular state is released once the county estimates are officially released for that state.
Scene selection begins in early summer, and could run into the late fall depending on image availability. The Cropland Data Layer program primarily uses the Landsat platform for acreage estimation. However, other platforms such as Spot and the Indian IRS platforms are used to fill "data acquisition" holes within a state. A spring and summer date of observation is preferred for maximum crop cover separation for multi-temporal analysis of summer crops. If only one date of observation is available (unitemporal), a mid summer date is preferred. If only an early spring date March-May or a fall date September-October is available (unitemporal) during the growing season, then it is best to not use that scene or analysis district for estimation, as bare soil in the spring and fully senesced crops in the fall will provide erroneous results.
The clustering/classification is an iterative process, as fields get misclassified, they can be fixed or marked as bad for training and reprocessed. Known pixels are separated by cover type and clustered, within cover type using a modified ISODATA clustering algorithm, as it allows for merging and splitting of clusters. Modified implies that the output clusters are not labeled (other than as coming from the input cover type) as they can be reassigned later if desired. Clustering is done separately for each cover type (or specified combination of cover types, such as all small grains). The clustered cover types are then assembled together into one signature file, where entire scenes are classified using the maximum likelihood algorithm. Clustering is based on the LARSYS (Purdue University) ISODATA algorithm. It performs an iterative process to divide pixels into groups based on minimum variance. The pairs of clusters in close proximity (based on Swain-Fu distance) are merged. High variance clusters can be split into two clusters (variance of first principal component is used as a measure). The output of any clustering program is a statistics file that stores mean vectors and covariance matrices of final set of clusters.
The outputs are a categorized or classified image in PEDITOR format and the associated accuracy statistics for each cover type. The maximum likelihood classifier performs a pixel-by-pixel classification based on the final, combined statistics file. It calculates the probability of each pixel being from each signature; then classifies a pixel to the category with highest probability. The processing time depends on size of file to be classified (i.e. number of pixels), number of categories in the statistics file and number of input dimensions (number of bands/pixel).
For estimation purposes, clouds can be minimized by defining Analysis Districts (AD) along adjacent scene edges, by cutting the Analysis Districts by county boundary, or cutting the clouds out by primary sampling units. Analysis Districts can be individual or multiple scenes footprints that have to be observed on the same date, and analyzed as one. An AD can be comprised of one or more scenes. An AD can be defined by either a scene edge or a county boundary. Multi-temporal AD's are possible as long as both dates in all scenes are the same. A single or multi-scene AD will use all potential training fields for clustering/classification/estimation.  Several factors can lead to problems in a classification, some get corrected in early edits and some do not:
Several factors can lead to problems in a classification, some get corrected in early edits and some do not: poor imagery dates, with respect to the major crops of interest, complete training fields that are incorrectly identified in the ground truth, parts of training fields that are not the same as the major crop or cover type, irrigation ditches, wooded areas, low spots filled with water, and/or bare soil areas in an otherwise vegetated field. Crops that look alike to the clustering algorithm(s) due to planting/growing cycle: spring wheat and barley at almost any time, crops in senescence, and grassy waste fields and idle cropland. Cover types that are essentially the same but used differently: wooded pasture versus woods or waste fields (only difference may be the presence of livestock), corn for grain versus corn silage, and cover crops such as rye and oats. Cover types that change signatures back and forth during the growing season: alfalfa and other hays before and after cutting, with multiple cuttings per year. Once the analyst is satisfied with the classification, the next step can be acreage estimation or image mosaicking.
Three estimation methods are available for each AD: regression, pixel ratio and direct expansion. Where available, regression is chosen as the preferred type of estimation. This approach essentially corrects the area sample (ground only) estimate based on the relationship found between reported data and classified pixels in each stratum where it is used. A regression relationship should be based on 10 or more segments for any stratum used. Where there are not enough segments in each stratum, a pixel based ratio estimator may be used which essentially combines data across stratum to get the relationship. Finally, the direct expansion (total number of possible segments times the average for sampled segment) may be used in the absence of pixel based methods. Regression adjusts the direct expansion estimate based on pixel information. It usually leads to an estimate with a much lower variance than direct expansion alone. Segments, called outliers, which do not fit the linear relationship estimated by the regression are reviewed; if errors are found, they are corrected or that segment may be removed from consideration in the analysis.
Full scene classifications (large scale) are run wherever the regression or pixel ratio estimates are usable. Estimates derived from the classification are compared to the ground data to make one final check. State estimates are made by summing pixel based estimators where available and ground data only estimators everywhere else. County estimates are then derived from the state estimates using a similar approach. Final numbers are delivered to state field offices and the NASS Agricultural Statistics Board for their use in setting the official final estimates. The states also have administrative data, such as FSA certified acres at the county level, and other NASS survey data.  Every 5th year, NASS also performs the Census of Agriculture at the county level.
The Landsat TM/ETM+ scenes that SARS uses are radiometrically and systematically corrected. There is a need to tie down registration points on a continuing basis for every state in the project. Without some image/image registration, the scene registration tends to float 2-3 pixels in any given direction, for any given scene. Manual registration for every scene of every project, would be nearly impossible, as the CDL is on a repeating production cycle every year, and human resource levels for this process are low. Image recoding is necessary between different analysis districts, to rectify to a common signatures set for a state. Clouds pose a problem when trying to make acreage estimates, and there are mechanisms within Peditor to minimize their extent, as there are ways to minimize cloud coverage in the mosaic process by prioritizing scene overlap.
Each categorized scene is co-registered to EarthSat's GeoCover LC imagery (50 meters RMS), and then stitched together using Peditor's Batch program. A block correlation is run between band two from each raw scene, and band two of the ortho-base image. The registration of the GeoCover mosaicked scene and the individual raw input scenes are used to get an approximate correspondence. A correlation procedure is used on the raw Landsat scenes and the mosaicked scene to get an exact mapping of each pixel from the input Landsat scenes to the mosaicked scene. The results of the correlation are used to remap the pixels from the individual input scenes into the coordinate system of the mosaicked scene.  The mosaic process now performs: 1) Precision registration of images automatically, 2) Converts each categorized image and associated statistics file to a set standard automatically (recode), 3) Specify overlap priority by scene or county, 4) Filters out clouds when possible. The scenes are stitched together using the priorities previously assigned from the scene observation dates/analysis districts map. Scenes/analysis districts with better quality observation dates are assigned a higher priority when stitching the images together. Clouds are assigned a null value on all scenes, and scenes of lower priority that are cloud free, take precedence over clouded higher priority images. Once cloud cover is established throughout the mosaic the clouds are assigned a digital value.
The Cropland Data Layer DVD products contain two years (if available) of imagery in a GEOTIFF image file format. In order to maximize the visual contrast between different crops in various states, colors that provide the best contrast for the crop mix in a particular State are chosen. However, the digital values for each category within every State remain the same. So corn in ND will have the same digital number as corn in AR. See mastercat.htm on the CDL DVD in the statinfo directory for a full listing by cover type.
All CDL distribution for the previous crop year is held until the release of the official NASS county estimates for the major commodities grown within a given state. Corn and Soybeans are released in March for the previous crop year - Midwestern States. Rice and Cotton are released in June for the previous crop year - Delta States. Small grains are released in March for the Great Plains States.
NASS publishes all available accuracy statistics for end-user viewing. The Percent Correct is calculated for each cover type in the ground truth, it shows how many of the total pixels were correctly classified (i.e. across all cover types). 'Commission Error' is the calculated percentage of all pixels categorized to a specific cover type that were not of that cover type in the ground truth (i.e. incorrectly categorized). CAUTION: a quoted Percent Correct for a specific cover type is worthless unless accompanied by its respective Commission Error. Example: if you classify every pixel in a scene to 'wheat', then you have a 100% correct wheat classifier (however its Commission Error is also almost 100%). The 'Kappa Statistic' is an attempt to adjust the Percent Correct using information gained from the confusion matrix for that cover type. Many remote sensing groups use the Percent Correct and/or Kappa statistics as their final measure of classification accuracy.
The NASS CDL Program is continuing efforts to reduce end-user burden, increase functionality, and take advantage of enhancements in computer technology. The Cropland Data Layer Program is a one of a kind agricultural inventory program, where every state participating in the program is re-surveyed (i.e., ground truthed) every June, and thus re-categorized. The data on the DVD is in the public domain, and you are free to do with it as you choose.  NASS would appreciate acknowledgment or credit regarding the source of the categorized images in any uses that you may have.
It is important to note that in no case is farmer reported data revealed or derivable from the public use Cropland Data Layer DVD's.
</procdesc>
        <procdate>20051031</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>USDA-NASS Spatial Analysis Research Section</cntorg>
              <cntper>USDA-NASS Spatial Analysis Research Section staff</cntper>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>
              <address>3251 Old Lee Highway, Rm 305</address>
              <city>Fairfax</city>
              <state>Virginia</state>
              <postal>22030-1504</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>703/877-8000</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>703/877-8044</cntfax>
            <cntemail>HQ_RD_OD@nass.usda.gov</cntemail>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
    <cloud>Reference the DVD for cloud coverage information.</cloud>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
        <direct>Raster</direct>
        <rastinfo>
          <rasttype>Grid Cell</rasttype>
          <rowcount>16747</rowcount>
          <colcount>21952</colcount>
        </rastinfo>
      </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <gridsys>
          <gridsysn>Universal Transverse Mercator</gridsysn>
          <utm>
            <utmzone>18</utmzone>
            <transmer>
              <sfctrmer>0.9996</sfctrmer>
              <longcm>-75</longcm>
              <latprjo>0</latprjo>
              <feast>500000</feast>
              <fnorth>0</fnorth>
            </transmer>
          </utm>
        </gridsys>
        <planci>
          <plance>row and column</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>30</absres>
            <ordres>30</ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>meters</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>WGS84</horizdn>
        <ellips>WGS84</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.00</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <overview>
      <eaover>NASS collects the remote sensing Acreage Estimation Program's field level training data during the June Agricultural Survey. This is a national survey based on a stratified random sample of land areas selected from each state's area frame. An area frame is a land use stratification based on percent cultivation. The selected areas are targeted toward cultivated parts of each state based on its area frame.  Our enumerators are given questionnaires to ask the farmers what, where, when and how much are they planting.  Our surveys focus on cropland, but the enumerators record all land covers within the sampled area of land whether it is cropland or not.  NASS uses broad land use categories to define land that is not under cultivation, including; non-agricultural, pasture/rangeland, waste, woods, and farmstead. NASS defines these non-agricultural land use types very broadly, which makes it difficult to precisely know what specific type of land use/cover actually is on the ground.  For instance, there is no breakdown as to the type of woods in a given field/pasture, that's where the power of a GIS could be useful.  If a external forestry GIS layer was overlaid, the land use can be accurately identified, and the specific cover type can be derived from the data layer. SARS is currently looking at creating extra categories for the enumerators to better identify non-cropland features, thereby, increasing the accuracy and improving the appearance of the classification.</eaover>
      <eadetcit>
Data Dictionary: USDA - NATIONAL AGRICULTURE STATISTICS SERVICE'S 1:100,000-SCALE 2002 CROPLAND DATA LAYER, A Crop-Specific Digital Data Layer for New York, 2006 January 01
&gt;
&gt; Source: USDA - National Agriculture Statistics Service
&gt;
&gt; The following is a cross reference list of the categorization codes and
&gt; land covers used in all states. Note that not all land cover
&gt; categories listed below will appear in an individual state. Refer
&gt; to the "Cover Type Signatures List" on the DVD for the state specific
&gt; assignment of colors to cover type.
&gt;
&gt; Raster
&gt; Attribute Domain Values and Definitions: ROW CROPS 1-20
&gt;
&gt; Categorization Code   Land Cover
&gt;         "1"           Corn
&gt;         "2"           Cotton
&gt;         "3"           Rice
&gt;         "4"           Sorghum
&gt;         "5"           Soybeans
&gt;         "6"           Sunflowers
&gt;         "10"          Peanuts
&gt;         "11"          Tobacco
&gt;
&gt; Raster
&gt; Attribute Domain Values and Definitions: SMALL GRAINS, HAY AND SEEDS 21-40
&gt;
&gt; Categorization Code   Land Cover
&gt;         "21"          Barley
&gt;         "22"          Durum Wheat
&gt;         "23"          Spring Wheat
&gt;         "24"          Winter Wheat (AR,IL,MS,NM)
&gt;         "25"          Other Small Grains &amp; Hay (Oats, Millet, Rye
&gt;                       &amp; Winter Wheat, Alfalfa &amp; Other Hay)
&gt;         "26"          Winter Wheat/Soybeans Double Cropped
&gt;         "27"          Rye
&gt;         "28"          Oats
&gt;         "29"          Millet
&gt;         "30"          Speltz
&gt;         "31"          Canola
&gt;         "32"          Flaxseed
&gt;         "33"          Safflower
&gt;         "34"          Rapeseed
&gt;         "35"          Mustard
&gt;         "36"          Alfalfa
&gt;
&gt; Raster
&gt; Attribute Domain Values and Definitions: OTHER CROPS 41-60
&gt;
&gt; Categorization Code   Land Cover
&gt;         "41"          Beets
&gt;         "42"          Dry Edible Beans
&gt;         "43"          Potatoes
&gt;         "44"          Other Crops (Canola, Flaxseed, Safflower
&gt;                       &amp; very small acreage crops)
&gt;         "45"          Sugar Cane
&gt;         "46"          Sweet Potatoes
&gt;         "47"          Misc. Fruit and Veg
&gt;         "48"          Watermelon
&gt;         "50"          State 560 (State-specific crop, see DVD for details)
&gt;         "51"          State 561 (State-specific crop, see DVD for details)
&gt;         "52"          State 562 (State-specific crop, see DVD for details)
&gt;         "53"          State 563 (State-specific crop, see DVD for details)
&gt;         "54"          State 564 (State-specific crop, see DVD for details)
&gt;         "55"          State 565 (State-specific crop, see DVD for details)
&gt;         "56"          State 566 (State-specific crop, see DVD for details)
&gt;         "57"          State 567 (State-specific crop, see DVD for details)
&gt;         "58"          State 568 (State-specific crop, see DVD for details)
&gt;         "59"          State 569 (State-specific crop, see DVD for details)
&gt;
&gt; Raster
&gt; Attribute Domain Values and Definitions: FARMLAND USES 61-65
&gt;
&gt; Categorization Code   Land Cover
&gt;         "61"          Fallow/Idle Cropland
&gt;         "62"          Pasture/Range/CRP/Non Ag (Permanent &amp;
&gt;                       Cropland Pasture, Waste &amp; Farmstead)
&gt;         "63"          Woods, Woodland Pasture
&gt;
&gt; Raster
&gt; Attribute Domain Values and Definitions: TREE CROPS 66-80
&gt;
&gt; Categorization Code   Land Cover
&gt;         "67"          Peaches
&gt;         "68"          Apples
&gt;         "69"          Grapes
&gt;         "70"          Christmas Trees
&gt;         "71"          Orchards, State 721-729 (State-specific orchards,
&gt;                       see DVD for details),Cottonwood Tree
&gt;         "80"          Other Fruit
&gt;
&gt; Raster
&gt; Attribute Domain Values and Definitions: OTHER LAND 81-99
&gt;
&gt; Categorization Code   Land Cover
&gt;         "81"          Clouds
&gt;         "82"          Urban
&gt;         "83"          Water
&gt;         "84"          Roads/Railroads
&gt;         "85"          Ditches/Waterways
&gt;         "86"          Buildings/Homes/Subdivisions
&gt;         "87"          Wetlands
&gt;         "88"          Grassland
&gt;         "90"          Mixed Water/Crops
&gt;         "91"          Mixed Water/Clouds
&gt;         "92"          Aquaculture
&gt;
&gt; Raster
&gt; Attribute Domain Values and Definitions: OTHER CROPS 100-120
&gt;
&gt; Categorization Code   Land Cover
&gt;         "100"          Pickles
&gt;         "101"          Chick Peas
&gt;         "102"          Lentils
&gt;         "103"          Peas
&gt;
</eadetcit>
    </overview>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
        <distrib>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>Albert R. Mann Library</cntorg>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
              <address>Cornell University</address>
              <city>Ithaca</city>
              <state>New York</state>
              <postal>14853</postal>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>607-255-5406</cntvoice>
            <cntemail>mann-ref@cornell.edu</cntemail>
          </cntinfo>
        </distrib>
        <distliab>Cornell University provides these geographic data "as is". Cornell
          University makes no guarantee or warranty concerning the accuracy of
          information contained in the geographic data. Cornell University further
          makes no warranty either expressed or implied, regarding the condition of
          the product or its fitness for any particular purpose. The burden for
          determining fitness for use lies entirely with the user. Although these
          files have been processed successfully on computers at Cornell University,
          no warranty is made by Cornell University regarding the use of these data
          on any other system, nor does the fact of distribution constitute or imply
          any such warranty.</distliab>
        <stdorder>
        <digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>GeoTIFF</formname>
              <formcont>zipped geotiff</formcont>
              <filedec>zip</filedec>
              <transize>31.01</transize>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/80/27/cugir-008027.zip</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>metadata</formname>
              <formcont>FGDC XML metadata</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/80/27/fgdc.xml</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>HTML metadata</formname>
              <formcont>FGDC HTML metadata</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/80/27/fgdc.html</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>OGC:WMS</formname>
              <formcont>WMS, from GeoServer</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir.library.cornell.edu/geoserver/cugir/wms?version=1.1.0&amp;request=GetMap&amp;layers=cugir008027&amp;bbox=-80.24707998000001,40.266394229999996,-71.39972001999999,45.161536770000005&amp;width=256&amp;height=141&amp;srs=EPSG:4326&amp;format=image/png</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><fees>None</fees></stdorder>
      </distinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>USDA-NASS Customer Service</cntorg>
          <cntper>USDA-NASS Customer Service</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>
          <address>1400 Independence Avenue, SW, Room 5829-S</address>
          <city/>
          <state>Washington DC</state>
          <postal>20250-9410</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>1-800-727-9540</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>703/877-8044</cntfax>
        <cntinst>To order a DVD (see prices as noted at http://www.nass.usda.gov/research/Cropland/SARS1a.htm) please fill out the order form and submit it either electronically (invoice will follow with the DVD and/or DVD(s)) or mail the completed form with your check to: USDA-NASS Customer Service, 1400 Independence Avenue, SW, Room 5829-S, Washington DC 20250-9410. Please note "Cropland Data Layer - (State and Year)" in the "Memo" part of your check. Checks should be made out to "USDA-NASS". Allow 1 week for delivery.</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <resdesc>NASS Cropland Data Layer, New York 2002</resdesc>
    <distliab>
Disclaimer:
Users of our Cropland Data Layer (CDL) and associated raster and vector data files are solely responsible for interpretations made from these products. The CDL is provided "as is".  USDA-NASS does not warrant results you may obtain by using the Cropland Data Layer. Feel free to contact our staff at (HQ_RD_OD@nass.usda.gov) if technical questions arise in the use of our Cropland Data Layer. NASS does provide considerable metadata on the CDL in the Frequently Asked Questions (FAQ's) section on this CDL website, and on the ordered DVD's. Also, there are substantial statistical performance measures by Analysis District within a State on the Landsat data categorization accuracies for each DVD for each year.
</distliab>
    <stdorder>
      <digform>
        <digtinfo>
          <formname>GEOTIFF</formname>
          <formverd>2002</formverd>
          <formcont>GEOTIFF</formcont>
          <transize>
One DVD contains two concurrent years (where available) of Cropland Data Layer classifications for a single state.
The image file size will vary depending on the state and completeness of coverage. Generally, the New York GEOTIFF image file is approximately 390 megabits and may be zipped depending on the available DVD disk space.
</transize>
        </digtinfo>
        <digtopt>
          <offoptn>
            <offmedia>DVD</offmedia>
            <reccap>
              <recden>Uncompressed file size for the New York Cropland Data Layer is approximately 390 MB.</recden>
              <recdenu>MB</recdenu>
            </reccap>
            <recfmt>DOS-COPY</recfmt>
          </offoptn>
        </digtopt>
      </digform>
      <fees>The USDA-NASS charges a nominal fee to cover the cost of DVD production and shipping costs. Please visit http://www.nass.usda.gov/research/Cropland/SARS1a.htm for prices. Distribution issues can also be directed to the NASS Customer Service Hotline at 1-800-727-9540.</fees>
      <ordering>To order a DVD (see prices as noted at http://www.nass.usda.gov/research/Cropland/SARS1a.htm) please fill out the order form and submit it either electronically (invoice will follow with the DVD(s)) or mail the completed form with your check to: USDA-NASS Customer Service, 1400 Independence Avenue, SW, Room 5829-S, Washington DC 20250-9410. Please note "Cropland Data Layer - (State and Year)" in the "Memo" part of your check. Checks should be made out to "USDA-NASS". Allow 1 week for delivery. Distribution issues can also be directed to the NASS Customer Service Hotline at 1-800-727-9540.</ordering>
      <turnarnd>Allow 1 week for delivery.</turnarnd>
    </stdorder>
    <custom>
For a list of other states and years of data please visit: http://www.nass.usda.gov/research/Cropland/SARS1a.htm.
Distribution issues can also be directed to the NASS Customer Service Hotline at 1-800-727-9540.
</custom>
    <techpreq>There are no technical prerequisites requiring special software or hardware to view the data distributed on the DVD. A freeware browser, ArcExplorer (Environmental Systems Research Institute, Redlands, CA), is bundled onto the DVD, allowing for users without a GIS or image processing software package to be able to view the products.</techpreq>
    <availabl>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>20060101</begdate>
          <enddate>Unknown</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
    </availabl>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
      <metd>20190604</metd>
      <metc>
        <cntinfo>
          <cntorgp>
            <cntorg>Albert R. Mann Library</cntorg>
          </cntorgp>
          <cntaddr>
            <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
            <address>Albert R. Mann Library</address>
            <city>Ithaca</city>
            <state>New York</state>
            <postal>14853</postal>
            <country>USA</country>
          </cntaddr>
          <cntvoice>607-255-5406</cntvoice>
          <cntemail>mann-ref@cornell.edu</cntemail>
        </cntinfo>
      </metc>
      <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
      <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
      <mettc>local time</mettc>
    </metainfo>
</metadata>
