<!DOCTYPE metadata SYSTEM "http://fgdc.gov/metadata/fgdc-std-001-1998.dtd">
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Lamont-Doherty Earth Observatory (LDEO)</origin>
        <pubdate>2005</pubdate>
        <title>Sedimentary Environment, Hudson River estuary, 2004</title>
        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
        <onlink>https://cugir.library.cornell.edu/catalog/cugir-007885</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>This dataset provides sedimentary environments of the Hudson
        River Estuary from Verrazano Narrows Bridge to Troy. Areas of the Hudson
        River shallower than 4 meters have not been surveyed and sampled
        completely. The sedimentary environment interpretation is based on the
        evaluation of Chirp sub-bottom acoustic profiler data in conjunction
        with acoustic backscatter and bathymetry data. It is subdivided into
        depositional, erosional, and dynamic classes that are further
        subdivided, depending on the details identified in the sub-bottom data,
        or because of their location. A more complete description of this
        interpretation can be found in Nitsche et al. (2004) and Nitsche et al.
        (2005)</abstract>
      <purpose>In 1996, the New York State Department of Environmental
        Conservation (DEC) initiated an effort to map the benthic habitat of the
        Hudson River Estuary as part of a larger Hudson River Action Plan. This
        project includes extensive mapping using sidescan sonar, sub-bottom
        profiling, single and multi-beam bathymetric sonars, as well as
        collecting ground truth data with sediment cores, grab samples, and
        sediment profiling imagery (SPI). The goal of the project is the
        creation of a comprehensive data set that includes detailed interpretive
        maps of the physical environment of the floor of the estuary.  An
        overview of the first phase of the benthic mapping project can be found
        in Bell et al. (2006)</purpose>
      <supplinf>See also &lt;http://benthic.info&gt; More extensive
        discussion of the methods and interpretation can be found in the
        following publications: Bell, R.E., et al., 2006. "Benthic habitat
        mapping in the Hudson River Estuary", in The Hudson River Estuary
        (Levinton and Waldman, eds.), Cambridge Univ Press., pp. 51-64. //
        Carbotte, S.M., et al., 2004. Environmental change and oyster
        colonization within the Hudson River estuary linked to Holocene climate.
        Geo-Marine Letters 24: 212-224. // McHugh, C.M.G., et al., 2004. Spatial
        variations in a condensed interval between estuarine and open marine
        settings: Holocene Hudson River Estuary and adjacent continental shelf.
        Geology 32(2): 169-172. // Nitsche, F.O., et al., 2004. Process-related
        classification of acoustic data from the Hudson River Estuary. Marine
        Geology 209(1-4): 131-145. // Nitsche, F.O. et. al., 2005. Integrative
        acoustic mapping reveals Hudson River sediment processes and habitats.
        EOS 86(24): 225. // Nitsche, F.O. et al., 2005. "A seabed classification
        approach based on multiple acoustic sensors in the Hudson River
        Estuary", in High Resolution Morphodynamics and Sedimentary Evolution of
        Estuaries (FitzGerald and Knight, eds.), Springer, pp. 33-55. // Pekar,
        S.F., et al., 2004. Estuarine processes and their stratigraphic record:
        paleosalinity and sedimentation changes in the Hudson Estuary (North
        America). Marine Geology 209(1-4): 113-129. // Strayer, D.L., et al.,
        2006. Using geophysical information to define benthic habitats in a
        large river. Freshwater Biology 51: 25-38.</supplinf>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>1998</begdate>
          <enddate>2004</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>ground condition</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
          <bounding>
            <westbc>-74.10704</westbc>
            <eastbc>-73.685001</eastbc>
            <northbc>42.751991</northbc>
            <southbc>40.602704</southbc>
          </bounding>
        </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>estuary</themekey>
        <themekey>sediments</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
        <themekey>geology</themekey>
        <themekey>environment</themekey>
        <themekey>inlandWaters</themekey>
        <themekey>oceans</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
              <themekt>CUGIR Category</themekt>
              <themekey>environment</themekey>
<themekey>inland waters</themekey>
<themekey>oceans</themekey>
            </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>LCSH</placekt>
        <placekey>Hudson River (N.Y. and N.J.)</placekey>
        <placekey>Hudson River Estuary (N.Y. and N.J.)</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>none</accconst>
    <useconst>none</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>John Ladd</cntper>
          <cntorg> Hudson River National Estuarine Research Reserve, Hudson
            River Estuary Program, New York State Department of Environmental
            Conservation </cntorg>
        </cntperp>
        <cntpos>Benthic Mapping Coordinator</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
          <address>Bard College Field Station</address>
          <city>Annandale</city>
          <state>New York</state>
          <postal>12504</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>845-758-7010</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>jxladd@gw.dec.state.ny.us</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <browse>
              <browsen>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/78/85/preview.png</browsen>
              <browsed>preview of the dataset</browsed>
              <browset>PNG</browset>
            </browse>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>All sediment grab samples were positioned using Differential GPS
        (DGPS), with accuracy within 1 meter. The polygon borders are based on
        the samples (spaced an average of 0.5 km apart) and the sidescan sonar
        data. The sediment type polygons represent the general trend, but local
        misinterpretations are possible.</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <logic>No information provided.</logic>
    <complete>The data cover the Hudson River Estuary from the Verrazano-Narrows
      Bridge to Troy, with the exception of some areas shallower than 4m, which
      have not been surveyed and sampled completely.</complete>
    <lineage>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Processed bathymetry, sidescan sonar, and sub-bottom tracks
          were loaded into ArcGIS. Polygons were drawn manually in ArcGIS around
          the areas with distinct different characteristics and each polygon was
          assigned a certain type based on its character. The sedimentary
          environment interpretation was based on the evaluation of the Chirp
          data in conjunction with the backscatter and bathymetry data. We
          distinguish the following classes: 1) Depositional environments are
          identified as regions with low backscatter that ideally can be seen
          overlying other strata. A clear example of a depositional environment
          is the site off Hook Mountain (A1) where Cesium measurements have
          confirmed the interpretation of recent sedimentation. This also
          includes the high backscatter deposits associated with tributary
          mouths (A2, A3). We have developed 4 distinct subclasses. 2)
          Erosional/Non-depositional environments are defined as sites with
          clearly truncated bedding in the Chirp data, outcrops of bedrock as in
          the Hudson Highlands or where other information, stratigraphic or
          radionuclides indicate non-depositional. We have developed 3 distinct
          erosional/non-depositional subclasses. 3) The identification of
          dynamic environments is based on the morphology and the backscatter
          data. Within the dynamic regions it is possible that both erosional
          and depositional processes are active. A clear example of a dynamic
          environment is the sediment waves/dunes prominent in the upper reaches
          of the Hudson River Estuary. As these features migrate both deposition
          and erosion are active. We have identified several major subclasses
          for the dynamic environment.</procdesc>
        <procdate>Unknown</procdate>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
        <direct>Vector</direct>
        <ptvctinf>
          <sdtsterm>
            <sdtstype>G-polygon</sdtstype>
            <ptvctcnt>15</ptvctcnt>
          </sdtsterm>
        </ptvctinf>
      </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <gridsys>
          <gridsysn>Universal Transverse Mercator</gridsysn>
          <utm>
            <utmzone>18</utmzone>
            <transmer>
              <sfctrmer>0.999600</sfctrmer>
              <longcm>-75.000000</longcm>
              <latprjo>0.000000</latprjo>
              <feast>500000.000000</feast>
              <fnorth>0.000000</fnorth>
            </transmer>
          </utm>
        </gridsys>
        <planci>
          <plance>coordinate pair</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>0.000512</absres>
            <ordres>0.000512</ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>meters</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257222</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>Sedimentary environment</enttypl>
        <enttypd>Region have a particular sedimentary environment, based on
          interpretation of sidescan sonar, bathymetry, and sub-bottom data.</enttypd>
        <enttypds>LDEO</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>type</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Sedimentary environment type based on interpretation of
          sidescan sonar, bathymetry, and sub-bottom data</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>LDEO</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Deposition - thin</edomv>
            <edomvd>Low backscatter; Sub-bottom data shows thin (&lt;50 cm)
              usually transparent layer of sediment accumulation</edomvd>
            <edomvds>LDEO</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Deposition - thick</edomv>
            <edomvd>Low backscatter; Sub-bottom data shows thick (&gt;50 cm)
              usually transparent layer of sediment accumulation</edomvd>
            <edomvds>LDEO</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Deposition - over bedrock</edomv>
            <edomvd>Low backscatter; Sub-bottom data indicate bedrock underneath
              thin drape</edomvd>
            <edomvds>LDEO</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Deposition - unres. thickness</edomv>
            <edomvd>Low backscatter; Sub-bottom data are not available or not
              clear enough to identify thickness of layer</edomvd>
            <edomvds>LDEO</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Erosional - truncated</edomv>
            <edomvd>Sub-bottom data show indication of truncated stratigraphy
              outcropping on the river bottom. This class can only be identified
              where good sub-bottom data are available.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>LDEO</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Erosional - bedrock</edomv>
            <edomvd>Multibeam bathymetry and sidescan data show bedrock
              outcropping at the surface. In general, no sub-bottom penetration.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>LDEO</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Erosional - non-deposition</edomv>
            <edomvd>Moderate to high backscatter; multibeam may show smooth or
              rough surface. Sub-bottom does not show any indication of recent
              drape or truncated reflections. Applies to areas where there is no
              clear indication of deposition or other dynamic classes. No 7Be
              radionuclides where analysis exists.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>LDEO</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Dynamic - waves</edomv>
            <edomvd>Regions with waves imaged with multibeam or sidescan</edomvd>
            <edomvds>LDEO</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Dynamic - scour</edomv>
            <edomvd>Typically located around obstacles such as bridge abutments.
              Moderate to high backscatter, rough surface in multibeam
              bathymetry. No penetration and/or rough surface in sub-bottom
              data.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>LDEO</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Dynamic - debris</edomv>
            <edomvd>Areas of complex morphology that includes small mounds of
              potential dumps or debris flow deposits. Often these areas show
              sign of scouring and sediment tails around individual features.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>LDEO</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Dynamic - lineation</edomv>
            <edomvd>These are bedforms that are parallel to the current in
              contrast to the waves/dunes, which are typically aligned
              perpendicular to the current. Examples of lineations with distinct
              topographic relief are found in the Highlands.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>LDEO</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Dynamic - drift</edomv>
            <edomvd>Regions characterized by deposition in the lee of obstacles.
              Often scour is also evident along the edges of obstacles so that
              regions of dynamic drift are characterized by both deposition and
              erosion.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>LDEO</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Dynamic - streaks</edomv>
            <edomvd>Features visible in the backscatter are aligned along the
              current but have not evident topographic relief. Examples of these
              features are associated with the Newburg Beacon Bridge (A2).</edomvd>
            <edomvds>LDEO</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Dynamic - slump</edomv>
            <edomvd>Features that are found a few times in the interpretation
              for example the slump structure along the edge of the channel
              adjacent to Catskill Creek, and the slide off of stony Point.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>LDEO</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Unsurveyed</edomv>
            <edomvd>These regions are not classified due to lack of data
              coverage. These are generally the shallow regions that were not
              surveyed.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>LDEO</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>AREA</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Area in square meters</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>LDEO</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>0</rdommin>
            <rdommax>unbounded</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
        <distrib>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>Albert R. Mann Library</cntorg>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
              <address>Cornell University</address>
              <city>Ithaca</city>
              <state>New York</state>
              <postal>14853</postal>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>607-255-5406</cntvoice>
            <cntemail>mann-ref@cornell.edu</cntemail>
          </cntinfo>
        </distrib>
        <distliab>Cornell University provides these geographic data "as is". Cornell
          University makes no guarantee or warranty concerning the accuracy of
          information contained in the geographic data. Cornell University further
          makes no warranty either expressed or implied, regarding the condition of
          the product or its fitness for any particular purpose. The burden for
          determining fitness for use lies entirely with the user. Although these
          files have been processed successfully on computers at Cornell University,
          no warranty is made by Cornell University regarding the use of these data
          on any other system, nor does the fact of distribution constitute or imply
          any such warranty.</distliab>
        <stdorder>
        <digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>Shapefile</formname>
              <formcont>zipped shapefile</formcont>
              <filedec>zip</filedec>
              <transize>1.43</transize>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/78/85/cugir-007885.zip</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>metadata</formname>
              <formcont>FGDC XML metadata</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/78/85/fgdc.xml</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>HTML metadata</formname>
              <formcont>FGDC HTML metadata</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/78/85/fgdc.html</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
                <digtinfo>
                  <formname>KML</formname>
                  <formcont>generated KML, via WFS</formcont>
                </digtinfo>
                <digtopt>
                  <onlinopt>
                    <computer>
                      <networka>
                        <networkr>https://cugir.library.cornell.edu/geoserver/cugir/wfs?version=1.0.0&amp;request=GetFeature&amp;typeName=cugir007885&amp;outputFormat=application%2Fvnd.google-earth.kml%2Bxml</networkr>
                      </networka>
                    </computer>
                  </onlinopt>
                </digtopt>
              </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>GeoJSON</formname>
              <formcont>generated GeoJSON, via WFS</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir.library.cornell.edu/geoserver/cugir/wfs?version=1.0.0&amp;request=GetFeature&amp;typeName=cugir007885&amp;outputFormat=application%2Fjson</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>OGC:WMS</formname>
              <formcont>WMS, from GeoServer</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir.library.cornell.edu/geoserver/cugir/wms?version=1.1.0&amp;request=GetMap&amp;layers=cugir007885&amp;bbox=-74.11970117,40.53822539,-73.67233983,42.81646961&amp;width=50&amp;height=256&amp;srs=EPSG:4326&amp;format=image/png</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><fees>None</fees></stdorder>
      </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
      <metd>20190524</metd>
      <metc>
        <cntinfo>
          <cntorgp>
            <cntorg>Albert R. Mann Library</cntorg>
          </cntorgp>
          <cntaddr>
            <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
            <address>Albert R. Mann Library</address>
            <city>Ithaca</city>
            <state>New York</state>
            <postal>14853</postal>
            <country>USA</country>
          </cntaddr>
          <cntvoice>607-255-5406</cntvoice>
          <cntemail>mann-ref@cornell.edu</cntemail>
        </cntinfo>
      </metc>
      <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
      <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
      <mettc>local time</mettc>
    </metainfo>
</metadata>
