<!DOCTYPE metadata SYSTEM "http://fgdc.gov/metadata/fgdc-std-001-1998.dtd">
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>U.S. Geological Survey</origin>
        <pubdate>2006</pubdate>
        <title>NLCD 1992/2001 Retrofit Land Cover Change, New York</title>
        <geoform>raster digital data</geoform>
        <serinfo>
          <sername>National Land Cover Database</sername>
          <issue>1992/2001 Retrofit Land Cover Change</issue>
        </serinfo>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Sioux Falls, SD</pubplace>
          <publish>U.S. Geological Survey</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <onlink>https://cugir.library.cornell.edu/catalog/cugir-008005</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>The National Land Cover Database 1992/2001 Change Product was produced through
                a cooperative project conducted by the Multi-Resolution Land Characteristics (MRLC)
                Consortium. The MRLC Consortium, a partnership of federal agencies (www.mrlc.gov),
                consists of the U.S. Geological Survey (USGS), the National Oceanic and Atmospheric
                Administration (NOAA), the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), the U.S.
                Department of Agriculture (USDA), the U.S. Forest Service (USFS), the National Park
                Service (NPS), the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service (FWS), the Bureau of Land
                Management (BLM) and the USDA Natural Resources Conservation Service (NRCS). The
                goal of the project is to generate a current, consistent, and seamless 1992/2001
                Land Cover Change Product for the United States at medium spatial resolution for
                Anderson Level 1 classes. This land cover change map and all documents pertaining to
                it are considered "provisional" until a formal accuracy assessment can be conducted.
                For detailed definitions and discussion of the NLCD 1992/2001 Change product, refer
                to &lt;http://www.mrlc.gov/&gt;. New developments in mapping methodology, new
                sources of input data, and minor differences between mapping legends in the 1992
                National Land Cover Database (NLCD 1992) and the 2001 National Land Cover Database
                (NLCD 2001) have compounded any direct comparisons. NLCD 2001 method improvements
                have resulted in an improved land cover product over NLCD 1992 in such areas as
                classification accuracy, spatial detail, database content, and multiple product
                flexibility. The result is that direct comparison of these two independently created
                land cover products is not recommended. The 1992/2001 NLCD Land Cover Change Product
                was developed to offer a more accurate and useful guide to change analysis than can
                be provided by direct comparison of NLCD 1992 with NLCD 2001. Users are cautioned
                that this product is designed to be the most accurate for applications at the
                mapping zone scale, and is not designed to be accurately applied over smaller
                sub-mapping zone areas. The NLCD 1992/2001 Change Product is partitioned in the U.S.
                into mapping zones. A total of 66 mapping zones were delineated within the
                conterminous U.S. based on ecoregion and geographical characteristics, edge matching
                features and the size requirement of Landsat mosaics. Zone 13 (the northeastern
                U.S.) consists of mapping zones 60, 61, 63, 64, 65, and 66, which collectively
                encompasses the entirety of Maine, New Hampshire, Vermont, Massachusetts, Rhode
                Island, Connecticut, New York, New Jersey, Delaware, and Maryland, as well as
                portions of Pennsylvania, West Virginia, Virginia, and North Carolina.</abstract>
      <purpose>The goal of this project is to provide the Nation with complete, current and
                consistent public domain information on land cover change.</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>1988</begdate>
          <enddate>2003</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>ground condition</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>In work</progress>
      <update>As needed</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
          <bounding>
            <westbc>-80.035679</westbc>
            <eastbc>-70.516586</eastbc>
            <northbc>45.847801</northbc>
            <southbc>40.086478</southbc>
          </bounding>
        </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>Land Cover</themekey>
        <themekey>Land Cover Change</themekey>
        <themekey>Change Detection</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
        <themekey>imageryBaseMapsEarthCover</themekey>
        <themekey>environment</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
              <themekt>CUGIR Category</themekt>
              <themekey>landcover</themekey>
<themekey>environment</themekey>
            </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>None</placekt>
        <placekey>New York</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>None</useconst>
    <browse>
              <browsen>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/80/05/preview.png</browsen>
              <browsed>preview of the dataset</browsed>
              <browset>PNG</browset>
            </browse>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>This land cover change map and all documents pertaining to it are considered
                "provisional" until a formal accuracy assessment can be conducted. For more
                information, see the metadata for individual mapping zones that is included in the
                data download.</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <logic>See the metadata for individual mapping zones that is included in the data
            download.</logic>
    <complete>See the metadata for individual mapping zones that is included in the data
            download.</complete>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>U.S. Geological Survey</origin>
            <pubdate>2006</pubdate>
            <title>NLCD 1992/2001 Retrofit Land Cover Change, Superzone 13</title>
            <onlink>https://www.mrlc.gov/changepair/area13_changeproduct.zip</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>online</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>1988</begdate>
              <enddate>2003</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>NLCD Retrofit 1992/2001 Land Cover Change</srccitea>
        <srccontr>original unclipped dataset</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>CUGIR staff clipped data to New York state boundary.</procdesc>
        <procdate>20170724</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>CUGIR staff assigned nodata value 0</procdesc>
        <procdate>20190523</procdate>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
        <direct>Raster</direct>
        <rastinfo>
          <rasttype>Grid Cell</rasttype>
          <rowcount>16989</rowcount>
          <colcount>22610</colcount>
        </rastinfo>
      </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <mapproj>
          <mapprojn>Albers Conical Equal Area</mapprojn>
          <albers>
            <stdparll>29.500000</stdparll>
            <stdparll>45.500000</stdparll>
            <longcm>-96.000000</longcm>
            <latprjo>23.000000</latprjo>
            <feast>0.000000</feast>
            <fnorth>0.000000</fnorth>
          </albers>
        </mapproj>
        <planci>
          <plance>row and column</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>30.000000</absres>
            <ordres>30.000000</ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>meters</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257222</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>nlcd_1992_2001_change_ny</enttypl>
        <enttypd>NLCD 1992/2001 Land Cover Change Layer</enttypd>
        <enttypds>National Land Cover Database 1992/2001 Change Product</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Value</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Land Cover Change Class Code Value.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>NLCD 2001</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>1</edomv>
            <edomvd>Modified Anderson Level I class code for Open Water - All areas of
                            open water, generally with less than 25% vegetation or soil cover.
                            Pixels coded to a value of 1 have not changed between 1992 and
                            2001.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>2</edomv>
            <edomvd>Modified Anderson Level I class code for Urban - Includes developed
                            open spaces with a mixture of some constructed materials, but mostly
                            vegetation in the form of lawn grasses such as large-lot single-family
                            housing units, parks, golf courses, and vegetation planted in developed
                            settings for recreation, erosion control, or aesthetic purposes. Also
                            includes developed, low, medium, and high intensity with a mixture of
                            constructed materials and vegetation, such as single-family housing
                            units and highly developed areas where people reside or work in large
                            numbers such as apartment complexes, row houses and
                            commercial/industrial areas. Pixels coded to a value of 2 have not
                            changed between 1992 and 2001.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>3</edomv>
            <edomvd>Modified Anderson Level I class code for Barren - Barren areas of
                            bedrock, desert pavement, scarps, talus, slides, volcanic material,
                            glacial debris, sand dunes, strip mines, gravel pits and other
                            accumulations of earthen material. Generally, vegetation accounts for
                            less than 15% of total cover. Pixels coded to a value of 3 have not
                            changed between 1992 and 2001.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>4</edomv>
            <edomvd>Modified Anderson Level 1 class code for Forest - Areas dominated by
                            trees generally greater than 5 meters tall, and greater than 20% of
                            total vegetation cover. Includes Deciduous Forest, Evergreen Forest and
                            Mixed Forest. Pixels coded to a value of 4 have not changed between 1992
                            and 2001.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>5</edomv>
            <edomvd>Modified Anderson Level 1 class code for Grassland/Shrub - Includes
                            grassland areas dominated by grammanoid or herbaceous vegetation and
                            shrub/scrub areas dominated by shrubs less than 5 meters tall with shrub
                            canopy typically greater than 20% of total vegetation, including true
                            shrubs, young trees in an early successional stage, or trees stunted due
                            to harsh environmental conditions. Management techniques which associate
                            soil, water, and forage-vegetation resources are more suitable for
                            rangeland management than are practices generally used in managing
                            pastureland. Some rangelands have been or may be seeded to introduced or
                            domesticated plant species. Includes those areas in the Eastern States
                            which commonly are called brushlands. Pixels coded to a value of 5 have
                            not changed between 1992 and 2001.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions and Anderson,
                            et al., 1976.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>6</edomv>
            <edomvd>Modified Anderson Level 1 class code for Agricultural Land,
                            including cultivated crops and pasture/hay - Cultivated crops are
                            described as areas used for the production of annual crops, such as
                            corn, soybeans, vegetables, tobacco, and cotton, and also perennial
                            woody crops such as orchards and vineyards. This class also includes all
                            land being actively tilled. Pasture/Hay is described as grasses,
                            legumes, or grass-legume mixtures planted for livestock grazing or the
                            production of seed or hay crops, typically on a perennial cycle. Pixels
                            coded to a value of 6 have not changed between 1992 and 2001.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>7</edomv>
            <edomvd>Modified Anderson Level I class code for Wetlands, including woody
                            wetlands and herbaceous wetlands - Areas where forest or shrub land
                            vegetation accounts for greater than 20 percent of vegetative cover and
                            the soil or substrate is periodically saturated with or covered with
                            water and/or areas where perennial herbaceous vegetation accounts for
                            greater than 80 percent of vegetative cover and the soil or substrate is
                            periodically saturated with or covered with water. Pixels coded to a
                            value of 7 have not changed between 1992 and 2001.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>8</edomv>
            <edomvd>Modified Anderson Level I class code for Perennial Ice/Snow - All
                            areas characterized by a perennial cover of ice and/or snow, generally
                            greater than 25% of total cover. Pixels coded to a value of 8 have not
                            changed between 1992 and 2001.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>12</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Open Water to Urban</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>13</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Open Water to Barren</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>14</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Open Water to Forest</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>15</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Open Water to Grassland/Shrub</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>16</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Open Water to Agriculture</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>17</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Open Water to Wetlands</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>18</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Open Water to Ice/Snow</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>21</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Urban to Open Water</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>23</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Urban to Barren</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>24</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Urban to Forest</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>25</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Urban to Grassland/Shrub</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>26</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Urban to Agriculture</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>27</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Urban to Wetlands</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>28</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Urban to Ice/Snow</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>31</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Barren to Open Water</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>32</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Barren to Urban</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>34</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Barren to Forest</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>35</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Barren to Grassland/Shrub</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>36</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Barren to Agriculture</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>37</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Barren to Wetlands</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>38</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Barren to Ice/Snow</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>41</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Forest to Open Water</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>42</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Forest to Urban</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>43</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Forest to Barren</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>45</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Forest to Grassland/Shrub</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>46</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Forest to Agriculture</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>47</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Forest to Wetlands</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>48</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Forest Forest to Ice/Snow</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>51</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Grassland/Shrub to Open Water</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>52</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Grassland/Shrub to Urban</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>53</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Grassland/Shrub to Barren</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>54</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Grassland/Shrub to Forest</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>56</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Grassland/Shrub to Agriculture</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>57</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Grassland/Shrub to Wetlands</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>58</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Grassland/Shrub to Ice/Snow</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>61</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Agriculture to Open Water</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>62</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Agriculture to Urban</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>63</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Agriculture to Barren</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>64</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Agriculture to Forest</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>65</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Agriculture to Grassland/Shrub</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>67</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Agriculture to Wetlands</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>68</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Agriculture to Ice/Snow</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>71</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Wetland to Open Water</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>72</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Wetland to Urban</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>73</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Wetland to Barren</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>74</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Wetland to Forest</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>75</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Wetland to Grassland/Shrb</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>76</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Wetland to Agriculture</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>78</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Wetland to Ice/Snow</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>81</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Ice/Snow to Open Water</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>82</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Ice/Snow to Urban</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>83</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Ice/Snow to Barren</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>84</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Ice/Snow to Forest</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>85</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Ice/Snow to Grassland/Shrub</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>86</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Ice/Snow to Agriculture</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>87</edomv>
            <edomvd>Land cover change code for Ice/Snow to Wetlands</edomvd>
            <edomvds>NLCD 1992/2001 land cover change class descriptions</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
        <distrib>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>Albert R. Mann Library</cntorg>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
              <address>Cornell University</address>
              <city>Ithaca</city>
              <state>New York</state>
              <postal>14853</postal>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>607-255-5406</cntvoice>
            <cntemail>mann-ref@cornell.edu</cntemail>
          </cntinfo>
        </distrib>
        <distliab>Cornell University provides these geographic data "as is". Cornell
          University makes no guarantee or warranty concerning the accuracy of
          information contained in the geographic data. Cornell University further
          makes no warranty either expressed or implied, regarding the condition of
          the product or its fitness for any particular purpose. The burden for
          determining fitness for use lies entirely with the user. Although these
          files have been processed successfully on computers at Cornell University,
          no warranty is made by Cornell University regarding the use of these data
          on any other system, nor does the fact of distribution constitute or imply
          any such warranty.</distliab>
        <stdorder>
        <digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>GeoTIFF</formname>
              <formcont>zipped geotiff</formcont>
              <filedec>zip</filedec>
              <transize>20.89</transize>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/80/05/cugir-008005.zip</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>metadata</formname>
              <formcont>FGDC XML metadata</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/80/05/fgdc.xml</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>HTML metadata</formname>
              <formcont>FGDC HTML metadata</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/80/05/fgdc.html</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>OGC:WMS</formname>
              <formcont>WMS, from GeoServer</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir.library.cornell.edu/geoserver/cugir/wms?version=1.1.0&amp;request=GetMap&amp;layers=cugir008005&amp;bbox=-80.32125179,39.91363831,-70.23101321,46.02064068999999&amp;width=256&amp;height=154&amp;srs=EPSG:4326&amp;format=image/png</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><fees>None</fees></stdorder>
      </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
      <metd>20190604</metd>
      <metc>
        <cntinfo>
          <cntorgp>
            <cntorg>Albert R. Mann Library</cntorg>
          </cntorgp>
          <cntaddr>
            <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
            <address>Albert R. Mann Library</address>
            <city>Ithaca</city>
            <state>New York</state>
            <postal>14853</postal>
            <country>USA</country>
          </cntaddr>
          <cntvoice>607-255-5406</cntvoice>
          <cntemail>mann-ref@cornell.edu</cntemail>
        </cntinfo>
      </metc>
      <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
      <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
      <mettc>local time</mettc>
    </metainfo>
</metadata>
