<!DOCTYPE metadata SYSTEM "http://fgdc.gov/metadata/fgdc-std-001-1998.dtd">
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>New York State Department of Environmental Conservation</origin>
        <pubdate>20130828</pubdate>
        <title>Index of New York State Regulatory Freshwater Wetlands</title>
        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Albany, NY</pubplace>
          <publish>New York State Department of Environmental Conservation (NYSDEC)</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <onlink>https://cugir.library.cornell.edu/catalog/cugir-008187</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>These data are a set of ARC/INFO coverages composed of polygonal and linear
        features. Coverages are based on official New York State Freshwater Wetlands Maps as
        described in Article 24-0301 of the Environmental Conservation Law. Coverages are not,
        however, a legal substitute for the official maps. Coverages are available on a county basis
        for all areas of New York State outside the Adirondack Park. </abstract>
      <purpose>To provide a faithful representation of official New York State regulatory freshwater
        wetlands maps for GIS resource analysis at scales equal to the 1 to 24,000 scale of original
        mapping or smaller scales (e.g., 1 to 100,000 scale).</purpose>
      <supplinf>Regulatory maps consist of mylar versions of New York State Department of
        Transportation 1 to 24,000 planimetric maps on which wetland boundaries and wetland
        identification codes are drawn. Planimetric maps are generally congruent with and have the
        same quad names as United States Geological Survey 7.5 minute topographic maps; a few of the
        Department of Transportation quads have extended borders. Regulatory wetland maps are
        prepared by NYSDEC and filed as required by the Freshwater Wetlands Act (Article 24 of the
        Environmental Conservation Law). Associated with the maps are Classification Sheets that
        list the Wetlands Identification Code, the municipality in which the wetland occurs and the
        regulatory class of each wetland. Preparation and filing dates vary by county. As amendments
        to the official maps occur, the coverages are updated so that the GIS information reflects
        the regulatory maps currently in use. Archive copies of county coverages with previous
        versions of the official maps are kept. An important feature of the official maps is that
        the lines indicate only "the approximate location of the actual boundaries of the wetlands"
        (ECL Section 24-0301(3)). For a final determination of the actual location of a wetland it
        is necessary to contact the NYSDEC office for the region in which the wetland
        occurs.</supplinf>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>1994</begdate>
          <enddate>2013</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Publication date per county. Coverages are updated as amendments occur, or as errors
        in the data are discovered and corrected. For the most recent updates to coverages by
        county, see the README file at
        https://s3.amazonaws.com/cugir-data/00/81/87/fwreadme.txt</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>As needed</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
          <bounding>
            <westbc>-79.762152</westbc>
            <eastbc>-71.856214</eastbc>
            <northbc>45.01585</northbc>
            <southbc>40.496103</southbc>
          </bounding>
        </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>Freshwater Wetlands</themekey>
        <themekey>Regulatory Wetlands</themekey>
        <themekey>index map</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>LCSH</themekt>
        <themekey>Wetlands</themekey>
        <themekey>Conservation of natural resources</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
        <themekey>inlandWaters</themekey>
        <themekey>environment</themekey>
        <themekey>planningCadastre</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
              <themekt>CUGIR Category</themekt>
              <themekey>index map</themekey>
<themekey>inland waters</themekey>
<themekey>environment</themekey>
<themekey>property</themekey>
            </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>LCSH</placekt>
        <placekey>New York (State)</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>1. The documentation in the Entity and Attribute Overview section of the metadata, and
      the README referred to in that section, are integral parts of the Regulatory Freshwater
      Wetlands data. Failure to use the documentation in conjunction with the digital data
      constitutes a misuse of the data. 2. The digital freshwater wetlands data provided are not a
      legal substitute for the official Regulatory Freshwater Wetlands maps maintained by the
      Department of Environmental Conservation pursuant to Environmental Conservation Law Section
      24-0301. Should a discrepancy exist between the digital data and the official maps, the
      official maps are the correct source of information. 3. The official regulatory freshwater
      wetlands maps may be amended from time to time; digital data obtained at an earlier date may
      therefore become obsolete. Digital data also may be altered independently of official map
      amendments in order to make improvements. These digital data cannot be relied on as a
      definitive statement of the location of freshwater wetlands. Wetland boundaries are subject to
      delineation by Department of Environmental Conservation regional personnel. 4. The borders of
      wetlands shown on both the official maps and the digital data are approximate at a scale of 1
      to 24,000. Traditional cartographic or digital comparison of the wetland maps to mapped
      information that is collected and digitized at a larger scale than 1 to 24,000 is not
      cartographically acceptable and is subject to error. 5. It is inappropriate to make further
      distributions of the data, because digital wetlands data are not official regulatory maps and
      are subject to change. All requests for the digital wetlands data should be referred to the
      Cornell University Geospatial Information Repository https://cugir.library.cornell.edu/ or to
      the Habitat Inventory Unit, New York State Department of Environmental Conservation, 625
      Broadway, 5th Floor, Albany, New York 12233-4754, telephone (518)402-8961.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Katherine Barnes</cntper>
          <cntorg>New York State Department of Environmental Conservation - Division of Fish,
            Wildlife, and Marine Resources</cntorg>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>625 Broadway, 5th Floor</address>
          <city>Albany</city>
          <state>NY</state>
          <postal>12233-4754</postal>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>(518) 402-8964</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>(518) 402-8925</cntfax>
        <cntemail>katherine.barnes@dec.ny.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>See Entity and Attribute Information</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <logic>See Process Description</logic>
    <complete>See Currentness Reference</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>Wetland boundaries were delineated as "approximate" on 1 to 24,000 scale maps
          using a variety of methods, including aerial photographic interpretation, reference to
          published maps and field investigations. However, due to changes over time in the wetland
          resource, field verification of wetland boundaries is increasingly important. Digital
          wetland borders are derived from individual 1 to 24,000 quads, either by digitizing or by
          scanning followed by semi-automated raster to vector conversion. Quality assurance and
          quality control procedures included overlay of plot of digital boundaries on original
          source map with the condition for acceptance being no visible separation allowed between
          boundaries.</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>New York State Department of Environmental Conservation</origin>
            <pubdate>20101013</pubdate>
            <title>New York State Freshwater Wetlands Map</title>
            <geoform>map</geoform>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>24000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>stable-base material</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>19840101</begdate>
              <enddate>20130828</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>NYSFWW</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Spatial and attribute information</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Wetland borders are derived from individual 1 to 24,000 quads, either by
          digitizing or by scanning followed by semi-automated raster to vector conversion. Labels
          are added and coded with the wetland identification and class. Annotation indicating the
          wetland identification code is also added. The quads comprising a county are edge matched
          and map joined to form a county coverage. Quadrangle borders of wetlands that cross quads
          are dissolved away. Where contiguous wetlands on adjacent regulatory quad sheets do not
          match, arcs are added along the quad border between the wetland pieces on either side of
          the border so that a continuous polygon is formed. Wetland class in the coverage is
          checked against an ASCII file derived from the official classification sheets. Class and
          wetland ID are added to arcs using an automated procedure that derives arc attribute
          values from polygon attribute values. Data are tiled as coverages showing wetlands of a
          single county. Detailed protocols are maintained by the Habitat Inventory Unit. For
          further information on related files and coverages, see the README file at
          https://s3.amazonaws.com/cugir-data/00/81/87/fwreadme.txt</procdesc>
        <procdate>2013</procdate>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <gridsys>
          <gridsysn>Universal Transverse Mercator</gridsysn>
          <utm>
            <utmzone>18</utmzone>
            <transmer>
              <sfctrmer>0.9996</sfctrmer>
              <longcm>-75.000000</longcm>
              <latprjo>0.000000</latprjo>
              <feast>500000</feast>
              <fnorth>0</fnorth>
            </transmer>
          </utm>
        </gridsys>
        <planci>
          <plance>coordinate pair</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>0.6098</absres>
            <ordres>0.6098</ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>meters</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>GRS 1980</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.25</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>Regulatory Freshwater Wetlands.</enttypl>
        <enttypd>ARC/INFO Coverages of New York State Regulatory Freshwater Wetlands tiled by
          county.</enttypd>
        <enttypds>Official New York State Freshwater Wetland Maps as described in Article 24-0301 of
          the Environmental Conservation Law.</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>WETID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The wetland identification code of the wetland. When a wetland contains included
          uplands, water bodies, tidal wetlands or other features, the polygon of the non-wetland
          feature is coded with UPL, WAT, TID or OTH, respectively, in columns 8 - 10 of this field
          and with the wetlands identification code of the surrounding wetland in the first 7
          columns. Only the wetland identification code is a valid value for arcs. Wetlands with an
          extended adjacent area have an asterisk (*) directly following the wetland identification
          code as part of WETID. Found in PAT and AAT.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Freshwater Wetlands Mapping Technical Methods Statement. Division of Fish and
          Wildlife Technical Report. New York State Department of Environmental Conservation.
          Albany, N.Y. April, 1986. 48 pages.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Unique ID</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>CLASS</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The regulatory class of the wetland as derived from the wetlands classification
          sheets. Values are 1, 2, 3, and 4 for Class I, II, III, and IV wetlands, respectively. A
          value of 0 is used for non-wetland features. A value of 9 is used for wetlands that do not
          have a class. Only non-zero values for class are valid for arcs. Found in PAT and
          AAT.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>6 New York Codes, Rules and Regulations, Part 664 Freshwater Wetlands Mapping and
          Classification Regulations</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>1</edomv>
            <edomvd>Class I</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Classification Sheets</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>2</edomv>
            <edomvd>Class II</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Classification Sheets</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>3</edomv>
            <edomvd>Class III</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Classification Sheets</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>4</edomv>
            <edomvd>Class IV</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Classification Sheets</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>0</edomv>
            <edomvd>non-wetland features</edomvd>
            <edomvds>DEC Habitat Inventory Unit internal documentation, "Procedures for Labels in
              Non-wetland Polygons"</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>9</edomv>
            <edomvd>wetlands that do not have a class</edomvd>
            <edomvds>DEC Habitat Inventory Unit internal documentation, "Procedures for Labels in
              Non-wetland Polygons"</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>REGU-ACRES</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The total regulatory size in acres of the wetland. This total includes all polygons
          associated with the wetland such as included uplands or open water. This is the official
          regulatory wetland size as specified in the Freshwater Wetlands Act (ECL Section
          24-0107(1)(c)). If more than one wetland in the county has the same wetland ID, this item
          will contain, incorrectly, the total area of all wetlands with the same wetland ID. Found
          in PAT.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Calculated</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>calculated value</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>WETL-ACRES</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The total number of wetland acres in the wetland. This value is the sum of only the
          wetland polygons belonging to a wetland ID; it excludes any included uplands or open water
          bodies. This is an ecologically based total size, in contrast to the regulatory total
          given in REGU-ACRES. Found in PAT.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Calculated</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>calculated value</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>REGION-ACRES</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The total number of regulated wetland acres as determined by DEC regional office
          staff. This item has a value only if DEC regional staff have determined a value for the
          size of the wetland that they consider more accurate than the value determined by the
          geographic information system. Regional value may be determined from wetland maps at
          scales larger than 1 to 24,000, from surveys, or from other means. This item may be coded
          as 0 for some or all of the wetlands in a county coverage if regional staff have not
          determined a value. Where REGION-ACRES exists, it should be considered the correct value
          to be used in place of REGU-ACRES. Found in PAT.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Calculated</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>calculated value</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>POLY-ACRES</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The number of acres in the individual polygon.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Calculated</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>calculated value</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>#_PARCELS</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The number of separate wetland polygons, or separate areas of wetland, making up
          the regulated wetland.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Calculated</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>calculated value</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
    <overview>
      <eaover>Data are tiled as coverages showing wetlands of a single county. Coverages are named
        with the first four letters of the county's name followed by WET, e.g., ALBAWET. A link to
        the README file is found in Detail Citation for detailed usage notes. THESE NOTES ARE
        ESSENTIAL TO PROPER USE OF THE COVERAGES.</eaover>
      <eadetcit>https://s3.amazonaws.com/cugir-data/00/81/87/fwreadme.txt</eadetcit>
    </overview>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
        <distrib>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>Albert R. Mann Library</cntorg>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
              <address>Cornell University</address>
              <city>Ithaca</city>
              <state>New York</state>
              <postal>14853</postal>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>607-255-5406</cntvoice>
            <cntemail>mann-ref@cornell.edu</cntemail>
          </cntinfo>
        </distrib>
        <distliab>Cornell University provides these geographic data "as is". Cornell
          University makes no guarantee or warranty concerning the accuracy of
          information contained in the geographic data. Cornell University further
          makes no warranty either expressed or implied, regarding the condition of
          the product or its fitness for any particular purpose. The burden for
          determining fitness for use lies entirely with the user. Although these
          files have been processed successfully on computers at Cornell University,
          no warranty is made by Cornell University regarding the use of these data
          on any other system, nor does the fact of distribution constitute or imply
          any such warranty.</distliab>
        <stdorder>
        <digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>GeoJSON</formname>
              <formcont>OpenIndexMaps</formcont>
              <transize>0.18</transize>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/81/87/cugir-008187-index.geojson</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>metadata</formname>
              <formcont>FGDC XML metadata</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/81/87/fgdc.xml</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>HTML metadata</formname>
              <formcont>FGDC HTML metadata</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/81/87/fgdc.html</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><fees>None</fees></stdorder>
      </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
      <metd>20190524</metd>
      <metc>
        <cntinfo>
          <cntorgp>
            <cntorg>Albert R. Mann Library</cntorg>
          </cntorgp>
          <cntaddr>
            <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
            <address>Albert R. Mann Library</address>
            <city>Ithaca</city>
            <state>New York</state>
            <postal>14853</postal>
            <country>USA</country>
          </cntaddr>
          <cntvoice>607-255-5406</cntvoice>
          <cntemail>mann-ref@cornell.edu</cntemail>
        </cntinfo>
      </metc>
      <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
      <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
      <mettc>local time</mettc>
    </metainfo>
</metadata>
