<!DOCTYPE metadata SYSTEM "http://fgdc.gov/metadata/fgdc-std-001-1998.dtd">
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources Conservation Service</origin>
        <pubdate>20060705</pubdate>
        <title>STATSGO2 Soils, New York, 2006</title>
        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Fort Worth, Texas</pubplace>
          <publish>U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural ResourcesConservation Service</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <onlink>https://cugir.library.cornell.edu/catalog/cugir-008009</onlink>
        <onlink>https://www.nrcs.usda.gov/wps/portal/nrcs/detail/soils/survey/geo/?cid=nrcs142p2_053629</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>STATSGO2 consists of general soil association units. It was developed by the
        National Cooperative Soil Survey and supersedes the State Soil Geographic (STATSGO) data set
        published in 1994 .It consists of a broad based inventory of soils and nonsoil areas that
        occur in a repeatable pattern on the landscape and that can be cartographically shown at the
        scale mapped. The data set was created by generalizing more detailed soil survey maps. Where
        more detailed soil survey maps were not available, data on geology, topography, vegetation,
        and climate were assembled, together with Land Remote Sensing Satellite (LANDSAT) images.
        Soils of like areas were studied, and the probable classification and extent of the soils were
        determined. Map unit composition was determined by transecting or sampling areas on the more
        detailed maps and expanding the data statistically to characterize the whole map unit. This
        data set consists of georeferenced vector digital data and tabular digital data. The map data
        were collected in 1-by 2-degree topographic quadrangle units and merged into a seamless
        national data set. It is distributed in state/territory and national extents. The soil map
        units are linked to attributes in the National Soil Information System data base which gives
        the proportionate extent of the component soils and their properties.</abstract>
      <purpose>These data provide information about soil features on or near the surface of the
        Earth. Data were collected as part of the National Cooperative Soil Survey. These data are
        intended for geographic display and analysis at the state, regional, and national level.The
        data should be displayed and analyzed at scales appropriate for 1:250,000-scale
        data.</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>2000</begdate>
          <enddate>20060705</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>publication date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>As needed</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
          <bounding>
            <westbc>-79.762154</westbc>
            <eastbc>-71.857208</eastbc>
            <northbc>45.01566</northbc>
            <southbc>40.495484</southbc>
          </bounding>
        </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>Soils</themekey>
        <themekey>General Soil Map</themekey>
        <themekey>State Soil Geographic</themekey>
        <themekey>STATSGO</themekey>
        <themekey>United States Department of Agriculture</themekey>
        <themekey>USDA</themekey>
        <themekey>National Soil Information System (NASIS)</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
        <themekey>geoscientificInformation</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
              <themekt>CUGIR Category</themekt>
              <themekey>geology</themekey>
            </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>None</placekt>
        <placekey>New York (State)</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>The U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources ConservationService should be
      acknowledged as the data source in productsderived from these data. Hardcopies utilizing these
      data shallclearly indicate their source. User agrees not to misrepresent thesedata, nor to
      imply that changes made were approved by the NaturalResources Conservation Service.The Digital
      General Soil Map of U.S. was designed primarily forregional, multicounty, river basin, State,
      and multistate resourceplanning, management, and monitoring. Data are not detailed enoughto
      make interpretations at a county level. This soil survey productis not designed for use as a
      primary regulatory tool in permittingor citing decisions, but may be used as a reference
      source. The useof these data is not restricted and may be interpreted by
      organizations,agencies, units of government, or others; however, they are responsiblefor its
      appropriate application. Federal, State, or local regulatorybodies are not to reassign to the
      Natural Resources ConservationService any authority for the decisions that they make. The
      NaturalResources Conservation Service will not perform any evaluations ofthese maps for
      purposes related solely to state or local regulatoryprograms.When data from the Digital
      General Soil Map of U.S. are overlayedwith other data layers, such as land use data, caution
      must beused in generating statistics on the co-occurence of the land usedata with the soil
      data. The composition of the soil map unit canbe characterized independently for the land use
      and for the soilcomponent, but there are no data on their joint occurrence at amore detailed
      level. Analysis of the overlayed data should be on amap polygon basis.Additional political,
      watershed, or other boundaries may beintersected with the soil data. Although the composition
      of eachpolitical and watershed unit may be described in terms of thesoil map units,
      information is not available to assign thecomponents to the boundary units with full accuracy.
      As with theland use categories, the analysis should be restricted to theclassified
      components.The approximate minimum area delineated is 625 hectares(1,544 acres), which is
      represented on a 1:250,000-scale map byan area approximately 1 cm by 1 cm (0.4 inch by 0.4
      inch). Lineardelineations are not less than 0.5 cm (0.2 inch) in width. Thenumber of
      delineations per 1:250,000 quadrangle typically is 100to 200, but may range up to 400.
      Delineations depict the dominantsoils making up the landscape. Other dissimilar soils, too
      smallto be delineated, are present within a delineation.Digital enlargements of these data to
      scales greater than atwhich they were originally mapped can cause misinterpretationof the
      data. If enlarged, maps do not show the small areas ofcontrasting soils that could have been
      shown at a larger scale.The depicted soil boundaries, interpretations, and analysisderived
      from them do not eliminate the need for onsite sampling,testing, and detailed study of
      specific sites for intensive uses.Thus, these data and their interpretations are intended
      forplanning purposes only.Data values for some data elements may be incomplete or
      missing.Where data are unavailable, a mask should be used to exclude thearea from analysis.The
      spatial and tabular data used to create this product areperiodically updated. Data are
      versioned, and users are responsiblefor obtaining the latest version of the
      product.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources Conservation Service</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>State Soil Scientist</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>
          <address>USDA - Natural Resources Conservation Service</address>
          <address>Alaska State Office</address>
          <address>800 West Evergreen, Suite 100</address>
          <city>Palmer</city>
          <state>AK</state>
          <postal>99645-6546</postal>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>907-761-7759</cntvoice>
        <cnttdd>800-877-8339</cnttdd>
        <cntemail>Joseph.Moore@ak.usda.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <browse>
              <browsen>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/80/09/preview.png</browsen>
              <browsed>preview of the dataset</browsed>
              <browset>PNG</browset>
            </browse>
    <crossref>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>U.S. Department of Agriculture, Soil Conservation Service</origin>
        <pubdate>1994</pubdate>
        <title>State Soil Survey Geographic (STATSGO) data base</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </crossref>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>Accuracy is tested by manual comparison of the source with hardcopy plots and/or
        symbolized display of the map data on aninteractive computer graphic system. Selected
        attributes thatcannot be visually verified on plots or on screen are interactivelyqueried
        and verified on screen. In addition, the attributesare tested against a master set of valid
        attributes. All attributedata conform to the attribute codes in the signed classificationand
        correlation document and amendments and are current as ofthe date of digitizing.</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <logic>Certain node/geometry and topology (GT)-polygon/chainrelationships are collected or
      generated to satisfy topologicalrequirements. (The GT-polygon corresponds to the soil
      delineation).Some of these requirements include: chains must begin and end atnodes, chains
      must connect to each other at nodes, chains do notextend through nodes, left and right
      GT-polygons are defined foreach chain element and are consistent throughout, and the
      chainsrepresenting the limits of the file (neatline) are free of gaps.The tests of logical
      consistency are performed using vendorsoftware. The neatline is generated by connecting the
      explicitlyentered four corners of the digital file. All data outside theenclosed region are
      ignored and all data crossing thesegeographically straight lines are clipped at the neatline.
      Datawithin a specified tolerance of the neatline are snapped to theneatline. Neatline
      straightening aligns the digitized edges ofthe digital data with the generated neatline (i.e.,
      with thelongitude/latitude lines in geographic coordinates). All internalpolygons are tested
      for closure with vendor software and arechecked on hard copy plots. All data are checked for
      common soillines (i.e., adjacent polygons with the same label). Quadranglesare edge matched
      within the state, merged into a statewide datasets, and then edge matched to adjacent state
      data sets. Edgelocations do not deviate from centerline to centerline by morethan 0.01
      inch.</logic>
    <complete>A map unit is a collection of areas defined and named the samein terms of their soil
      and/or nonsoil areas. Each map unit differsin some respect from all others in a survey area
      and is uniquelyidentified. Each individual area is a delineation. Each map unitin the Digital
      General Soil Map of U.S. consists of one to morethan 21 components.In those few areas where
      detailed maps did not exist,reconnaissance soil surveys were combined with data on
      geology,topography, vegetation, climate, and remote sensing images todelineate map units and
      estimate the percentages of components.Map unit components in this product are soil series
      phases, andtheir percent composition represents the estimated areal proportionof each within a
      map unit. The composition for a map unit isgeneralized to represent the statewide extent of
      that map unitand not the extent of any single map unit delineation. Thesespecifications
      provide a nationally consistent representation ofthe associated attribute data.The actual
      composition and interpretive purity of the map unitdelineations were based on statistical
      analysis of transect data.The composition was largely determined by measuring transects
      ondetailed soil survey maps. The number of transects used wasproportional to the relative
      size, number, and complexity of thedelineations. The combined data on the length of the map
      unitscrossed by the transects were used to determine the percentagesof the different soil and
      nonsoil areas in each map unit.Specific National Cooperative Soil Survey Standards
      andprocedures were used in the classification of soils, design andname of map units. These
      standards are outlined in U.S. Departmentof Agriculture. 2nd Ed., 1999. Soil Taxonomy: A basic
      system ofsoil classification for making and interpreting soil surveys.Nat. Res. Conserv.
      Serv., U.S. Dep. Agric. Handb. 436.; U.S.Department of Agriculture. 9th Ed., 2003. Keys to
      Soil Taxonomy.Soil Surv. staff, Nat. Res. Conserv. Serv.; U.S. Department ofAgriculture.
      Current Issue. National Soil Survey Handbook, title430-VI. Soil Surv. Staff, Nat. Res.
      Conserv. Serv.; and U.S.Department of Agriculture. 1993. Soil Survey Manual. Soil Surv.Staff,
      U.S. Dep. Agric. Handbook 18.Adherence to National Cooperative Soil Survey standards
      andprocedures is based on peer review, quality control, and qualityassurance. Quality control
      is outlined in documents that residewith the Natural Resources Conservation Service state
      soilscientist.</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>The accuracy of these digital data is based upon theircompilation to base maps
          that meet National Map AccuracyStandards. The difference in positional accuracy betweenthe
          map unit boundaries in the field and their digitizedmap locations is unknown. The
          locational acuracy of soildelineations on the ground varies with the transitionbetween map
          units.For example, in areas where changes in soils, climate,topography, and geology occur
          subtly across a portion of astate, the transition between soil map unit boundaries willbe
          gradual. Where these features change abruptly, such asfrom an area of foothills to a lake
          plain, the transitionwill be very narrow. Soil delineation boundaries weredigitized within
          0.01 inches of their locations on thedigitizing source. The digital map elements are edge
          matchedbetween data sets. The data along each state boundary arematched against the data
          for the adjacent state. Edgelocations generally do not deviate from centerline
          tocenterline by more than 0.01 inch.</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>U.S Department of Agriculture, Natural ResourcesConservation Service</origin>
            <pubdate>Unknown</pubdate>
            <title>multiple soil survey publications</title>
            <geoform>map</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Washington, D.C.</pubplace>
              <publish>U.S. Government Printing Office</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>paper</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>Unknown</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>SCS1</srccitea>
        <srccontr>base information for development of map unit delineationsand transect data for
          naming map units</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>U.S Department of Agriculture, Natural ResourcesConservation Service</origin>
            <pubdate>Unknown</pubdate>
            <title>multiple reconnaissance, county, and State generalsoil maps</title>
            <geoform>map</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Washington, D.C.</pubplace>
              <publish>U.S. Government Printing Office</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>paper</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>Unknown</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>SCS2</srccitea>
        <srccontr>reference information for development of map unitdelineations and transect data
          for naming map unitswhere detailed surveys did not exist</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>U.S. Geological Survey</origin>
            <pubdate>Unknown</pubdate>
            <title>multiple maps</title>
            <geoform>map</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Reston, Virginia</pubplace>
              <publish>U.S. Geological Survey</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>250000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>stable-base material</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>Unknown</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>USGS1</srccitea>
        <srccontr>base materials for compilation of map unit delineationlinework</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>U.S Department of Agriculture, Natural ResourcesConservation Service</origin>
            <pubdate>Unknown</pubdate>
            <title>multiple compiled mylar overlays of map unitdelineations, unpublished</title>
            <geoform>annotated overlay</geoform>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>stable-base material</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>Unknown</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>unknown</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>SCS3</srccitea>
        <srccontr>digitizing source</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural ResourcesConservation Service</origin>
            <pubdate>1994</pubdate>
            <title>State Soil Geographic (STATSGO) data base</title>
            <geoform>digital data</geoform>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>250000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>CD-ROM</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>1994</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>1994</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>SCS4</srccitea>
        <srccontr>source material of soil map unit delineations andsoil symbols</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>U.S. Department of Agriculture,Natural Resources Conservation Service</origin>
            <pubdate>2005</pubdate>
            <title>National Soil Information System (NASIS) data base</title>
            <geoform>tabular digital data</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Fort Collins, Colorado</pubplace>
              <publish>U.S. Department of Agriculture,Natural Resources Conservation
                Service</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>database</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>2005</begdate>
              <enddate>2005</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>NASIS</srccitea>
        <srccontr>attribute (tabular) information</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Map unit composition was determined by transecting orsampling areas on the more
          detailed soil maps and expandingthe data statistically to characterize the whole map
          unit.</procdesc>
        <srcused>SCS1</srcused>
        <procdate>1994</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Soil map unit lines and symbols were drafted in red pencilon a mylar overlay that
          was punch registered to fit the mylarUSGS 1:250,000-scale topographic quadrangle. A
          detailed andcomplete edit was performed on all overlays before digitizing.The soil
          delineation overlays were raster scanned at ascanning resolution of at least 0.01 inches
          and converted toa vector format or were manually digitized on a digitizingtablet with a
          resolution of at least 0.001 inches. Fourcontrol points corresponding to the four corners
          of thequadrangles were used for registration during data collection.The control points
          were either explicitly entered or developedby the software. The data sets were edge
          matched and mergedinto statewide coverages. A detailed and complete edit wasperformed on
          all digital data.</procdesc>
        <srcused>USGS1, SCS3</srcused>
        <procdate>1994</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>State coverages were merged into a seamless national coverage.This reduced tabular
          data redundancy and polygon number. A detailedand complete edit was performed on all
          digital data.</procdesc>
        <srcused>SCS4</srcused>
        <procdate>2000</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>The National Soil Information System data base was developedby Natural Resources
          Conservation Service soil scientistsaccording to national standards.</procdesc>
        <srcused>SCS4</srcused>
        <procdate>2005</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientistor delegate, upon
          completion of data quality verification,determined that the tabular data should be
          released for officialuse. A selected set of map units and components in the soilsurvey
          legend was copied to a staging database, and rating valuesfor selected interpretations
          were generated. The list of selectedinterpretations is stored in the database table named
          sainterp.</procdesc>
        <srcused>NASIS</srcused>
        <procdate>20050715</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientistor delegate
          verified that the labels on the digitized soil mapunits link to map units in the tabular
          database, and certifiedthe joined data sets for release to the Soil Data Warehouse.
          Asystem assigned version number and date stamp were added and thedata were copied to the
          data warehouse. The tabular data for themap units and components were extracted from the
          data warehouseand reformatted into the soil data delivery data model, thenstored in the
          Soil Data Mart. The spatial data were copied to theSoil Data Mart without
          change.</procdesc>
        <srcused>NASIS</srcused>
        <procdate>20050715</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>The tabular data were extracted from the Soil Data Mart withoutchange. The spatial
          data was exported to an ESRI shapefile.</procdesc>
        <srcused>NASIS</srcused>
        <procdate>20050718</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist ordelegate, upon
          completion of data quality verification, determinedthat the tabular data should be
          released for official use. Aselected set of map units and components in the soil survey
          legend wascopied to a staging database, and rating values for selectedinterpretations were
          generated. The list of selected interpretations isstored in the database table named
          sainterp.</procdesc>
        <srcused>NASIS</srcused>
        <procdate>20060628</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist ordelegate
          verified that the labels on the digitized soil map unitslink to map units in the tabular
          database, and certified the joineddata sets for release to the Soil Data Warehouse. A
          system assignedversion number and date stamp were added and the data were copied tothe
          data warehouse. The tabular data for the map units and componentswere extracted from the
          data warehouse and reformatted into the soildata delivery data model, then stored in the
          Soil Data Mart. The spatialdata were copied to the Soil Data Mart without
          change.</procdesc>
        <srcused>NASIS</srcused>
        <procdate>20060629</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>The tabular data associated with map units that overlap the clipping region "NY"
          were extracted from the data mart without change. The spatial data were clipped to
          clipping region "NY". The spatial data was exported to an ESRI shapefile. </procdesc>
        <srcused>NASIS</srcused>
        <procdate>20090317</procdate>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
        <direct>Vector</direct>
        <ptvctinf>
          <sdtsterm>
            <sdtstype>G-polygon</sdtstype>
            <ptvctcnt>3273</ptvctcnt>
          </sdtsterm>
        </ptvctinf>
      </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <geograph>
        <geogunit>Decimal degrees</geogunit>
        <latres>0.0000001</latres>
        <longres>0.0000001</longres>
      </geograph>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257222</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>General Soil Map Unit</enttypl>
        <enttypd>A closed polygon that consists of soils and nonsoil areas thatoccur in a repeatable
          pattern on the landscape and that can becartographically shown at the scale
          mapped.</enttypd>
        <enttypds>NRCS National Cooperative Soil Survey</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>AREASYMBOL</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>A symbol that uniquely identifies a single occurrence of aparticular type of area
          (e.g. Lancaster Co., Nebraska is NE109).</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>NASIS</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <codesetd>
            <codesetn>None</codesetn>
            <codesets>National Information Technology Center, NRCS, 2150 Centre Ave.,Bldg. A, Fort
              Collins, CO 80526</codesets>
          </codesetd>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>MUSYM</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The symbol used to uniquely identify the soil map unit in thesoil survey.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>NASIS</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <codesetd>
            <codesetn>None</codesetn>
            <codesets>National Information Technology Center, NRCS, 2150 Centre Ave.,Bldg. A, Fort
              Collins, CO 80526</codesets>
          </codesetd>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>MUKEY</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>A non-connotative string of characters used to uniquely identifya record in the
          Mapunit table.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>NASIS</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>No predefined set of mukeys.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SPATIALVERSION</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>A sequential integer number used to denote the serial version ofthe spatial data
          for a soil survey area.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>NASIS</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>1</rdommin>
            <rdommax>1</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
    <overview>
      <eaover>Map Unit Delineations are closed polygons that are geographicmixtures of groups of
        soils or soils and nonsoil areas.The map unit key uniquely identifies each closed map
        unitdelineation. Each map unit key is linked to a map unit symboland a map unit name. The
        map unit key is also the key for linkinginformation in the National Soil Information System
        tables.Map Unit Delineations are described by the National SoilInformation System data base.
        This attribute data base gives theproportionate extent of the component soils and the
        propertiesfor each soil. The data base contains both estimated and measureddata on the
        physical and chemical soil properties and soilinterpretations for engineering, water
        management, recreation,agronomic, woodland, range and wildlife uses of the soil.The National
        Soil Information System data base contains staticmetadata. It documents the data structure
        and includes suchinformation as what tables, columns, indexes, and relationshipsare defined
        as well as a variety of attributes of each of thesedata base objects. Attributes include
        table and column descriptionsand detailed domain information.The National Soil Information
        System data base also containsdistribution metadata. It records the criteria used in the
        setof distributed data.</eaover>
      <eadetcit>U.S. Department of Agriculture. 2nd Ed., 1999. Soil Taxonomy: Abasic system of soil
        classification for making and interpretingsoil surveys. Nat. Res. Conserv. Serv., U.S. Dep.
        Agric. Handb.436.U.S. Department of Agriculture. 9th Ed., 2003. Keys to SoilTaxonomy. Soil
        Surv. Staff, Nat. Res. Conserv. Serv.U.S. Department of Agriculture. Current Issue. National
        SoilSurvey Handbook, title 430-VI. Soil Surv. Staff, Nat. Res.Conserv. Serv.U.S. Department
        of Agriculture. 1993. Soil Survey Manual.Soil Surv. Staff, U.S. Dep. Agric. Handbook 18.U.S.
        Department of Agriculture. 1994. State Soil Geographic(STATSGO) Data Base: Data use
        information. Soil Conserv. Serv.</eadetcit>
    </overview>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
        <distrib>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>Albert R. Mann Library</cntorg>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
              <address>Cornell University</address>
              <city>Ithaca</city>
              <state>New York</state>
              <postal>14853</postal>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>607-255-5406</cntvoice>
            <cntemail>mann-ref@cornell.edu</cntemail>
          </cntinfo>
        </distrib>
        <distliab>Cornell University provides these geographic data "as is". Cornell
          University makes no guarantee or warranty concerning the accuracy of
          information contained in the geographic data. Cornell University further
          makes no warranty either expressed or implied, regarding the condition of
          the product or its fitness for any particular purpose. The burden for
          determining fitness for use lies entirely with the user. Although these
          files have been processed successfully on computers at Cornell University,
          no warranty is made by Cornell University regarding the use of these data
          on any other system, nor does the fact of distribution constitute or imply
          any such warranty.</distliab>
        <stdorder>
        <digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>Shapefile</formname>
              <formcont>zipped shapefile</formcont>
              <filedec>zip</filedec>
              <transize>10.04</transize>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/80/09/cugir-008009.zip</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>metadata</formname>
              <formcont>FGDC XML metadata</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/80/09/fgdc.xml</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>HTML metadata</formname>
              <formcont>FGDC HTML metadata</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/80/09/fgdc.html</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
                <digtinfo>
                  <formname>KML</formname>
                  <formcont>generated KML, via WFS</formcont>
                </digtinfo>
                <digtopt>
                  <onlinopt>
                    <computer>
                      <networka>
                        <networkr>https://cugir.library.cornell.edu/geoserver/cugir/wfs?version=1.0.0&amp;request=GetFeature&amp;typeName=cugir008009&amp;outputFormat=application%2Fvnd.google-earth.kml%2Bxml</networkr>
                      </networka>
                    </computer>
                  </onlinopt>
                </digtopt>
              </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>GeoJSON</formname>
              <formcont>generated GeoJSON, via WFS</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir.library.cornell.edu/geoserver/cugir/wfs?version=1.0.0&amp;request=GetFeature&amp;typeName=cugir008009&amp;outputFormat=application%2Fjson</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>OGC:WMS</formname>
              <formcont>WMS, from GeoServer</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir.library.cornell.edu/geoserver/cugir/wms?version=1.1.0&amp;request=GetMap&amp;layers=cugir008009&amp;bbox=-79.99930237999999,40.35987872,-71.62005962,45.15126528&amp;width=256&amp;height=146&amp;srs=EPSG:4326&amp;format=image/png</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><fees>None</fees></stdorder>
      </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
      <metd>20190524</metd>
      <metc>
        <cntinfo>
          <cntorgp>
            <cntorg>Albert R. Mann Library</cntorg>
          </cntorgp>
          <cntaddr>
            <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
            <address>Albert R. Mann Library</address>
            <city>Ithaca</city>
            <state>New York</state>
            <postal>14853</postal>
            <country>USA</country>
          </cntaddr>
          <cntvoice>607-255-5406</cntvoice>
          <cntemail>mann-ref@cornell.edu</cntemail>
        </cntinfo>
      </metc>
      <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
      <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
      <mettc>local time</mettc>
    </metainfo>
</metadata>
